. >> GOOD AFTERNOON.
WELCOME TO THE MAY 19TH 2026 REGULAR MEETING OF THE SAN
FRANCISCO BOARD OF SUPERVISORS. >> MADAM CLERK, WILL YOU PLEASE
CALL THE ROLL? THANK YOU, MR. PRESIDENT.
SUPERVISOR CHAN CHEN PRESENT SUPERVISOR SIR CHEN CHEN
PRESENT SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY PRESENT SUPERVISOR
FIELDER FIELDER AND NOT PRESENT SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD
PRESENT SUPERVISOR RANDLEMAN PRESENT MANDAL MEN PRESENT
SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR PRESENT SUPERVISOR SADR SADR
PRESENTS SUPERVISOR CHERYL SHERRELL PRESENT SUPERVISOR
WALTON WALTON PRESENT AND SUPERVISOR WONG WONG
PRESENT MR. PRESIDENT, YOU HAVE A QUORUM.
>> THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK. SAN FRANCISCO BOARD OF
SUPERVISORS ACKNOWLEDGES THAT WE ARE ON THE UNCEDED ANCESTRAL
HOMELAND OF THE RAW MATERIAL ALONI WHO ARE THE
ORIGINAL INHABITANTS OF THE SAN FRANCISCO PENINSULA?
AS THE INDIGENOUS STEWARDS OF THIS LAND AND IN ACCORDANCE
WITH THEIR TRADITIONS THE PROMISES ALONE HAVE NEVER CEDED
LOST NOR FORGOTTEN THEIR RESPONSIBILITIES AS THE
CARETAKERS OF THIS PLACE AS WELL AS FOR ALL PEOPLES WHO
RESIDE IN THEIR TRADITIONAL TERRITORY.
AS GUESTS WE RECOGNIZE THAT WE BENEFIT FROM LIVING AND WORKING
ON THEIR TRADITIONAL HOMELAND. WE WISH TO PAY OUR RESPECTS BY
ACKNOWLEDGING THE ANCESTORS ELDERS AND RELATIVES OF THE RAW
MATERIAL OWNING COMMUNITY AND BY AFFIRMING THEIR
SOVEREIGN RIGHTS AS FIRST PEOPLES.
COLLEAGUES, WILL YOU JOIN ME IN RECITING THE PLEDGE OF
ALLEGIANCE? I PLEDGE ALLEGIANCE TO THE FLAG
OF THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA FOR WHICH IT STANDS ONE NATION
UNDER GOD WITH LIBERTY AND JUSTICE FOR ALL.
>> ON BEHALF OF THE BOARD I WANT TO ACKNOWLEDGE THE STAFF
AT S.F. GOV. GOV TV TODAY THAT IS
PARTICULARLY SUZZY NOS. THEY RECORD EACH OF OUR
MEETINGS AND MAKE THE TRANSCRIPTS AVAILABLE TO THE
PUBLIC ONLINE. MADAM CLERK DO YOU HAVE ANY
COMMUNICATIONS? >> YES.
THE SAN FRANCISCO BOARD OF SUPERVISORS WELCOMES YOUR
ATTENDANCE IN PERSON HERE IN THE BOARD'S LEGISLATIVE
CHAMBER. AND WHEN YOU'RE NOT ABLE TO BE
HERE, THE PROCEEDINGS ARE AIRING LIVE ON S.F. GEOF TV'S
CHANNEL 26 WHERE YOU CAN VIEW THE LIVESTREAM AT S.F. GOV
TV.ORG. IF YOU'D LIKE TO SUBMIT PUBLIC
COMMENT AND WRITING YOU CAN SEND AN EMAIL TO B O S AT S.F.
GOV.SCOT ORG OR USE THE POSTAL SERVICE.
JUST ADDRESS THE ENVELOPE TO THE SAN FRANCISCO BOARD OF
SUPERVISORS. THE NUMBER ONE DR. CARLTON B
GOODLATTE PLACE CITY HALL ROOM 244 SAN FRANCISCO CALIFORNIA
94102 IF YOU NEED TO MAKE A REASONABLE ACCOMMODATION FOR A
FUTURE MEETING UNDER THE AMERICANS WITH DISABILITIES ACT
OR TO REQUEST LANGUAGE ASSISTANCE, CONTACT THE CLERK'S
OFFICE AT LEAST TWO BUSINESS DAYS IN ADVANCE BY CALLING
(415) 554-5184. AND FINALLY IN LINE WITH
SUPERVISOR JACKIE FIELDER'S APRIL 7TH MEMO REQUESTING TO BE
EXCUSED FROM THIS MEETING UNTIL JUNE 30TH A MOTION WOULD BE
IN ORDER TO CONSIDER THE REQUEST FOR TODAY'S MEETING.
>> THANK YOU, MR. PRESIDENT. THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK.
CAN I HAVE A MOTION TO EXCUSED SUPERVISOR FIELDER FROM TODAY'S
MEETING? MOVED BY CHANCE SECONDED BY
WALTON COLLEAGUES, I THINK WE CAN TAKE THAT WITHOUT
OBJECTION. WITHOUT OBJECTION.
SUPERVISOR FIELDER IS EXCUSED. MADAM CLERK, LET'S GO TO OUR
APPROVAL OF MEETING MINUTES. >> YES.
APPROVAL OF THE APRIL 14TH 2026 BOARD MEETING MINUTES.
MAY CAN I HAVE A MOTION TO APPROVE THE MINUTES AS
PRESENTED MOVED BY CHAN SECONDED BY DORSEY.
MADAM CLERK, WILL YOU PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON THE MINUTES AS
PRESENTED? SUPERVISOR CHAN CHIN EYES
SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN EYES SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY EYES
SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD EYES SUPERVISOR MENDELSON BY
RANDLEMAN EYES SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR EYES SUPERVISOR
SARDAR SADR EYE SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL EYES SUPERVISOR
WALTON WALTON EYE AND SUPERVISOR WONG WONG EITHER
ATTORNEYS WITHOUT OBJECTION THE MINUTES WILL BE APPROVED AFTER
PUBLIC COMMENT AS PRESENTED MADAM CLERK LET'S GO TO
UNFINISHED BUSINESS PLEASE CALL ITEM ONE ITEM ONE THIS IS AN
ORDINANCE TO APPROPRIATE APPROXIMATELY 1.2 MILLION OF
AMBULANCE BILLINGS AND APPROXIMATELY 426,000 OF
FIRE OVERTIME SERVICE FEES REVENUES IN THE FIRE DEPARTMENT
TO APPROPRIATE PERMANENT SALARIES OF 500,000 IN THE
DEPARTMENT OF EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT PERMANENT SALARIES
OF APPROXIMATELY 6 MILLION AND DEPENDENT COVERAGE OF
APPROXIMATE 990,000 IN THE FIRE DEPARTMENT AND PERMANENT
SALARIES OF 1.25 MILLION IN THE PUBLIC UTILITIES COMMISSION
AND TO APPROPRIATE 500,000 TO OVERTIME IN THE DEPARTMENT OF
EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT APPROXIMATELY 8.7 MILLION TO
OVERTIME IN THE FIRE DEPARTMENT AND 1.25 MILLION IN OVERTIME
IN THE PUBLIC UTILITIES COMMISSION TO SUPPORT THE
DEPARTMENT'S PROJECTED INCREASES IN OVERTIME.
THIS ORDINANCE REQUIRES A TWO THIRDS VOTE OF ALL MEMBERS OF
THE BOARD FOR APPROVAL OF THE FIRE DEPARTMENT'S APPROPRIATION
OF APPROXIMATELY 8 MILLION. >> PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON ITEM
ONE SUPERVISOR CHAN CHAN EYES SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN EYES
SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY EYES SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I
SUPERVISOR RANDLEMAN MANDEL MANDOLIN EYES SUPERVISOR MELGAR
MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SADR SADR I SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I
SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I AND SUPERVISOR WONG WONG I
THEIR ATTORNEYS WITHOUT OBJECTION THE ORDINANCE IS
FINALLY PASSED MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM TWO ITEM TWO
THIS IS AN ORDINANCE TO APPROPRIATE 2.5 MILLION OF OPEN
SPACE ACQUISITION FUNDING AND APPROPRIATING 2.5 MILLION
IN THE RECREATION AND PARK DEPARTMENT FOR A LOAN TO THE
SAN FRANCISCO ZOOLOGICAL SOCIETY IN FISCAL YEAR 2025
THROUGH 2026. >> LET'S TAKE THIS ITEM SAME
HOUSE, SAME CALL. >> WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
ORDINANCE IS FINALLY PASSED. >> MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL
ITEM NUMBER THREE. >> ITEM THREE THIS IS AN
ORDINANCE TO AMEND THE ADMINISTRATIVE BUSINESS AND TAX
REGULATIONS CAMPAIGN AND GOVERNMENTAL CONDUCT
ENVIRONMENT, HEALTH, LABOR AND EMPLOYMENT.
MUNICIPAL ELECTIONS PARK PLANNING POLICE PUBLIC WORKS
AND TRANSPORTS ATION CODES. THIS PERTAINS TO VARIOUS
BOARDS, COMMISSIONS AND ADVISORY BODIES.
PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON ITEM THREE SUPERVISOR CHAN CHIN NO
SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN NO SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY EYES
SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I SUPERVISOR RANDLEMAN HI
MENDELSON I SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR NO SUPERVISOR SADR SADR
EYES SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON NO
AND SUPERVISOR WONG WONG I THERE ARE SIX EYES AND FOUR NOS
WITH SUPERVISORS CHAN CHIN MELGAR AND WALTON VOTING NO THE
ORDINANCE IS FINALLY PASSED MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM
NUMBER FOUR ITEM FOUR. THIS IS AN ORDINANCE TO AMEND
THE ADMINISTRATIVE CODE TO CREATE THE DOWNTOWN HOSPITALITY
LOAN AND TO MAKE THE APPROPRIATE FINDINGS PLEASE
CALL THE ROLL ON ITEM FOUR SUPERVISOR CHAN CHIN EYES
SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN I SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I
SUPERVISE HER MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I SUPERVISOR RANDLEMAN HI MANDELL
MAN I SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SADR SADR I
SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I SUPERVISOR WALTON ALL RIGHT
WALTON I AND SUPERVISOR WONG WONG I THERE ARE CHINESE
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE ORDINANCE IS FINALLY PASSED MADAM CLERK
PLEASE CALL ITEMS FIVE AND SIX TOGETHER.
YES, ITEMS FIVE AND SIX TOGETHER.
ITEM FIVE IS A RESOLUTION TO DESIGNATE THE OUTREACH
COMMUNITY BASED WEEKLY AND ADVERTISING AND OUTREACH
NEIGHBORHOOD BASED MONTHLY ADVERTISING FOR THE FOLLOWING
NEWSPAPERS FOR THE OUTREACH COMMUNITY BASED WEEKLY
NEWSPAPER THE BAY AREA REPORTER FOR THE LESBIAN GAY BISEXUAL
AND TRANSGENDER COMMUNITY THE WIND NEWSPAPER FOR THE CHINESE
COMMUNITY FOR THE OUTREACH NEIGHBORHOOD BASED MONTHLY
NEWSPAPERS THE CLINT REILLY COMMUNICATIONS DOING BUSINESS
AS THE SAN FRANCISCO EXAMINER FOR THE EUREKA VALLEY EXCELSIOR
THE FINANCIAL DISTRICT. THE FOREST HILL HAIGHT ASHBURY
MARINA MISSION NORTH BEACH. PACIFIC HEIGHTS.
PRESIDIO HEIGHTS THE RICHMOND RUSSIAN HILL SOUTH OF MARKET
SUNSET AND THE TENDERLOIN NEIGHBORHOODS.
IT'LL TAKE A LOT FOR THE EXCELSIOR MISSION AND POTRERO
HILL NEIGHBORHOODS THE HENRYS SOCIETY JOURNAL FOR THE BAYVIEW
HUNTERS POINT VISITATION VALLEY AND WESTERN EDITION
NEIGHBORHOODS THE NOMI VALLEY BOYS FOR THE DIAMOND HEIGHTS
AND NOMI VALLEY NEIGHBORHOODS THE PICTURE OF YOU FOR THE
DOGPATCH EASTERN SOUTH OF MARKET MISSION BAY AND POTRERO
HILL NEIGHBORHOODS SAN FRANCISCO BAY TIMES FOR THE
CASTRO TO BOAST TRIANGLE MISSION AND THE SNOWY VALLEY
NEIGHBORHOODS THE SAN FRANCISCO CHRONICLE SERVING THE ENTIRE
CITY THE WORLD JOURNAL SERVING CHINATOWN INGLESIDE MISSION
RICHMOND AND SUNSET NEIGHBORHOODS THE SING DOW
DAILY FOR THE CHINATOWN RICHMOND SUNSET PORTOLA VALLEY
EXCELSIOR OUTER MISSION THE TENDERLOIN OCEAN VIEW INGLESIDE
AND THE MERCED HEIGHTS NEIGHBORHOODS AND THE ELDER
BOTERO FOR THE MISSION BERNAL HEIGHTS BAYVIEW AND EXCELSIOR
NEIGHBORHOODS FOR FISCAL YEAR 2026 THROUGH 27 AND FOR ITEM
SIX THIS RESOLUTION DESIGNATES THE CLINTON RILEY
COMMUNICATIONS DOING BUSINESS AS THE SAN FRANCISCO EXAMINER
TO BE THE OFFICIAL NEWSPAPER OF THE CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN
FRANCISCO FOR ALL OFFICIAL ADVERTISING FOR FISCAL YEAR
2026 THROUGH 2027. >> AND LET'S TAKE THESE ITEMS
SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTIONS ARE
ADOPTED. >> MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL
ITEM NUMBER SEVEN ITEM SEVEN THIS RESOLUTION AUTHORIZES THE
RECREATION AND PARK DEPARTMENT TO ENTER INTO AN AGREEMENT TO
LOAN UP TO 8.5 MILLION TO THE SAN FRANCISCO ZOOLOGICAL
SOCIETY TO SUPPORT THE OPERATION AND LONG TERM
FINANCIAL SUSTAINABILITY OF THE SAN FRANCISCO ZOO EFFECTIVE
UPON APPROVAL OF THIS RESOLUTION TO BE REPAID OVER
TEN YEARS IN THE FORM OF DEDUCTIONS FROM THE SAN
FRANCISCO ZOO'S MANAGEMENT FEE TO ALLOW THE CITY TO TERMINATE
THE LEASE AND MANAGEMENT AGREEMENT IN THE EVENT THE LOAN
IS NOT TIMELY REPAID OR IF THE CONDITIONS IN THE LOAN
AGREEMENT ARE OTHERWISE NOT MET .
>> AND AGAIN SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED. >> MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL
ITEM NUMBER EIGHT ITEM EIGHT THIS IS A RESOLUTION TO
AUTHORIZE AND APPROVE AN AGREEMENT WITH THE SUCCESSOR
AGENCY TO THE REDEVELOPMENT AGENCY ACTING IN ITS CAPACITY
AS THE LEGISLATIVE BODY OF COMMUNITY FACILITIES DISTRICT
NUMBER EIGHT THE HUNTERS POINT SHIPYARD MAINTENANCE DISTRICT
FOR THE CITY TO RECEIVE FUNDING FOR ITS OPERATION
AND MAINTENANCE OF THE HUNTERS POINT SHIPYARD PHASE ONE PARKS
AND OPEN SPACE SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL.
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTIONS ADOPTED MADAM CLERK
PLEASE CALL ITEM NUMBER NINE ITEM NINE THIS RESOLUTION
APPROVES THE 2023 LEASE AND USE AGREEMENT BETWEEN THE CITY
AND THE AIRPORT COMMISSION AND RZA CO LTD TO CONDUCT
FLIGHT OPERATIONS FOR A TERM COMMENCING ON THE FIRST DAY OF
THE CALENDAR MONTH IMMEDIATELY FOLLOWING THE RECEIPT OF FULL
CITY APPROVALS OF THE LEASE THROUGH JUNE 30TH 2033 AND TO
MAKE THE APPROPRIATE FINDINGS SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL.
>> WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED.
MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM NUMBER TEN.
>> ITEM TEN THIS IS A RESOLUTION TO AUTHORIZE A SIX
MONTH WAIVER OF THE CITY'S BEHEST AND PAYMENTS ORDINANCE
FOR THE MAYOR. MEMBERS OF THE MAYOR'S OFFICE
AND THE EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR OF THE OFFICE OF ECONOMIC
AND WORKFORCE DEVELOPMENT AND EACH OF THEIR DIRECT
REPORTS TO SOLICIT DONATIONS FROM NONPROFITS, PRIVATE
ORGANIZATIONS, GRANT MAKERS, FOUNDATIONS AND OTHER PERSONS
AND ENTITIES FOR THE PURPOSE OF SUPPORTING THE CONTINUED
ECONOMIC REVITALIZATION OF SAN FRANCISCO SUPERVISOR GENERAL
JUST REQUESTING FOR ROLL CALL OKAY MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL
THE ROLL ON ITEM TEN SUPERVISOR CHIN NO CHIN NO SUPERVISOR CHIN
CHIN I. SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I
SUPERVISOR MAHMUD MAHMUD I SUPERVISOR RANDLEMAN I MANDOLIN
I SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SADR SADR I
SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I
AND SUPERVISOR WONG WONG I THERE ARE NINE EYES AND ONE NO
WITH SUPERVISOR CHAN VOTING NO THE RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED MADAM
CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM 11. ITEM 11 THIS IS A RESOLUTION TO
APPROVE THE LIST OF PROJECTS TO BE FUNDED BY FISCAL YEAR 2026
THROUGH 2027. THE ROAD MAINTENANCE
AND REHABILITATION ACCOUNT FUNDS FOR THE LOCAL STREETS
AND ROADS PROGRAM AS ESTABLISHED BY CALIFORNIA
SENATE BILL ONE, THE ROAD REPAIR AND 2017 ACCOUNTABILITY
ACT PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON ITEM 11 SUPERVISOR YEAR CHAN I
CHIN I SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN I SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I
SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I SUPERVISOR RANDLEMAN I MANDOLIN
I SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SADR SADR I
SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I
AND SUPERVISOR WONG WONG I THERE ARE TEN EYES WITHOUT
OBJECTION THE RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL
ITEM NUMBER 12 ITEM 12 THIS IS A RESOLUTION TO DECLARE THE
INTENTION OF THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS TO RENEW AND EXPAND
THE PROPERTY BASED BUSINESS IMPROVEMENT DISTRICT KNOWN AS
THE DOWNTOWN COMMUNITY BENEFIT DISTRICT TO APPROVE THE
MANAGEMENT DISTRICT PLAN AND ENGINEER'S REPORT AND TO
AND PROPOSED BOUNDARIES MAP TO ORDER AND SET THE TIME IN PLACE
FOR THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS TO CONVENE A COMMITTEE OF THE
WHOLE WHICH WILL BE JULY 21ST 2026 AT 3 P.M. TO APPROVE THE
FORM OF THE NOTICE OF PUBLIC HEARING AND ASSESSMENT BALLOT
PROCEEDING AND ASSESSMENT BALLOTS TO DIRECT ENVIRONMENTAL
FINDINGS AND TO DIRECT THE CLERK OF THE BOARD TO PROVIDE
NOTICE OF THE PUBLIC HEARING AND BALLOTING.
>> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
RESOLUTIONS ADOPTED. >> MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL
ITEM NUMBER 13 ITEM 13 THIS IS AN ORDINANCE TO AMEND THE
ADMINISTRATIVE CODE TO ESTABLISH THE SAN FRANCISCO
HATE CRIME REWARD FUNDS. >> SUPERVISOR DORSEY THANK YOU
PRESIDENT RANDLEMAN COLLEAGUES AS THIS LEGISLATION CREATING A
HATE CRIME REWARD FUND COMES BEFORE US TODAY ON FIRST
READING I THINK IT'S APPROPRIATE THAT WE REMEMBER
THREE VICTIMS WHO LOST THEIR LIVES YESTERDAY IN A SENSELESS
ATTACK AT A SAN DIEGO MOSQUE. AND TO EXPRESS OUR CONDOLENCES
TO THEIR FAMILY MEMBERS AND LOVED ONES AS WELL AS TO
THE COMMUNITIES UNDERSTANDABLY SHAKEN BY THIS TRAGEDY.
THIS HORRIFIC CRIME BY TWO PERPETRATORS WHO APPEAR TO HAVE
TAKEN THEIR OWN LIVES IS BEING INVESTIGATED BY AUTHORITIES AS
A HATE CRIME. AND AS THE NEW YORK TIMES
REPORTED THIS MORNING, THE ATTACK HAS CALLED FURTHER
ATTENTION TO CONCERNS ABOUT INCREASING ISLAMOPHOBIA IN THE
UNITED STATES. HATE CRIMES ARE UNIQUELY
CORROSIVE TO A FREE SOCIETY IN AS MUCH AS THEY INTEND HARM
NOT SOLELY TO INDIVIDUAL VICTIMS BUT TO INSTILL
PERVASIVE FEAR IN VULNERABLE COMMUNITIES.
THAT IS WHY CITIES THAT CHERISH THE BLESSINGS OF DIVERSITY
AND PLURALISM LIKE SAN FRANCISCO AND LIKE SAN DIEGO
FOR THAT MATTER MUST DO EVERYTHING WE CAN TO HELP OUR
DIVERSE COMMUNITIES FEEL SAFE REGARDLESS OF RELIGION, RACE,
SEXUAL ORIENTATIONS, GENDER IDENTITIES OR THE BACKGROUNDS
THEY REFLECT. THIS LEGISLATION IS MODELED ON
THE UPDATED HOMICIDE REWARD FUND WE UNANIMOUSLY ENACTED A
YEAR AGO. IT'S ABOUT SUPPORTING VICTIMS,
PROTECTING TARGETED COMMUNITIES, STRENGTHENING
ACCOUNTABILITY AND ENCOURAGING MEMBERS OF THE PUBLIC TO COME
FORWARD WITH INFORMATION IF IT CAN HELP ENSURE THE JUSTICE IS
DONE. I WANT TO THANK MY CO-SPONSOR
SUPERVISORS HUANG SADR AND SHERYL.
>> AND I HOPE WE'LL HAVE YOUR SUPPORT.
THANKS PROVIDED DORSEY LET'S TAKE THIS ITEM SAME HOUSE, SAME
CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE ORDINANCE IS PASSED ON FIRST
READING MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM NUMBER 14 ITEM 14
THIS IS A MOTION TO APPROVE THE MAYOR'S NOMINATION FOR
REAPPOINTMENT OF JANETTE HOWARD TO THE TREASURE ISLAND
DEVELOPMENT AUTHORITY BOARD OF DIRECTORS FOR A TERM ENDING
FEBRUARY 26TH, 2029 AND WE'LL TAKE THAT SAME HOUSE SAME CALL
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE MOTION IS APPROVED.
>> MADAME CLERK LET'S GO TO ROLL CALL SUPERVISOR CHAN YOUR
FIRST UP TO INTRODUCE NEW BUSINESS.
>> >> THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK TODAY COLLEAGUES I HAVE TWO
IN MEMORY EMS. FIRST WITH GREAT SADNESS I
WOULD LIKE TO ADJOURN TODAY'S MEETING IN THE MEMORY OF MR.
KENNETH LEUNG. >> KENNETH KENNY OR MR. RAO
PASS AWAY ON MAY 1ST AT A WONDERFUL AGE OF 96 HE LIVED A
LONG FULL LIFE HAS ESPECIALLY IN HIS LATER YEARS WHERE HE
ENJOYED EVERY MOMENT CONNECTING WITH THE COMMUNITY THROUGH
MUSIC AND PLAYING HIS FAVORITE INSTRUMENTS AT HIS STORE ON
JACKSON STREET IN CHINATOWN, KENNY AND HIS WIFE LOUISE WERE
PROUD OWNERS OF ALLEY AND IVA COMPANY, A REPUTABLE
NEIGHBORHOOD MUSIC STORE IN CHINATOWN FIRST FOUNDED
IN 1970, HE WAS EXTREMELY PROUD OF HIS ACHIEVEMENTS WHEN ALLEY
AND YUVA BECAME HIS SAN FRANCISCO LEGACY BUSINESS
IN 2023. THEY RECOGNITION GAVE HIS STORE
A SECOND LIFE WHEN HIS SHOP WAS PROPELLED INTO THE
INTERNATIONAL MUSICIANS SCENE, HE FOUND HIMSELF IN HIS
RETIREMENT YEARS GIVING INTERVIEWS TO MEDIA OUTLETS
FROM HONG KONG, CHINA AND SINGAPORE AND GREETING
REPUTABLE MUSICIANS FROM ACROSS THE PACIFIC.
IN 2023 HIS SHOP WAS SELECTED TO BE A PART OF THE APAC
CONFERENCE IN SAN FRANCISCO WHERE EVERY ATTENDEE HAD A
CHANCE TO TAKE HOME SOMETHING FROM HIS SHOP AND SECOND
IN MEMORIAM. TODAY COLLEAGUES I WOULD LIKE
TO OFFER IS TO MR. GERALD WARREN JOHNSON BORN JANUARY 28,
1925. GERALD WAS A PROUD SON OF NEW
ORLEANS WHOSE LIFE EMBODIED COURAGE, RESILIENCE
AND STEADFAST COMMITMENT TO JUSTICE AND OPPORTUNITY RAISED
DURING SEGREGATION. HE MOVED TO SAN FRANCISCO
IN 1946 AND BECAME AN EARLY ADVOCATE FOR CIVIL RIGHTS
BRAVELY CHALLENGING DISCRIMINATION LONG BEFORE THE
MOVEMENT GAINED NATIONAL ATTENTION IN 1984 ALONGSIDE
WITH HIS WIFE VALERIE GERALD CO-FOUNDED THE SMALL BUSINESS
EXCHANGE NEWSPAPERS CREATING OPPORTUNITIES FOR MINORITY
AND WOMEN OWNED BUSINESSES ACROSS THE COUNTRY.
>> THROUGH HIS LEADERSHIP AND VISION, HE HELPED OPEN
DOORS FOR COUNTLESS UNDERSERVED ENTREPRENEURS AND BECAME A
CHAMPION FOR ECONOMIC INCLUSION AND COMMUNITY EMPOWERMENT.
HE WAS A DEVOTED FATHER TO SARA DOMINGO AND KIMBERLY JOHNSON AS
WELL AS GRANDCHILDREN SARA AND DANIEL.
GERALD'S LEGACY WAS ROOTED NOT ONLY IN HIS PUBLIC
ACCOMPLISHMENTS BUT ALSO IN THE LOVE GUIDANCE AND STRENGTH HE
SHARE WITH HIS FAMILY IN THE BAY AREA AND NEW ORLEANS.
THROUGH HIS INFLUENCE REACH FAR BEYOND NEW ORLEANS, GERALD
CARRY THE SPIRIT AND VALUES OF HIS HOMETOWN.
THROUGHOUT HIS LIFE HE CHAMPIONED LEGENDARY
CONTRIBUTION TO THE SAN FRANCISCO COMMUNITY THROUGH
ORGANIZING AND ADVOCATING FOR SOCIAL JUSTICE AND EQUAL
EMPLOYMENT OPPORTUNITIES. HE IS REMEMBERED FOR HIS
STRENGTH, UNWAVERING INTEGRITY AND DEDICATION TO UPLIFTING
OTHERS. HIS LEGACY CONTINUES TO INSPIRE
FUTURE GENERATION TO PURSUE FAIRNESS, EQUALITY
AND OPPORTUNITY FOR ALL. >> AND THE REST I SUBMIT.
THANK YOU. THANK YOU SUPERVISOR CHAN.
>> SUPERVISOR CHEN THANK YOU, MADAM CHAIR.
I HAVE ONE CHARTER AMENDMENT INTRODUCTION, ONE RESOLUTION
AND ONE HEARING COLLEAGUES OVER THE LAST FEW WEEKS MY OFFICE
HAS BEEN BUSY PREPARING A CHARTER AMENDMENT FOR A NEW
MUNICIPAL FINANCE CORPORATION AND PUBLIC BANK SAN FRANCISCO
HAS BEEN GRAPPLING TO EVENTS LARGE SCALE SOLUTION THAT CAN
ADDRESS OUR HOUSING AFFORDABILITY CHALLENGES AS
THIS SMALL BUSINESS TO THRIVE AND TO SURVIVE AND FINANCE THE
INVESTMENT NEEDED TO ACHIEVE CLIMATE SUSTAINED
SUSTAINABILITY WE NEED AND DESERVE BOLD SOLUTION TO
ADDRESS OUR MOST PRESSING CHALLENGES AND WE MUST USE
EVERY TOOL WE CAN TO KEEP SAN FRANCISCO AFFORDABLE TO SUSTAIN
OUR LOCAL COMMUNITIES AND LEAD TOWARD A MORE JUST ECONOMIC
RECOVERY FOR ALL A MUNICIPAL FINANCE CORPORATION AND PUBLIC
BANK AS TRIED AND TESTED SOLUTION THAT HAS PROVEN ITS
IMPACT ON LOCAL COMMUNITIES. THE BANK OF NEVADA CODA WHICH
HAS A POPULATION THE SIZE OF SAN FRANCISCO, HAS CONSISTENTLY
DELIVERED PROFIT SUPPORTING ECONOMIC DEVELOPMENT
AND KEEPING THE LOCAL ECONOMY STABLE EVEN DURING THE 22,008
FINANCIAL CRISIS AND COVID PANDEMIC, PUBLIC BANKS MAGNIFY
MAGNIFY THE POWER OF THEIR INVESTMENTS BY REINVESTING ALL
PROFITS BACK INTO LENDING FOR THE COMMUNITY AROUND THE WORLD
MORE THAN A QUARTER OF THE WORLD'S ASSETS ARE HELD
IN PUBLIC BANKS. >> THE CALIFORNIA PUBLIC BANK
ACT, WHICH WAS AUTHORIZED BY CITY ATTORNEY DAVID CHIU,
PROVIDES A PATHWAY FOR SAN FRANCISCO TO TAKE THIS STEP.
>> THIS CHARTER AMENDMENT CODIFIES THE MISSION PRINCIPLES
AND BUSINESS PLANS THAT WERE DEVELOPED AT BY LOCAL EXPERTS
IN COLLABORATION WITH NATIONAL CONSULTANTS AND ACCEPTED BY THE
BOARD OF SUPERVISORS. IT ESTABLISHES GOOD GOVERNANCE
STRUCTURES APPOINTED BY AN OVERSIGHT BODY SELECTED BY THE
TREASURY COMPTROLLER, CITY ATTORNEY, MAYOR AND BOARD
SUPERVISORS WHICH SIGNIFICANTLY SAFEGUARDS OVERSIGHT AND CHECKS
AND BALANCES TO PROTECT THE PUBLIC INTERESTS.
>> IT ENSURES THAT MUNICIPAL FINANCE CORPORATION AND PUBLIC
BANK WILL BE RUN BY STUDENT BANKING PROFESSIONALS BANKERS
WHO WILL UPHOLD FINANCIAL INDUSTRY BEST PRACTICES
AND RIGOROUS FINANCIAL MANAGEMENT.
THE FINANCE OF THE MUNICIPAL FINANCE CORPORATION AND PUBLIC
BANK WILL NOT CO-MINGLE WITH THE CITY AND COUNTY AND HAVE NO
IMPACT ON THE GENERAL FUND. THE MUNICIPAL FINANCIAL
CORPORATION WILL PARTNER WITH LOCAL CREDIT UNIONS
AND COMMUNITY DEVELOPMENT FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS TO
DEVELOP SPECIALIZED LENDING PRODUCTS BASED ON THE GAPS
AND NEEDS ANALYSIS ANALYSIS IDENTIFIED IT IN THE BUSINESS
PLAN. THIS LENDING CAN SERVE A WIDE
RANGE OF SAN FRANCISCO'S NEEDS FROM ACQUISITIONS OF
MULTIFAMILY HOUSING UNDER THE CITY'S SMALL SITES PROGRAM
COMMUNITY LAND TRUST PROJECTS, BUILDING ELECTRIFICATION
PROJECTS, SUPPORTING SMALL BUSINESS OWNERS TO EXPAND
AND EVEN HELPING TO ENABLE THE TRANSITION OF LEGACY BUSINESS
TO WORKERS OWNERSHIP AND TO NAME A FEW.
I WANT TO REALLY ACKNOWLEDGE MY LEGISLATIVE AIDE IN THE OFFICE
FOR HISTORIC PART OF THIS CHARTER AMENDMENT, CHARLIE
SIMMONS. >> AND I'M ALSO VERY GRATEFUL
FOR THE CRITICAL LEADERSHIP OF THE SAN FRANCISCO PUBLIC
COALITIONS PUBLIC BANK COALITION AND THE SAN FRANCISCO
REINVESTMENT WORKING GROUP. >> I ALSO WANT TO APPRECIATE
CALI SUMMARY OF THE LOCAL AGENCY FORMATION COMMISSION.
WIKI WONG AND MO JAMAL WITH THE CITY ATTORNEY AND AMANDA FREE
OF THE TREASURER'S OFFICE FOR THEIR PARTNERSHIP.
I WANT TO THANK ALL MY EARLY CO-SPONSORS SUPERVISOR FIELDER
WALTON MALKA AND MOVE. >> TODAY I'M ALSO INTRODUCING A
RESOLUTION TO DECLARE AUGUST 28TH, 2026 AS JUNE JORDAN
SCHOOL FOR EQUITY DAY IN SAN FRANCISCO IN RECOGNITION OF ITS
OUTSTANDING CONTRIBUTION TO EDUCATIONAL EQUITY.
YOU LEADERSHIP, EDUCATION AND COMMUNITY EMPOWERMENT JEN
JORDAN OPENED IN 2003 AND WAS INTENTIONALLY DESIGNED TO BE A
SMALL PUBLIC SCHOOL SPECIALIZING IN SOCIAL JUSTICE,
RESTORATIVE PRACTICES, YOUTH VOICE AND ACADEMIC SUCCESS.
>> THE SCHOOL CARRIES ON THE LEGACY OF ACCLAIMED BLACK
FEMINIST POET EDUCATOR AND ACTIVIST JUNE JORDAN IN ITS
STEADFAST COMMITMENT TO SOCIAL JUSTICE AND LIBERATION.
>> SERVING PREDOMINANTLY STUDENTS FROM WORKING CLASS
AND LOW INCOME COMMUNITIES OF COLOR FROM THE SOUTHEAST SIDE
OF THE CITY JUNE JORDAN STRIVED TO IMPROVE ACCESS TO EDUCATION
AND NARROW ACHIEVEMENT IN GAP WITH PRIVATE SCHOOL QUALITY
EDUCATION ATTENTIVE SUPPORT AND STUDIES UNPACKING A
PERSON'S TEACHERS, EDUCATORS, COUNSELORS AND STAFF WORK
TIRELESSLY EVERY DAY TO NURTURE STUDENTS TO BECOME LEADERS
AND AGENTS OF POSITIVE CHANGES IN THE COMMUNITY.
STUDENTS BUILD KEY COMPETENCIES AND GRADUATE WITH STRONG
AND THOUGHTFUL POST-SECONDARY PLANS.
>> THEY LIVE, EMPOWER LEARNING ABOUT ACCOUNTABILITY THE FORCE
OF MARGINALIZED ASIAN HUMANITY INTEGRITY, COURAGEOUS RESPECT
AND COMMUNITY IMPACT IN THE FACE OF TODAY'S CHALLENGING
LANDSCAPE. JORDAN REMAINS A VITAL
COMMUNITY ANCHORED DEEPLY ROOTED IN DIGNITY, BELONGING
CULTURAL INFORMATION, COLLECTIVE RESPONSIBILITY
AND EQUITY FOR YOUTH. THANK YOU COLLEAGUES AND FOR
YOUR SUPPORT IN UPLIFTING JEN JORDAN'S SCHOOL FOR EQUITY
AND FOR THEIR OUTSTANDING CONTRIBUTION TO EDUCATION,
EQUITY AND COMMUNITY EMPOWERMENT.
LASTLY, COLLEAGUES TODAY I'M ALSO INTRODUCING A HEARING
REQUESTS ON THEIR $4.7 MILLION CONTRACT THAT WAS AWARDED TO A
SINGLE ORGANIZATION WITHOUT COMPETITIVE BID BY THE
DEPARTMENT OF HOMELESSNESS AND SUPPORTIVE HOUSING.
>> IN THE MONTHS AFTER THE AWARD THERE WERE QUESTIONS
ABOUT HOW THE ORGANIZATION RECEIVING THE AWARD WAS CHOSEN
AND WHAT THE GOAL WAS. >> CRITERIA EXPECTED OUTCOME OF
THE CONTRACT INCLUDING THOSE QUESTIONS ARE STILL LEFT
UNANSWERED. >> IT DOES CONTRACT DIRECTS NEW
RESOURCES TO OPENING NEW OFFICES IN COMMUNITIES WHERE
EXISTING SIMILAR SERVICES ARE BEING CUT.
GIVEN THE BUDGET FOCUS WE OWE OUR COMMUNITY ESPECIALLY THOSE
RELYING ON THOSE THOSE SERVICES A TRANSPARENCY FROM THE
DEPARTMENT ABOUT HOW THIS DECISIONS ARE BEING MADE.
>> I'M REQUESTING THAT THE MAYOR'S OFFICE MAYOR'S OFFICE
OF HOUSING AND COMMUNITY DEVELOPMENT AND THE DEPARTMENT
ON HOMELESSNESS AND SUPPORTIVE HOUSING REPORT AND THEIR BEST
ASSESSMENT. >> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR CHEN WILL RETURN TO
ROLL CALL FOR INTRODUCTIONS. >> MR. PRESIDENT.
MADAM CLERK, LET'S GO TO OUR 2:30 P.M. SPECIAL ORDER.
>> IT'S NOW TIME FOR THE RECOGNITION AGAIN OF
COMMENDATIONS FOR MERITORIOUS SERVICE TO THE CITY AND COUNTY
OF SAN FRANCISCO. >> WE WILL START WITH DISTRICT
THREE SUPERVISOR SAUTER THANK YOU, PRESIDENT MAILMAN.
>> COLLEAGUES TODAY I HAVE THE HONOR OF WELCOMING CHINATOWN
TRIP TO OUR CHAMBERS FOR A SPECIAL RECOGNITION TRIP.
WOULD YOU ALL PLEASE COME ON UP AND JOIN US AS WE CELEBRATE
AAPI MONTH WE HAVE A BIG MILESTONE TO MARK CHINATOWN
TRIP IS 50 YEARS OLD. TRIP STANDS FOR TRANSPORTATION
RESEARCH AND IMPROVEMENT PROJECT AND FOR FIVE DECADES
THIS PROJECT HAS TURNED INTO A LEGACY OF FIGHTING FOR BETTER
PUBLIC TRANSIT AND IMPROVED PEDESTRIAN SAFETY IN CHINATOWN.
TRIP WAS BORN OUT OF THE STRIKE OF 1976 WHICH LEFT SAN
FRANCISCO WITHOUT BUS TROLLEY OR CABLE CAR SERVICE FOR A VERY
LONG SIX WEEKS. >> A GROUP OF CHINESE-AMERICAN
BUS DRIVERS INCLUDING PHIL CHEN LANDED ON MIKE YAP AND TERRY
CHAO SPRUNG INTO ACTION AFTER THEY REALIZED HOW THE STRIKE
WAS LEAVING THOUSANDS OF CHINATOWN SENIORS STRANDED.
>> THE DRIVERS TEAMED UP WITH NONE OTHER THAN ANY CHANG FROM
SELF-HELP FOR THE ELDERLY TO START AN IMPROMPTU TRANSIT
SERVICE FOR SENIORS. THEY TOOK TURNS DRIVING THEIR
CARS MANNING DISPATCH RADIOS AND HELPING SENIORS GET TO
GROCERIES, MEDICAL APPOINTMENTS AND TO SEE FRIENDS.
THIS AD HOC SERVICE WAS ESTABLISHED THREE YEARS BEFORE
S.F. MTA HAD THEIR OWN PARATRANSIT SERVICE AND IT
WOULD HELP INSPIRE TODAY'S MUCH USE SENIOR ESCORT PROGRAM AT
SELF-HELP FOR THE ELDERLY. >> AFTER THE STRIKE ENDED, THE
ORGANIZERS SHIFT THEIR FOCUS TO IMPROVING BUS SERVICE TO BETTER
SERVE CHINATOWN. THEIR EARLY FIGHTS STILL SHAPE
THE LINES WE KNOW AND LOVE TODAY.
>> FOR EXAMPLE, CHINATOWN TRIP WAS INSTRUMENTAL IN ALLOWING
THE NUMBER 55 SACRAMENTO GO TO EVOLVE INTO THE NUMBER ONE
CALIFORNIA BRINGING SERVICE FROM THE FINANCIAL DISTRICT TO
CHINATOWN AND FURTHER INTO THE RICHMOND.
AND THIS VERY MORNING I WAITED TO GET ON THE ONE FOR 25
MINUTES FOR PACKED BUSSES. I GOT ON THE FIFTH ONE AT
PORTLAND CLAY. AND SO IT'S TIME THAT WE GET
BACK TOGETHER AND IMPROVE THE ONE ONCE AGAIN.
ANOTHER EARLY CAMPAIGN RESULTED IN A NEW BUS LINE THE NUMBER 83
PACIFIC WHICH WE NOW KNOW AS THE NUMBER ONE PACIFIC AFTER
HIGHER UPS AT MTA BALKED AT A BUS ROUTE RUNNING ALONG PACIFIC
AVENUE BECAUSE IT WAS DEEMED TOO NARROW.
MIKE AND LANDY MADE AN IMPROMPTU DECISION TO DIVERT
ANOTHER ROUTE AND DRIVE ALONG PACIFIC AVENUE TO PROVE THAT IT
WOULD WORK OUT. AND TODAY AND TO THIS DAY IT
DOES WORK OUT. CHINATOWN TRIP BUT SOON LINKED
UP LINK UP WITH OTHER GRASSROOTS GROUPS FOCUSED ON
THEIR OWN ISSUES FROM PARKS TO HOUSING AND COMBINE EFFORTS
INTO A NEW ORGANIZATION CHINATOWN RESOURCE CENTER.
THAT GROUP EVOLVED INTO WHAT WE NOW KNOW TODAY AS CHINATOWN
COMMUNITY DEVELOPMENT CENTER OR.
>> FIVE DECADES AGO PUBLIC TRANSIT WAS AT A BREAKING POINT
WITH OUR CITY GROUND TO A HALT FROM A STRIKE.
TODAY THE REASON MAY BE DIFFERENT BUT WE ARE YET AGAIN
AT A PIVOTAL POINT FOR THE FUTURE OF PUBLIC TRANSIT.
I WANT TO RECOGNIZE WHAT I SAW HERE EARLIER THE DIRECTOR OF
S.F. CTA TILLY CHANG IS IN THE CHAMBERS AS WELL.
HI TILLY. THANK YOU FOR JOINING US.
CHINATOWN TRIP I'M VERY, VERY GRATEFUL FOR THE LEGACY YOU
HAVE BUILT OVER THESE PAST FIVE DECADES.
I CANNOT IMAGINE DISTRICT THREE OR CHINATOWN WITHOUT YOUR
ADVOCACY. THANK YOU FOR YOUR PAST 50
YEARS. THANK YOU FOR COMMITTING TO
ANOTHER 50 YEARS WHICH WE SO BADLY NEED TOGETHER.
>> AND THE FLOOR IS YOURS IF YOU WANT TO OFFER A FEW REMARKS
. >> YES.
MY NAME IS LADY DOG AND I'M HERE TO THANK GOD SUPERVISOR
DANNY SATO FOR THE RECOGNITION OF CHINATOWN TRIPS 50TH YEAR OF
EXISTENCE. AND LET ME TELL YOU BACK THEN I
NEVER REALIZED THAT I WOULD BE UP HERE STILL DOING THIS.
>> IT'S INCREDIBLE AND WE CAME TOGETHER AS COMMUNITY MEMBERS
TO CREATE A GRASSROOT. >> WE CAME TOGETHER AS A
COMMUNITY GRASSROOTS GROUP. >> WE WERE CONCERNED WITH POOR
QUALITY TRANSIT AND TRANSPORTATION ISSUES
AFFECTING OUR GROWING COMMUNITY OVER THE FIVE DECADES ALONG
WITH OUR PARTNERS DC WE'VE DEVELOPED COOPERATIVE
RELATIONSHIPS WITH VARIOUS CITIES AGENCIES MOST NOTABLY
WITH THE MTA IN ACCOMPLISHING OUR GOALS.
OUR INITIAL SUCCESS WAS THE IMPROVEMENT OF THE SCHEDULING
OF THE NUMBER 30 STOCKTON BUS AND EVEN CAR NOTED THE THE
CHRONICLE SUN COLUMNISTS OCCASIONAL WRITES ABOUT 30
STOCKTON. >> IN OTHER WORDS FOR
ADVOCATING A TRAFFIC LIGHT PAUL AND PACIFIC TO DO A PEDESTRIAN
FATALITY. >> AND BACK THEN THEY SAID NO
WAY. WHY IT COST $10,000 PER CORNER
TO 40 THOUSAND. >> AND NOWADAYS HOW MUCH DOES
IT COST? ABOUT A MILLION AND A HALF JUST
TO INSTALL A SIMPLE SIGNAL LIGHT.
SO OVER TIME WE HAVE TRULY BECOME ENDURING.
CIVIC PARTNERS. THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
THANK YOU. AND WE HAVE PROBABLY THE
COOLEST SWAG I'VE SEEN. WE HAVE SOME MUNI SWAG FOR YOU
ALL SO I'LL COME AROUND WITH YOU.
>> WE'LL GET YOU YOUR SWAG GOING TO THE PICTURE.
THANKS. THANK YOU.
WHERE ARE THEY GOING? DISTRICT FOR SUPERVISOR WONG.
GOOD AFTERNOON, COLLEAGUES. TODAY I'M PROUD TO RECOGNIZE
NATIONAL EMERGENCY MEDICAL SERVICES WEEK.
WE'RE I'D LIKE TO INVITE OUR GUESTS TO JOIN US UP ON THE
PODIUM. >> HEY, I'M PROUD TO RECOGNIZE
NATIONAL EMERGENCY MEDICAL SERVICES WEEK AND COMMEND THEIR
EXTRAORDINARY PROFESSIONALS AND COMMUNITY PARTNERS WHO MAKE
WHO MAKE SAN FRANCISCO'S EMERGENCY MEDICAL RESPONSE
SYSTEM. I ALSO WANT TO THANK ASSISTANT
DEPUTY CHIEF MALLOY, CHIEF BRATTON, CHIEF RABBIT CAPTAIN
TOM NURSE PROGRAM COORDINATOR PREVENTION OFFICER, HOME
AND ALL THE REPRESENTATIVES FROM THE SAN FRANCISCO FIRE
DEPARTMENT AND OUR BROADER EMERGENCY RESPONSE COMMUNITY.
AND TO THOSE WHO ARE NOT HERE BECAUSE THEY ARE OUT THERE
DOING THE WORK RIGHT NOW SERVING SAN FRANCISCANS IN REAL
TIME. >> WE THANK YOU AS WELL.
NATIONAL EMS WEEK IS A MOMENT FOR COMMUNITIES ACROSS THE
COUNTRY TO RECOGNIZE THE PEOPLE WHO STAND ON THE FRONT LINES OF
EMERGENCY CARE. THAT RECOGNITION FEELS
ESPECIALLY MEANINGFUL THIS WEEK AS JUST YESTERDAY OUR CITY
HONORED OUTSTANDING INDIVIDUALS ACROSS THE FULL SPECTRUM OF SAN
FRANCISCO'S EMS SYSTEM FROM EMERGENCY COMMUNICATION LINES
AND FIRST RESPONDERS TO FIELD OPERATIONS, HOSPITAL BASED
EMERGENCY CARE DISASTER PREPAREDNESS, COMMUNITY
PARTNERSHIP LEADERSHIP AND THE EXPANDING FIELD OF COMMUNITY
MEDICINE. I'M PROUD TO BE A NURSE TRAINED
VOLUNTEER MYSELF AND HAVE WORKED FOR THE AMERICAN RED
CROSS PUBLIC SAFETY AS THE PROMISE WE MAKE TO EVERY SAN
FRANCISCAN. AND THAT PROMISE DEPENDS ON THE
PROFESSIONALS WHO ANSWER THE CALL OFTEN ON SOMEONE'S MOST
DIFFICULT DAY BRINGING NOT ONLY TECHNICAL EXPERTISE
AND DECISIVE ACTION BUT CALM COMPASSION AND REASSURANCE WHEN
IT MATTERS MOST. WHAT MAKES A STRONG EMS SYSTEM
IS NOT JUST INDIVIDUAL EXCELLENCE BUT COORDINATION,
TRUST AND SHARED PURPOSE. IT IS THE DISPATCHER CALMLY
GUIDING A CALLER THROUGH A CRISIS.
THE EMTS AND PARAMEDICS MAKING SPLIT SECOND DECISIONS IN THE
FIELD. THE HOSPITAL TEAMS DELIVERING
LIFESAVING CARE. THE COMMUNITY PARTNERS HELPING
EXTEND THE SUPPORT BEYOND THE EMERGENCY ITSELF.
TOGETHER THESE PROFESSIONALS WORK AROUND THE CLOCK OFTEN
UNDER IMMENSE PRESSURE TO PROTECT AND IMPROVE THE LIVES
OF SAN FRANCISCANS. >> THEIR SERVICE REFLECTS THE
VERY BEST OF THE CITY. PROFESSIONALISM, RESILIENCE,
COMPASSION AND AN UNWAVERING COMMITMENT TO OTHERS.
ON BEHALF OF THE RESIDENTS OF SAN FRANCISCO AND ESPECIALLY
OUR DISTRICT FOR OUR COMMUNITIES, THANK YOU FOR YOUR
LEADERSHIP, DEDICATION AND EXTRAORDINARY SERVICE.
WITH THAT IT'S MY HONOR TO BE ABLE TO HONOR AND COMMEND THE
THESE EXTRAORDINARY EMS PROFESSIONALS AND EMERGENCY
RESPONSE PARTNERS WHOSE SERVICE HELPS KEEP SAN FRANCISCANS SAFE
EVERY SINGLE DAY. AND I'D LIKE TO INVITE
ASSISTANT DEPUTY CHIEF MALLOY TO SAY A FEW WORDS.
>> GOOD AFTERNOON AND THANK YOU FOR THE RECOGNITION DURING EMS
WEEK. I'M TRULY HONORED TO ACCEPT IT
ON BEHALF OF THE ENTIRE EMERGENCY MEDICAL SERVICES
COMMUNITY. >> I WANT TO ACKNOWLEDGE THE
EXTRAORDINARY DEDICATION OF ALL OUR EMS PROVIDERS PARAMEDICS,
COMMUNITY PARAMEDICS, EMTS, FIREFIGHTERS ALONG WITH
DISPATCHERS, NURSES, LAW ENFORCEMENT PARTNERS AND THE
MANY SUPPORT STAFF WHO KEEP THE SYSTEM RUNNING EVERY HOUR OF
EVERY DAY. >> THERE THERE THEIR COMMITMENT
,SKILL AND COMPASSION ARE WHAT MAKE OUR EMERGENCY RESPONSE
SYSTEM STRONG. >> THEY SHOW UP IN PEOPLE'S
HARDEST MOMENTS AND THEY DO IT WITH PROFESSIONALISM, EMPATHY
AND COURAGE. AGAIN, ONCE AGAIN I'D LIKE TO
HUMBLY THANK YOU AND ACCEPT ON THEIR BEHALF AND AND BE
AND BEFORE YOU TAKE YOUR PHOTO I MISSED SUPERVISOR CHEN IN THE
QUEUE. >> SUPERVISOR CHEN, THANK YOU
BOTH PERSONALLY. AMENDMENT I WAS JUST WANT TO
ECHO AND EXPRESS MY DEEP GRATITUDE AND APPRECIATION FOR
THE ENTIRE TEAM AND THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR KEEPING OUR
COMMUNITY SAFE ESPECIALLY YOU KNOW WE JUST HAD OUR NURSE
TRAINING IN DISTRICT 11 KEEPING OUR NEIGHBORHOODS SAFE.
I REALLY APPRECIATE APPRECIATE THE DEDICATION, THE
PROFESSIONALISM THAT YOU ARE PROVIDING AND KEEPING EVERYONE
SAFE IN SAN FRANCISCO. THANK YOU.
YOU CAN
KNOW SUPERVISOR DORSEY. >> YOU'VE GOT TWO TODAY.
I DO. THANK YOU, PRESIDENT MALVERN
COLLEAGUES. I HAVE THE PLEASURE OF
RECOGNIZING A VALUED MEMBER OF SAN FRANCISCO'S IRISH COMMUNITY
AND AN OUTSTANDING PUBLIC SERVANT.
THE REPUBLIC OF IRELAND'S CONSUL GENERAL TO THE WESTERN
UNITED STATES, MITCHEL SMITH. >> HE HELPED TO RECOVER THE
CAPACITY. AND WHAT MAKES THIS RECOGNITION
ESPECIALLY TIMELY IS THAT CONSUL GENERAL SMITH WILL BE
DEPARTING SAN FRANCISCO LATER THIS MONTH FOLLOWING A
DISTINGUISHED TEN YEAR REPRESENTING IRELAND HERE ON
THE WEST COAST OF THE UNITED STATES.
>> CONSUL GENERAL SMITH HAILS FROM THE VILLAGE OF CARMEL
IN COUNTY ARMAGH, NORTHERN IRELAND.
A BEAUTIFUL COMMUNITY NESTLED NEAR THE RING OF GILLIAM
AND KNOWN FOR ITS DEEP HISTORY, STRONG SENSE OF IDENTITY
AND BREATHTAKING LANDSCAPE. FROM THOSE ROOTS HE'S BUILT AN
EXTRAORDINARY INTERNATIONAL CAREER DEDICATED TO
STRENGTHENING IRELAND'S GLOBAL GLOBAL PRESENCE AND DEEPENING
RELATIONSHIPS AROUND THE WORLD. BEFORE COMING TO SAN FRANCISCO,
CONSUL GENERAL SMITH SERVED AS DIRECTOR OF GLOBAL IRELAND
IN IRELAND'S DEPARTMENT OF FOREIGN AFFAIRS WHERE HE HELPED
LEAD MAJOR EFFORTS AND EXPAND IRELAND'S INTERNATIONAL
ENGAGEMENT PROMOTE IRELAND AS A PLACE TO LIVE, WORK, INVEST
AND STUDY AND STRENGTHEN CONNECTIONS BETWEEN IRELAND
AND COMMUNICATE COMMUNITIES ACROSS THE GLOBE.
OVER THE COURSE OF HIS CAREER HE HAS SERVED IN LEADERSHIP
ROLES ACROSS ASIA, THE MIDDLE EAST AND THE UNITED STATES,
INCLUDING HELPING ESTABLISH IDA IRELAND'S FIRST SOUTH EAST
ASIAN OFFICE IN SINGAPORE AND LEADING ECONOMIC
DEVELOPMENT EFFORTS THAT STRENGTHENED TIES BETWEEN
IRELAND AND MAJOR INTERNATIONAL COMPANIES.
HIS WORK HAS HELPED EXPAND IRELAND'S ECONOMIC, CULTURAL
AND DIPLOMATIC INFLUENCE WORLDWIDE.
>> HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO, CONSUL GENERAL SMITH HAS
CONTINUED THAT TRADITION OF LEADERSHIP WHILE STRENGTHENING
THE DEEP AND HISTORIC TIES BETWEEN IRELAND AND THE BAY
AREA. AS SOMEONE WITH IRISH ROOTS ON
BOTH SIDES OF MY OWN FAMILY THE DORSEY'S OF GALWAY AND THE
COUNTIES OF ROSCOMMON I AM ESPECIALLY APPRECIATIVE FOR THE
IMPORTANT CONNECTIONS AND THE ROLE THAT IRELAND'S DIPLOMATIC
COMMUNITY PLAYS IN KEEPING THEM VIBRANT FOR FUTURE GENERATIONS.
FOR THE PAST TWO YEARS I'VE ALSO HAD THE PLEASURE OF
HOSTING THE IRISH CONSULATE THE ST PATRICK'S DAY SOCIAL
GATHERING IN MY OFFICE HERE IN CITY HALL.
THAT HAS BEEN A WONDERFUL OPPORTUNITY TO CELEBRATE IRISH
HERITAGE, FRIENDSHIP AND COMMUNITY ALONGSIDE CONSUL
GENERAL SMITH AND MEMBERS OF SAN FRANCISCO'S IRISH COMMUNITY
. BEYOND THAT ALL OF US IN SAN
FRANCISCO'S LGBTQ PLUS COMMUNITY ARE ALSO GRATEFUL TO
CONSUL GENERAL SMITH FOR HIS LEADERSHIP TO HONOR ROGER
CASEMENT, WHOSE BRONZE PLAQUE WAS ADDED LAST YEAR TO THE
CASTRO'S RAINBOW HONOR WALK. ROGER CASEMENT WAS AN IRISH
PATRIOT AND DIPLOMAT WHO EXPOSED HUMAN RIGHTS ABUSES
IN AFRICA AND SOUTH AMERICA AND FOUGHT FOR IRELAND'S
INDEPENDENCE. CASEMENT'S IDENTITY AS A GAY
MAN WAS CRUELLY WEAPONISED AGAINST THOSE WHO PUSHED FOR
HIS CLEMENCY AND HE WAS EXECUTED FOR TREASON IN 1916.
THANKS TO MANY SUPPORTERS INCLUDING THE CONSUL GENERALS
OFFICE, THIS INTERSECTION OF IRISH AND LGBTQ PLUS HISTORY
WILL FOREVER ENDURE AT CASTRO'S 18TH AND CASTRO STREET BEYOND
ME HALL'S IMPRESSIVE PROFESSIONAL AND DIPLOMATIC
ACCOMPLISHMENTS HE IS ALSO SOMEONE DEEPLY GROUNDED
IN FAMILY AND COMMUNITY. TOGETHER WITH HIS WIFE CLARE
AND THEIR FOUR CHILDREN, HE HAS BROUGHT WARMTH, ENERGY AND A
STRONG SENSE OF IRISH CULTURE AND TRADITION TO OUR CITY.
ON BEHALF OF THE CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN FRANCISCO
CONSUL GENERAL SMITH, I WANT TO THANK YOU FOR YOUR LEADERSHIP,
YOUR FRIENDSHIP AND YOUR SERVICE AND FOR STRENGTHENING
THE ENDURING BOND BETWEEN IRELAND AND SAN FRANCISCO.
AND BEFORE INVITING YOU TO SAY A FEW WORDS I BELIEVE I HAVE
SEVERAL OR A COUPLE OF COLLEAGUES WHO WANT TO EXPRESS
THEIR APPRECIATION AND GRATITUDE FOR YOUR
FRIENDSHIP AND SERVICE TO OUR CITY.
>> SO THANK YOU CONSUL GENERAL SMITH AND SUPERVISE YOUR
MELGAR. >> SO I AT MY BIRTHDAY'S ON
MARCH 17TH AS THE CONSUL KNOWS THAT MAKES ME ELIGIBLE FOR
IRISH CITIZENSHIP. I HAVE TO SAY I HAVE SO ENJOYED
GETTING TO KNOW YOU HANGING OUT WITH YOUR FAMILY.
YOU ARE ALSO WONDERFUL. YOU HAVE BEEN A STELLAR
REPRESENTATIVE OF YOUR GOVERNMENT HERE IN OUR FAIR
CITY WITH THE IRISH COMMUNITY ESPECIALLY ON THE WEST SIDE.
BUT YOU ALSO HAVE BEEN SO THOUGHTFUL AND KIND
AND INCLUSIVE AND COLLABORATIVE AND I AM GOING TO MISS YOU
DEARLY. I KNOW YOU'RE GOING ON TO
BIGGER AND BETTER THINGS ON THE WORLD STAGE BUT WE HAVE BEEN
SO, SO LUCKY THAT YOU HAVE BEEN THE ONE TO REPRESENT YOUR
COUNTRY HERE WITH US AND ALSO THAT YOU SHARED YOUR WONDERFUL
FAMILY WITH US AND YOUR KIDS WENT TO SCHOOL HERE AND I KNOW
THAT THEY WILL ALWAYS HAVE THAT IN THEIR HEARTS AS THEY GO ON
WITH THEIR LIVES. THANK YOU FOR HAVING SHARED
YOURSELF AND YOUR FAMILY WITH SAN FRANCISCO.
WE HAVE SO ENJOYED HAVING YOU SUPERVISE ALONG.
GOOD AFTERNOON EVERYONE. >> FIRST I WANT TO THANK
SUPERVISOR DORSEY FOR LEADING THIS RECOGNITION AND BRING US
TOGETHER TO HONOR CONSUL GENERAL SMITH AND HIS FAMILY
BEFORE THEIR DEPARTURE FROM SAN FRANCISCO.
CONSUL GENERAL, THANK YOU FOR YOUR SERVICE AND FOR YOUR
PARTNERSHIP YOU'VE BUILT HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO.
THE TIES BETWEEN OUR CITY AND IRELAND ARE DEEPLY
MEANINGFUL SHAPED NOT ONLY BY HISTORY BUT BY THE IRISH
COMMUNITY THAT CONTINUES TO PLAY SUCH AN IMPORTANT ROLE
IN THE LIFE OF THIS CITY. AS A SUPERVISOR REPRESENTING
THE SUNSET AND AS SOMEONE WORKING TO ESTABLISH CERN
CISCO'S IRISH CULTURAL DISTRICT, I ESPECIALLY WANT TO
THANK YOU FOR YOUR ENGAGEMENT OF THE IRISH COMMUNITY HERE
IN SAN FRANCISCO AND FOR HELPING BUILD THE CONNECTIONS
THAT WILL CONTINUE WELL BEYOND THIS MOMENT AND TO YOUR FAMILY.
THANK YOU AS WELL. PUBLIC SERVICE IS NEVER DONE
ALONE AND WE KNOW THESE CHAPTERS ARE SHARED BY THE
LOVED ONES WHO SUPPORT US EVERY STEP OF THE WAY.
I'M GENUINELY EXCITED FOR THE WORK THAT WILL CONTINUE AHEAD
AND LOOK FORWARD TO CONTINUING TO COLLABORATE CLOSELY WITH THE
IRISH COMMUNITY AS WE MOVE FORWARD WITH SUPPORTING THE
CULTURAL DISTRICT AND DEEPENING THOSE TIES EVEN FURTHER.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR LEADERSHIP AND YOUR SERVICE TO OUR CITY.
>> WE WISH YOU AND YOUR FAMILY NOTHING BUT THE VERY BEST
IN YOUR NEXT CHAPTER. THANK.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH. MR. CONSUL GENERAL, MY
COLLEAGUES HAVE SAID ANYTHING THAT I WOULD THINK ABOUT SAYING
ALREADY AND SAID IT BETTER BUT I JUST WANT TO SAY FOR MYSELF
THAT IT HAS BEEN A TRUE HONOR AND PRIVILEGE TO BE ABLE TO GET
TO KNOW YOU AND WORK WITH YOU ON SOME THINGS AND YOU'VE BEEN
GREAT. SAN FRANCISCO LOVES YOU.
WE'RE GOING TO MISS YOU A LOT AND THANK YOU SUPERVISOR DORSEY
FOR FOR BRINGING THE CONSUL GENERAL IN HERE TO GET A LITTLE
RECOGNITION. THANK YOU.
NOW THE FLOOR IS YOURS. GAMO GETS ITS THANK YOU
IN IRISH TO SEE THE THE IRISH FLAGS AROUND TODAY.
IT WAS MY HEART PROUD TO RECEIVE THIS.
THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR DORSEY THANK YOU
PRESIDENT MANDELA AND THANK YOU ALL THE MEMBERS OF THE BOARD
AND THANK YOU FOR THE KIND WORDS TO RECEIVE THIS TODAY
AND IN THE CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN FRANCISCO, A CITY THAT HAS
MEANT SO MUCH AND MEAN SO MUCH TO MY FAMILY AND I IS DEEPLY
HUMBLING PLEASURE MY DAUGHTER SOPHIE SAN AND KOENEN AND I
HAVE THOROUGHLY ENJOYED THIS PLACE WE'VE BUILT LIFELONG
FRIENDSHIPS. >> THIS WILL ALWAYS BE IN OUR
HEARTS A CITY WITH ENORMOUS BEAUTY DIVERSITY.
IT HAS A CREATIVITY. IT HAS A RESILIENCE, IT HAS A
COMPASSION AND IT'S CONSTANTLY CHANGING.
I'VE SEEN HOW IT'S CHANGED OVER THE LAST FOUR YEARS BUT CHANGE
AND REINVENTING ITSELF BUT ALSO STILL LOOKING AFTER ITS
COMMUNITY AND ITS PEOPLE. AND WE HAVE AS YOU'VE MENTIONED
SEVERAL TIMES A PROUD IRISH COMMUNITY HERE WITH AN
IMPACTFUL HISTORY. BUT WHAT MAKES SAN FRANCISCO SO
SPECIAL AND WHAT MAKES OUR COMMUNITY SO SPECIAL IS THAT
THE IRISH STORY HAS BEEN WOVEN INTO THE RICHNESS OF EVERY
OTHER COMMUNITY HERE AND THE AND THAT'S WHAT MAKES THIS CITY
REMARKABLE. WE'RE PROUD I'M PROUD THE
COMMUNITY IS PROUD TO BE PART OF THAT INTERCONNECTEDNESS.
AND YOU SEE THAT INCREDIBLE INTERCONNECTEDNESS WITH THE
WORK OF THE UNITED IRISH CULTURAL CENTER AND ITS VISION
FOR THE SUNSET THE SUPPORT THAT THE IRISH IMMIGRATION
AND PASTORAL CENTER PROVIDES THE WORK OF THE UNITED IRISH
SOCIETIES AND THIS AND PATRICK'S DAY A PERIOD THAT
COMES FROM THAT THE VIBRANT SAN FRANCISCO CORK SISTER CITY
RELATIONSHIP ON TREASURE ISLAND WE HAVE THE HOME OF THE GAELIC
ATHLETIC ASSOCIATION GAELIC GAMES.
I THINK IT'S THE BEST STADIUM, OUR BEST LAND AND THE VISTA INN
IN THE UNITED STATES WITH THE GLENS SOCCER TEAM THERE WITH A
DIVERSITY OF COMMUNITIES 90 DIFFERENT COMMUNITIES PLAYING
FOOTBALL SOCCER SORRY. ACROSS ACROSS THE CITY SAN
FRANCISCO HAS BEEN SHAPED PROFOUNDLY BY THE IRISH.
IF YOU TURN ON YOUR WATER TAP IN THE KITCHEN TODAY, IT'S
BECAUSE OF A LIMERICK MAN MICHAEL O'SHAUGHNESSY WHO
ENGINEERED AND DESIGN US IF YOU I THINK SO IF YOU IF YOU LOOK
AT WOMEN'S RIGHTS WOMEN'S PIER KIT KENNEDY BACK IN THE MEDIA
1800S FOUGHT FOR THAT AT A TIME WHEN VERY FEW PEOPLE DID
AND WAS SUCCESSFUL. WE LOOK AT THE MEN AND WOMEN
IN UNIFORM THAT WE HAVE RIGHT ACROSS THE CITY SERVING AND THE
IRISH CONNECTIONS ARE THERE THAT ARE THERE DOES MY HEART
PRIDE AND DOES THAT IS PROUD OF WHY THE IRISH GOVERNMENT
AND TODAY WE BUILD ON THOSE CONNECTIONS WE SEE THAT THE A
MEMORIAL IS HAS BEEN AGREED AND HAS BEEN PLANNED FOR FOR
LINCOLN PARK SUPERVISOR DORSEY YOU TALKED ABOUT THE ROGER
CASEMENT PLAQUE WHICH WAS A HUGE HONOR AND A HUGE VERY
PROUD TO BE THERE THAT DAY WHEN IT WAS UNVEILED IN THE RAINBOW
HONOR WALK AND WE HAVE THE THE RAINBOW THE ORIGINAL RAINBOW
FLAG MAKING ITS WAY TO CORK OVER THE SUMMER FOR THE FIRST
TIME EVER WE HAVE THE LAUREL TIE COMMEMORATION BY THE IRISH
TO THE CHINESE RAILWAY WORKERS TO HONOR THEM AND THEIR
CONSTRUCTION OF THE TRANSCONTINENTAL RAILWAY
AND MANY OTHERS MANY IN CULTURE AND ECONOMIC AND TECHNOLOGY
THESE INITIATIVES WILL CONTINUE SO SUPERVISORS THIS CITY SAN
SAN FRANCISCO IS THE GREATEST CITY IN THE WORLD AND IT IS
OUTSIDE IRELAND AND IT TRULY IS.
>> IT WILL IT WILL ALWAYS HAVE A PLACE IN OUR HEARTS AND I
WANT TO THANK YOU. I WANT TO THANK THE MAYOR AND I
WANT TO THANK THE PEOPLE OF THIS CITY FOR MAKING THIS SUCH
AN IMPACTFUL PART OF MY LIFE. >> GO TO MEET HIM, OLGA, THANK
YOU SO MUCH. SUPERVISOR DARCY SO WE SO BRING
THE CONSUL GENERAL INTO THE WELL YEAH.
MM HMM. OH YEAH.
VERY WELL TO THANK YOU FOR YOUR OKAY ROUND TWO NEXT COLLEAGUES
,I BEG YOUR INDULGENCE FOR A RARE INSTANCE OF AMENDATORY
DOUBLE DIPPING BUT AS YOU'LL SOON HEAR, IT'S FOR A TRULY
EXTRAORDINARY COMMUNITY MEMBER .
>> SISTER MARGUERITE BARTLEY, MY SISTER AND YOU WOULD
APPROACH THE LECTERN SISTER BART LING'S COMPASSION, FAITH
AND LEADERSHIP HAVE TRANSFORMED COUNTLESS LIVES IN SAN
FRANCISCO THROUGH HER WORK AT GOOD SHEPHERD GRACE CENTER FOR
THE PAST 17 YEARS, SISTER MARGUERITE HAS DEDICATED
HERSELF TO HELPING WOMEN WITHOUT RESOURCES OVERCOME
ALCOHOL AND DRUG ADDICTION AND BUILD HOPEFUL HEALTHY
FUTURES. UNDER HER LEADERSHIP, GRACE
CENTER HAS PROVIDED NOT ONLY RECOVERY SERVICES BUT ALSO
DIGNITY, STABILITY, COMPASSION AND A TRUE SENSE OF COMMUNITY
FOR WOMEN WORKING TO REBUILD THEIR LIVES.
AS MANY OF YOU KNOW, RECOVERY IS AN ISSUE THAT IS DEEPLY
PERSONAL TO ME. I KNOW FIRSTHAND HOW
TRANSFORMATIVE RECOVERY FROM ADDICTION AND ALCOHOLISM CAN BE
AND I ALSO KNOW THAT NO ONE SUCCEEDS ALONE.
RECOVERY DEPENDS ON PEOPLE WHO ARE WILLING TO SHOW COMPASSION,
PROVIDE SUPPORT AND BELIEVE IN SOMEONE EVEN WHEN THEY MAY
STRUGGLE TO BELIEVE IN THEMSELVES THAT IS EXACTLY
THE KIND OF LEADERSHIP SISTER MARGUERITE HAS PROVIDED FOR
NEARLY TWO DECADES AT GRACE CENTER.
THROUGH HER FAITH, KINDNESS AND TIRELESS COMMITMENT SHE HAS
HELPED COUNTLESS WOMEN OVERCOME ADDICTION AND MOVE TOWARD
HEALTHIER, STABLE, MORE STABLE FUTURES.
SHE HAS ALSO STRENGTHENED GRACE CENTER ITSELF BY EXPANDING
RESOURCES, BUILDING COMMUNITY PARTNERSHIPS AND HELPING ENSURE
THE ORGANIZATION CAN CONTINUE ITS MISSION FOR YEARS TO COME.
THE WORK OF RECOVERY IS OFTEN QUIET DIFFICULT AND DEEPLY
HUMAN BUT IT CHANGES LIVES, FAMILIES AND COMMUNITIES EVERY
SINGLE DAY. SISTER MARGUERITE HAS TRULY LED
WITH WHAT HER COLLEAGUES DESCRIBE AS THE HEART OF A
SHEPHERD AND SAN FRANCISCO IS STRONGER BECAUSE OF YOUR
SERVICE SISTER. AS SHE PREPARES HER NEXT
ASSIGNMENT FOR THE SISTERS OF GOOD SHEPHERD, I WANT TO THANK
HER ON BEHALF OF A GRATEFUL CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN
FRANCISCO FOR HER EXTRAORDINARY LEADERSHIP, COMPASSION AND LAST
LASTING IMPACT. SISTER MARGUERITE,
CONGRATULATIONS ON THIS WELL-DESERVED COMMENDATION
AND THANK YOU FOR EVERYTHING YOU HAVE DONE FOR OUR CITY
AND FOR THE WOMEN YOU HAVE HELPED ALONG THE WAY AND TO
AND FOR TO AFFIRM THE ENDURING PROMISE OF RECOVERY.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH. >> I LIKE TO SAY THANK YOU VERY
MUCH FOR THIS COMBINATION FOR THE SUPERVISORS AND I ACCEPTED
ON BEHALF OF THE GOOD SHEPHERD SISTERS WHO HAVE SERVED HERE
IN SAN FRANCISCO FOR 94 YEARS HELPING YOUNG WOMEN IN TROUBLE.
>> YES, BUT WE DON'T DO IT ALONE.
>> WE HAVE OUR GOOD SHEPHERD GUILD.
WE HAVE OUR BOARD. WE HAVE OUR STAFF, OUR
VOLUNTEERS AND ESPECIALLY THE BRAVE WOMEN WHO TAKE THOSE
STEPS FOR RECOVERY AND FOR HELPING THEIR FAMILIES
AND STRENGTHENING THEIR COMMUNITIES.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH FOR EVERYTHING YOU HAVE
. >> NEXT UP DISTRICT FIVE
SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD. >> COLLEAGUES, TODAY IS MY
HONOR IN CELEBRATION OF AAPI HERITAGE MONTH TO RECOGNIZE
STEPHEN THE NICOSIA STEVE, CAN YOU COME UPSTAIRS?
>> >> STEVE IS A DEDICATED COMMUNITY LEADER NONPROFIT
EXECUTIVE AND PUBLIC SERVANT WHOSE DECADES OF WORK HAVE
HELPED STRENGTHEN SAN FRANCISCO'S JAPANESE-AMERICAN
COMMUNITY. >> STEVE HAS SPENT MORE THAN 50
YEARS SERVING THIS CITY THROUGH LEADERSHIP ROOTED IN CARE AND A
DEEP COMMITMENT TO COMMUNITY WELL-BEING.
STEVE I FIRST REMEMBER WHEN I FIRST MET YOU YEARS BEFORE I
EVEN RAN FOR OFFICE AND YOU WERE QUITE STERN AND MADE SURE
THAT I KNEW WHO YOU WERE WHO WAS BOSS.
AND STEVE, AS PEOPLE KNOW, IS WHOLEHEARTEDLY THE GODFATHER OF
JAPANTOWN. AND THERE'S A REASON FOR THAT.
>> HIS WORK HAS SPANNED DECADES IN THE COMMUNITY.
SINCE 1971 HE SERVED AS CO-FOUNDER AND EXECUTIVE
DIRECTOR OF KIMCHI CREATING A TIME WHEN THERE WAS VERY FEW
CULTURALLY RESPONSIVE SERVICES FOR JAPANESE-AMERICAN SENIORS
IN SAN FRANCISCO. AND WHAT STARTED AS A
GRASSROOTS EFFORT GREW UNDER HIS LEADERSHIP INTO A
NATIONALLY RECOGNIZED SENIOR SERVICES ORGANIZATION.
OVER MORE THAN FOUR DECADES, STEVE HAS HELPED BUILD KIMCHI
INTO A TRUSTED INSTITUTION PROVIDING HOUSING SUPPORT,
NUTRITION PROGRAMS, TRANSPORTATION AND SOCIAL
SERVICES FOR SENIORS ACROSS THE CITY.
HIS WORK HAS ENSURED THAT GENERATIONS OF SENIORS COULD
AGE WITH DIGNITY AND CULTURALLY GROUNDED CARE AND IN A
NEIGHBORHOOD WHICH OVER 20% OF THE NEIGHBORHOOD IS OVER THE
AGE OF 80. A SERVICE LIKE KIMCHI IS A
PUBLIC TREASURE. >> STEVE ALSO CO-FOUNDED THE
NEON MUNCHIE STREET FAIR DURING THE ASIAN-AMERICAN MOVEMENT
AND HELPING CREATE A SPACE WHERE JAPANESE-AMERICAN
AND BROADER ASIAN-AMERICAN COMMUNITIES COULD GATHER
THROUGH ART, MUSIC AND PERFORMANCE.
>> THAT TRADITION CONTINUES TODAY AS ONE OF SAN FRANCISCO'S
MOST ENDURING CULTURAL CELEBRATIONS AS WELL AS ONE OF
MY FAVORITE PERSONAL FAVORITE EVENTS IN THE CITY NOT LEAST OF
WHICH IS BECAUSE SHE CHIEF CHRISTINE AND I COOK BURGERS
ALMOST EVERY YEAR. ALONGSIDE STEVE AT THE FAIR,
STEVE HAS SERVED SAN FRANCISCO IN PUBLIC SAFETY GOVERNANCE AS
WELL. FOR NEARLY THREE DECADES HE HAS
SERVED ON THE SAN FRANCISCO FIRE COMMISSION.
AND WHILE I ACKNOWLEDGE ALL OF THOSE ARE HERE FROM OUR FIRE
DEPARTMENT AS WELL IN RECOGNITION STEVE WAS FIRST
APPOINTED IN 1996 AND HE HAS SERVED CONTINUOUSLY THROUGH
MULTIPLE MAYORAL ADMINISTRATIONS INCLUDING
REAPPOINTMENT BY MAYOR GAVIN NEWSOM, MAYOR ED LEE AND MAYOR
LONDON BREED. HE'S NOT RETIRING.
>> IF ANYONE WAS WORRIED BUT HE HAS HELD THAT LEADERSHIP ROLES
AS BOTH PRESIDENT AND VICE PRESIDENT OF THE COMMISSION
ACROSS MULTIPLE TERMS INCLUDING SERVICE.
AS RECENTLY AS THE PRESENT REFLECTING A LONGSTANDING ROLE
IN OVERSEEING THE CITY'S KEY PUBLIC SAFETY INSTITUTIONS,
STEVE'S CIVIC ENGAGEMENT CONTINUES TODAY.
>> THROUGH ACTIVE ROLES FOCUSED ON JAPANTOWN, HE'S CURRENTLY A
MEMBER OF THE RE-IMAGINED JAPANTOWN COMMUNITY, A MEMBER
OF THE JAPANTOWN COMMUNITY BENEFIT DISTRICT, THE STEERING
COMMITTEE AND SERVES AS PRODUCER OF THE JAY TOWN
CONSULATE CONTINUES TO SUPPORT CULTURAL PROGRAMING
AND COMMUNITY EVENTS AS GRACE HERRICK, EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR OF
THE JAPANTOWN COMMUNITY BENEFITS DISTRICT SHARED.
>> STEVE IS NOT ONLY A COMMUNITY LEADER BUT A BIG
BROTHER TO MANY OF US WHO GREW UP IN GEORGETOWN.
HE HAS CONTINUALLY HELPED US GEORGETOWN KIDS BECOME LEADERS
OF OUR COMMUNITY AND HIS EARLIER LEADERSHIP AS EXECUTIVE
DIRECTOR OF THE JAPANTOWN TASK FORCE AND JAPANTOWN CULTURAL
DISTRICT FROM 2017 TO 2021. STEVE HELPED GUIDE MAJOR
COMMUNITY INITIATIVES, STRENGTHEN ORGANIZATIONAL
STRUCTURE AND SUPPORT LONG TIME CULTURAL AND ECONOMIC PLANNING
FOR THE NEIGHBORHOOD. DURING THAT TIME HE ALSO HELPED
PRODUCE AND SUPPORT A RANGE OF JAPANTOWN CULTURAL PROGRAMING
INCLUDING PEACE PLAZA EVENTS AND FESTIVALS.
MORE RECENTLY HE HAS CONTINUED PRODUCING AND SUPPORTING
JAPANTOWN CULTURAL EVENTS INCLUDING THE NEON MONKEY
MERCHANTS ASSOCIATION PROGRAMING THE JAY TOWN JAZZ
AND TAIKO FESTIVAL PEACE PLAZA PROGRAMING AND JETSON TAIKO
AND JAZZ EVENTS. ACROSS ALL THESE EFFORTS HIS
FOCUS HAS REMAINED ON SUSTAINING COMMUNITY SPACE
AND INTERGENERATIONAL CONNECTION AND CELEBRATION.
HIS CONTRIBUTIONS HAVE BEEN RECOGNIZED WILDLY WIDELY
INCLUDING THE KGO PROFILE AND EXCELLENCE THE KQED
ASIAN-AMERICAN HERITAGE AWARD, THE SPUR AWARD, THE FOREIGN
MINISTER'S COMMENDATION FROM JAPAN IN 2016 AND THE ORDER OF
THE RISING SUN, GOLD AND SILVER RAYS.
>> STEVE, THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR YOUR DECADES OF SERVICE TO SAN
FRANCISCO. WE THINK YOU HAVE A COUPLE OF
MORE DECADES LEFT THAT WE'LL GET OUT OF YOU AS WELL AND YOUR
CONTINUED LEADERSHIP IN JAPANTOWN AND YOUR LIFELONG
COMMITMENT TO STRENGTHEN COMMUNITIES FOR FUTURE
GENERATIONS. AND BEFORE YOU SPEAK, WE'D LIKE
TO HAVE SOME OF THE MEMBERS OF THE FIRE DEPARTMENT SPEAK AS
WELL. >> MR. PRESIDENT, MEMBERS OF
THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS DEAN CHRISMAN FIRE CHIEF.
I WOULD JUST LIKE TO PAINT A PICTURE FOR YOU THAT I THINK IS
ONE OF THE MORE BEAUTIFUL SCENES THAT I'VE SEEN IN SAN
FRANCISCO AND SUPERVISOR MAHMUD ALLUDED TO.
IT COMES AT THE END OF THE CHERRY BLOSSOM PARADE AND IT'S
AT THE BOOTH WHERE THE ASIAN FIREFIGHTER ASSOCIATION
CONDUCTS A SALE AT TERIYAKI BURGERS.
AND IT REALLY IS THE BEAUTY OF IT IS THE BREADTH OF AGES THAT
PARTICIPATES IN THIS EVENT. YOU HAVE CHILDREN, YOU HAVE
ASPIRING FIREFIGHTERS, YOU HAVE FIREFIGHTERS, YOU HAVE EMT, YOU
HAVE PARAMEDICS, YOU HAVE RETIRED FIREFIGHTERS.
YOU HAVE RETIRED FIREFIGHTERS FRIENDS.
YOU HAVE THIS AMAZING GROUP OF PEOPLE ALL WORKING TO SERVE THE
COMMUNITY. AND REALLY I ATTRIBUTE THIS TO
COMMISSIONER STEVEN CHICAGO. AND WHEN YOU WATCH HIM WITNESS
AND PARTICIPATE, YOU CAN SEE THE PRIDE AND THE HAPPINESS
IN HIS EYES TO SEE THIS WHOLE GROUP OF PEOPLE COMMITTED TO
COMMUNITY SERVICE. NOW NONE OF US WILL EVER MEET
THE COMMITMENT THAT COMMISSIONER NICASTRO HAS AS
FULLY INVESTED IN SAN FRANCISCO .
BUT THIS GROUP EFFORT IS REALLY LED BY HIM AND HIS STABILITY
STEPS ABILITY STABILIZING FORCE ON THE COMMISSION HAS BEEN AN
AMAZING HELP TO US AS A NEW COMMAND STAFF STARTING LAST
YEAR. AND HIS WISDOM AND INTELLIGENCE
ON THE COMMISSION HAS BEEN INCREDIBLY HELPFUL TO US.
SO REALLY THANK YOU SUPERVISOR MAHMUD FOR HONORING HIM
AND THANK YOU TO THE REMAINDER OF THE BOARD FOR PARTICIPATING
AND SUPPORTING HIM. HE'S A REAL GIFT TO SAN
FRANCISCO. WE ARE SO LUCKY TO HAVE HIM A
LIFETIME OF COMMUNITY SERVICE. WE ARE VERY LUCKY TO HAVE YOU.
>> THANK YOU. THANK YOU.
SUPERVISORS. >> THANK YOU FOR LETTING ME
SPEAK. MY NAME IS SAMMY BRANNON.
I'M DEPUTY CHIEF OF ADMINISTRATION FOR THE SAN
FRANCISCO FIRE DEPARTMENT. AND I JUST WANTED TO SAY A
HEARTFELT THANK YOU TO COMMISSIONER KODJOE.
NOT ONLY HAS HE BEEN AN INSPIRING LEADER IN JUST NOT
JUST JAPANTOWN BUT THE ENTIRE CITY.
BUT HE ACTUALLY HAS BEEN A MENTOR AND AN ASPIRATION FOR ME
WHEN I FIRST AND WAS STILL NEW IN THE FIRE DEPARTMENT.
HE DID FIND ME RECOGNIZE THAT I WAS JAPANESE-AMERICAN
AND POINTED IT OUT THAT I NEED TO REALLY TAKE THAT INTO HEART.
>> SOMETHING THAT NOT VERY MANY PEOPLE SAID TO ME GROWING UP.
AND FOR SOMEONE TO RECOGNIZE MY CULTURE AND MY HERITAGE.
AND HE WAS SHOCKED TO FIND THAT I DID SPEAK JAPANESE THAT THAT
RESONATED WITH ME AND I THINK I AND I HAVE HIM TO THANK FOR
WHERE I AM TODAY. SO COMMISSIONER NAKATA DOMO
ADEQUATE THOUGH BECAUSE I'M A AND COMMISSIONER NAKATA BEFORE
YOU SPEAK. >> SUPERVISOR SHERYL HAS SOME
REMARKS. COMMISSIONER CHICAGO THE FIRST
TIME WELL THE SECOND TIME WE MET BUT THE FIRST TIME WE
REALLY MET WAS AT JAPANTOWN. IT WAS MY FIRST SIGNIFICANT
VISIT TO JAPAN TOWN. AND YOU LAID AN X OUT AN
EXPANSIVE VIEW OF THE HISTORY OF THE COMMUNITY AND YOUR
ABILITY TO PROVIDE THE WISDOM OF THE HISTORY OF SAN
FRANCISCO. SO MANY PARTS OF THAT COMBINED
WITH YOUR INCISIVE INSIGHT INTO WHAT OUR CITY NEEDS TODAY IS
INCREDIBLY UNIQUE. AND YOUR SERVICE TO JAPANTOWN
COMBINED WITH YOUR SERVICE TO THE ENTIRE CITY OF SAN
FRANCISCO IS UNIQUE. >> SO I WANT TO THANK YOU FOR
COMBINING THE MICRO AND THE MACRO LIKE SO FEW WERE ABLE TO
DO AND FOR YOUR CONTINUED LEADERSHIP.
>> THANK YOU. >> I I WILL ADD MY OWN
CONGRATULATIONS AND THANKS COMMISSIONER NAKAJIMA.
I THINK SOON AFTER I JOINED THIS BOARD OF SUPERVISORS YOU
HELPED TO REINTRODUCE ME TO JAPANTOWN.
AND YOU HAVE BEEN A HAPPY PRESENCE TO SEE IN ALL OF OUR
CIVIC EVENTS AND YOUR STEWARDSHIP OF OUR FIRE
DEPARTMENT IS SOMETHING FOR WHICH WE ARE ALL INCREDIBLY
GRATEFUL. SO THANK YOU COMMISSIONER
NAKAJIMA AND THANK YOU SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD FOR FOR
HONORING OUR COMMISSIONER. >> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
AS A JAPANESE-AMERICAN IN TERMS OF ALL OF THE CULTURAL
TREASURES WE INHERITED FROM OUR GRANDPARENTS AND OUR COMMUNITY.
BEING HUMBLE IS PART OF THAT ATTRIBUTE AND SERVICES.
THE OTHER PART OF THAT ATTRIBUTE.
SUPERVISOR MUMMERY, THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR THIS RECOGNITION
PARTICULARLY BECAUSE YOU ARE DISTRICT FIVE SUPERVISOR BUT
ALSO WITH THE DIVERSITY OF DISTRICT FIVE.
JAPANTOWN IS PART OF THAT AS WELL.
SO WE THANK YOU FOR THAT. BUT WE ALSO THANK YOU FOR THE
ADVOCACY AND THE WORK. >> I HAVE TO BE MARK HOW
IMPORTANT THIS EVENT IS NOT JUST FOR MYSELF AS AN
ASIAN-AMERICAN PACIFIC ISLANDER BUT THE FACT THAT WE'RE IN SAN
FRANCISCO. WHEN I CHINATOWN FISCAL STATE
AND ASIAN-AMERICAN STUDIES I USED TO THINK ABOUT SAN
FRANCISCO BEING THE ASIAN AMERICAN CAPITAL OF THE UNITED
STATES. AND I KNOW MY FRIENDS IN NEW
YORK AND LOS ANGELES MAYBE WEREN'T PARTICULARLY KEEN ON
THAT. BUT IF YOU DO THE RESEARCH
YOU'RE FORGET IF YOU FIND OUT THAT HISTORICAL BASIS ALL CAME
FROM HERE. PART OF THAT IS JAPANTOWN.
I HAVE TO TELL YOU THAT ONCE UPON A TIME BACK WHEN ASIAN
AMERICAN HERITAGE JUST WAS A COIN PHRASE AND WHEN IT WAS
FIRST IMPLEMENTED HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO I VAGUELY REMEMBER
BEING UNDER THAT DOME WITH ABOUT SIX OF US AND IT WAS A
PROCLAMATION OF ASIAN AMERICAN HERITAGE MONTH.
AND THEN GOVERNOR MAYOR NEWSOM WAS PRESIDING AND I WAS HANGING
OUT WITH A COUPLE OF MY COLLEAGUES THE LATE SILVER
PLAGUE UP THERE WAS ALSO TED FANG AND MANY OF US.
AND AS THIS PROCLAMATION OCCURRED I LOOKED AT SULU
AND TED FANG AND I BASICALLY SAID WE GOT TO DO BETTER THAN
THIS. AND PART OF THAT WAS THAT WE
COME FROM SAN FRANCISCO WHICH AGAIN HAS SUCH RICH HISTORY ALL
OF THESE ACCOLADES AND DISCUSSIONS IN TERMS OF SAN
CISCO POINTS TO WHAT WE HAVE BEST OUR CULTURE FOR OUR
COMMUNITY AND ALL OF OUR PIONEERS WHO MADE SAN FRANCISCO
WHAT IT IS TODAY. >> BUT THAT'S SOMETHING THAT WE
SHOULD NEVER LOSE SIGHT OF. AND WITH THE CHANGING DYNAMICS
OF SAN FRANCISCO WITH THEIR BUILDINGS, WITH ALL OF THE
DISCUSSION DON'T DEVALUE THE BIGGEST COMMODITY, THE BIGGEST
TREASURE THAT WE HAVE WHICH IS OUR MEMBERS, OUR COMMUNITY
AND THIS ASIAN AMERICAN HERITAGE AWARD IS JUST NOT FOR
MYSELF. IT'S FOR EVERYBODY ELSE IN THE
ROOM ALL OF THEM IN THE PAST AND IN THE FUTURE AND THAT'S
WHAT'S REALLY IMPORTANT. TALKING ABOUT THE FUTURE IF YOU
TALK ABOUT JAPANTOWN SUPERVISORS, YOU KNOW WE ALWAYS
LAMENT AND TALK ABOUT THE HISTORY OF JAPANTOWN
AND BELIEVE IT OR NOT SAN FRANCISCANS USED TO BE 44
BLOCKS BEFORE THE WAR DURING 46, 1946, 1947.
WE KNOW WHERE WE WERE. WE JAPANESE-AMERICAN HONOR
20,000 JAPANESE-AMERICANS IN TEN DIFFERENT CONCENTRATION
CAMPS. CALL IT WHAT YOU WANT NO DUE
PROCESS AND NO REIMBURSEMENT, NO REPARATION.
BUT WE OUR COMMUNITY, OUR PIONEERS ADAPTED TO THAT.
>> HOW DO YOU THINK FOLKS FELT IN CAMP TRYING TO FIGURE OUT A
FUTURE FOR SAN FRANCISCO AND THE JAPANESE-AMERICAN
COMMUNITY AND THEN TO COME BACK AND REBUILD OUR ISSEI
GENERATION AND OUR NISEI GENERATION AND THEN TO HAVE THE
CITY AND COUNTY AND THIS CHAMBER EMBLEM MADE AND EXECUTE
EMINENT DOMAIN EMINENT DOMAIN FOR US IN THE FILLMORE
JAPANTOWN AREA MEANS THE TOTAL DESTRUCTION OF EVERYTHING THAT
WE GREW UP WITH. AND PART OF THAT IS TO TRY TO
MAINTAIN THAT. AND TODAY'S STANDARDS THAT'S
REALLY, REALLY IMPORTANT. WE TALK ABOUT FOUR BLOCKS OF
JAPANTOWN BUT WE KNOW IT GOES BEYOND THAT.
IT TAKES A VILLAGE TO DO THE WORK THAT I HAVE AND BROTHERS
AND SISTERS AND SUPERVISORS RESPECTFULLY.
THE VILLAGE IS HERE IN THIS CHAMBER REPRESENTING OUR
COMMUNITY AND IT'S SOMETHING THAT WE SHOULD NEVER FORGET AS
WELL. >> THOSE SINS OF OUR
FOREFATHERS STILL AFFECT US TODAY.
WE'RE TRYING TO STILL MAINTAIN THAT COMMUNITY THAT HAS
RESONANCE THAT HAVE CHANGED WITH THE DYNAMICS.
WE'RE DEALING WITH ISSUES LIKE CERTIFICATE OF PRECEDENCE WHAT
THE HECK WAS THAT? THESE ARE CERTIFICATES GIVEN TO
MEMBERS OF OUR COMMUNITY THE FILLMORE JAPANESE COMMUNITY
THAT GUARANTEES YOU A PLACE BACK IN OUR COMMUNITY.
AND AFTER 60 YEARS THAT STILL HASN'T BEEN QUITE IMPLEMENTED
BUT THE WORK IS BEING DONE NOW. >> SO TALK ABOUT THOSE EFFECTS
AND WHERE WE ARE NOW. I'M GLAD YOU TALKED ABOUT
HAVING THIS COMMUNITY BENEFIT DISTRICT.
THE VILLAGE IS PART OF ALL OF THE NONPROFITS THAT ARE HERE AS
WELL. AND PART OF THAT VILLAGE FOR
MYSELF AND THE LOVE OF SAN FRANCISCO AND JAPANTOWN IS THE
LOVE AND THE HONOR OF BEING A MEMBER OF THE SAN FRANCISCO
FIRE DEPARTMENT. THIS DEPARTMENT IN TERMS OF THE
LOVE OF OUR COMMUNITY HELP ME DEFINE FOR MYSELF THE LOVE OF
SAN FRANCISCO THAT A YOUNG MAN FROM GEORGETOWN CAN COME OUT OF
THE WEST INDIES AND FILLMORE PURCHASE A BAY WITHIN PUBLIC
SERVICES AND BEGIN TO UNDERSTAND FULLY THE BEAUTY OF
SAN FRANCISCO. MEMBERS OF THE BOARD.
SUPERVISOR MORROW THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR EVERYTHING THAT YOU
HAVE DONE. >> I APPRECIATE IT.
THANK YOU
. >>
ALL RIGHT. >> NEXT UP DISTRICT TEN
SUPERVISOR WALTON. >> THANK YOU SO MUCH,
PRESIDENT, MADAM AND COLLEAGUES TODAY IT IS MY HONOR TO RISE
THIS AMERICAN ASIAN PACIFIC ISLANDER HERITAGE MONTH TO
RECOGNIZE A YOUNG LEADER WHOSE LIFE AND WORK EMBODIES SERVICE
CULTURE AND COMMUNITY. >> AUGUST TINO TINO FELICE WAS
BORN AND RAISED IN SAN FRANCISCO.
TINO'S ROOTS IN THIS CITY RUN DEEP AND HIS COMMITMENT TO
UPLIFTING OUR COMMUNITIES HAS ALREADY LEFT A LASTING IMPACT
ON COUNTLESS LIVES. FOR NEARLY TWO DECADES TINO HAS
DEDICATED HIMSELF TO SERVING THROUGH THE SAMOAN COMMUNITY
DEVELOPMENT CENTER WHERE HE HAS BECOME A TRUSTED MENTOR,
ADVOCATE AND BRIDGE BUILDER. FROM NEWS SERVICES AND FAMILY
PROGRAMING TO SUPPORTING TRANSITIONAL AGE YOUTH, TINO
HAS CONSISTENTLY CREATED PATHWAYS FOR YOUNG PEOPLE
AND FAMILIES TO THRIVE. HIS WORK IS NOT SIMPLY ABOUT
PROGRAMS. IT IS ABOUT RELATIONSHIPS,
TRUST AND MAKING EVERY PERSON FEEL SEEN, VALUED AND EMPOWERED
. WHAT MAKES TINO ESPECIALLY
REMARKABLE IS THE PRIDE AND LOVE HE CARRIES FOR HIS
CULTURE AT A TIME WHEN SO MANY YOUNG PEOPLE ARE SEARCHING FOR
IDENTITY AND BELONGING. TINO STANDS TALL AND WHO HE IS
AND ENCOURAGES THE NEXT GENERATION TO DO THE SAME.
THROUGH HIS WORK ACROSS PACIFICA COMMUNITY EVERY
CONNECTION HE BUILDS STRENGTHENS THE FABRIC OF OUR
CITY. AS HE CONTINUES HIS STUDIES
AND SOCIAL WORK AT SAN FRANCISCO STATE UNIVERSITY
AND CARRIES FORWARD HIS SERVICE TO THE PEOPLE OF SAN FRANCISCO,
TINO REMINDS US ALL LEADERSHIP ROOTED IN HUMILITY, CULTURE
AND LOVE. WHAT IT TRULY LOOKS LIKE TODAY.
WE THANK TINO FELICE FOR HIS UNWAVERING COMMITMENT TO THE
PACIFICA COMMUNITY, TO THE YOUTH AND FAMILIES OF SAN
FRANCISCO AND TO BUILDING A FUTURE GROUNDED IN CULTURE,
DIGNITY AND COLLECTIVE CARE. CONGRATULATIONS TINO AND THANK
YOU FOR ALL THAT YOU DO FOR ME. >> SORRY.
YOU KNOW WHEN YOU CALL ONE OF US YOU CALL IT A WHOLE VILLAGE.
SO THANK YOU AGAIN AGAINST ALL OF THE LEVEL TWO PRESIDENT
SUPERVISORS DEPARTMENTS AND COMMUNITY MEMBERS GATHER
HERE TODAY. FIRST AND FOREMOST I GIVE ALL
THE HONOR AND GLORY TO GOD FOR GRANTING ME THE STRENGTH, THE
FAITH AND A PURPOSE TO CONTINUE TO SHOW UP FOR MY COMMUNITY.
I ALWAYS SAY YOU MAY BE SMARTER THAN ME.
YOU MAY BE STRONGER THAN ME OR YOU MIGHT SPEAK MORE ELOQUENTLY
TO ME BUT YOU'RE NOT GOING TO SERVE ME FOR MY COMMUNITY
AND MY GOD. >> SORRY I DIDN'T HEAR.
>> AND THIS IS THE FIRE THAT KEEPS ME GOING AND THE
MOTIVATION I CARRY WITH ME EACH AND EVERY DAY.
YOU KNOW WE WAKING UP AND AGAIN THANK YOU SUPERVISOR WALDEN
AND DTN AND ALSO YOUR OFFICE AS YOU CONTINUE TO SUPPORT YOUR
PARTNERSHIP AND JUST THE LOVE THAT YOU SHOWED TO OUR PACIFICA
COMMUNITY WITHIN SAN FRANCISCO. I WANT TO GIVE HONORED TO OUR
ANCESTORS WHO PAVED THE WAY. MY GRANDPARENTS PARENTS NATE
WHO PAVED THE WAY TO SACRIFICE AND WHO CARRIED US THROUGH THIS
MOMENT TO OUR ELDERS, THANK YOU FOR YOUR CONTINUED GUIDANCE,
WISDOM AND LOVE. I WOULD NOT BE STANDING HERE
WITHOUT YOU AND ESPECIALLY THE ONES THAT ARE WATCHING OVER US.
QUEEN AISHA AND A 1990 SIGN IN ANTIOCH.
SO EVEN TO MY AC DC FAMILY BACK THERE THANK YOU FOR ALWAYS
SHOWING UP FOR SUPPORTING ME AND FOR DOING THIS WORK
ALONGSIDE ME TO UPLIFT COMMUNITY.
I KNOW IT'S NOT EASY. I KNOW YOU KNOW WE BUT WE MAKE
YOU HAPPY AND WE MAKE IT FUN THOUGH SO AGAIN THANK YOU AC DC
FAMILY. SO AS WE ADD TEAMS EVERYBODY IS
HERE TODAY EVEN KNOW DC WAS DC WAVE DIRECTOR CHERISE AND ALL
HER TEAM AND YOU KNOW I AFA Y CD CIC AC DC UCSF WRAP AROUND
AND TAYLORMADE AND IF I MISS YOU I APOLOGIZE I COULD GIVE ME
AFTER I LEAVE HERE BUT JUST WANTED TO SAY THANK YOU GUYS
FOR JUST A CONTINUED COMMITMENT TO CONTINUE TO SHOW UP EVERY
SINGLE DAY. THIS RECOGNITION BELONGS TO ALL
OF US. ALL OF YOU.
ASSEMBLY I'M JUST SIMPLY HONORED.
ACCEPT IT ON BEHALF OF THE COMMITTEE THAT IS BEING
RECOGNIZED TODAY THAT IS NOT JUST ABOUT THIS IS NOT JUST
ABOUT ME. THIS IS ABOUT ALL OF US AND AND
THE WORK WE CONTINUE TO BUILD TOGETHER FOR THE NEXT
GENERATIONS TO COME TO OUR FUTURE AND EMERGING LEADERS
IN OUR PACIFIC COMMUNITY KEEP PUSHING FORWARD, KEEP FUNDING
YOUR PURPOSE, KEEP BUILDING IN YOUR IN EVERY SPACE YOU
ENTER. AS I AS I STAND HERE TODAY, OUR
EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR DR. PATTI TITO IS SPEAKING AT 12 AND HPI
GRADUATES AT USF TODAY. SO YOU KNOW, AGAIN THIS IS WHO
WE ARE. WE SHOW UP WHEREVER OUR
PACIFICA PEOPLE ARE AND WE WANT THEM TO KNOW THAT THERE ARE NO
LIMITS. SOMEONE AROUND LIKE ME CAN DO
THIS. YOU CAN DO THIS TOO.
LET'S CONTINUE TO ENCOURAGE THE NEXT GENERATION TO DREAM
WITHOUT BOUNDARIES AND TO ALWAYS KEEP GOD FIRST TO MY
FAMILY AS I ALWAYS HERE TO MY VILLAGE TO COMMUNITY VILLAGE AS
WELL. THANK YOU FOR BEING MY
BACKBONE. I KNOW THERE ARE MOMENTS I MISS
BUT KNOW THAT THE SPIRIT IS ALWAYS ONE BUT MY SPIRIT IS
ALWAYS WITH YOU SO MY JOY AND MY SINCERE MARLEE YOU ARE
MY PURPOSE EVERY EARLY MORNING WHO EVERY LONG NIGHT IS WHO
DRIVES ME TO GO OUT AND SERVE HAVING MY SON YOU KNOW BY MY
SIDE. DAWN PROGRAM MY WORK IS THE
GREATEST BLESSING TO ME OF MY LIFE.
THANK YOU FOR GIVING ME THE GRACE.
THANK YOU FOR GIVING ME THE TIME AND THANK YOU FOR
BELIEVING IN THIS WORK AS MUCH AS I DO.
AND I LIKE TO LEAVE YOU GUYS WITH A SAMOAN PROVERB ALL THE
ALILA BOLA EL IT'S OUR TOUR. THE PATHWAY TO LEADERSHIP IS
THROUGH SERVICE. THIS PROVERB IS SOMETHING THAT
WE LIVE BY CDC IT IS THE FOUNDATION WE STAND ON AND IS
THE HEARTBEAT BEHIND EVERYTHING WE DO.
WE ARE COMMITTED TO CONTINUE TO SERVE OUR PASIFIKA COMMUNITY
AND OUR BROADER COMMUNITY WITH THE SAME PASSION, DEDICATION
AND LOVE FOR OUR PEOPLE THAT HAS ALWAYS CARRIED US FORWARD.
THIS IS FOR OUR COMMUNITY. THIS IS FOR OUR FUTURE FOR
TITLE LOVER THANK YOU. WE'RE GOING TO WE'RE GOING TO
RACE THE AUGUST RECESS FOR A FEW MINUTES WHERE WE'RE GOING
TO RECESS FOR ABOUT FIVE MINUTES AND TRY TO DRUM UP SOME
SUPERVISORS SO WE'LL BE IN RECESS TILL 330
. >> ASAPH GOV TV SAN FRANCISCO
GOVERNMENT TELEVISION
AND ALL RIGHT WE ARE BACK IN SESSION.
IF YOU ARE STANDING FIND YOURSELF A SEAT OR LEAVE.
ALL RIGHT DISTRICT 11 SUPERVISOR CHEN THANK YOU BOARD
PRESIDENT MANDO MAN MAY I HAVE NO.
>> I'LL COME TO THE PODIUM. >> WHO HAPPY AAPI HERITAGE
MONTH. I'M SO PROUD TO HONOR KNOW HOW
AUROVILLE EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR OF THE EXCELSIOR AWARDS FOR A
DECADE EXCELSIOR AWARDS HAS BEEN A VITAL DISTRICT 11
INSTITUTIONS. IT BEGAN AS A COMMUNITY DRIVEN
EFFORT TO PROVIDE WORKFORCE DEVELOPMENT AND EQUITABLE
EMPLOYMENT PATHWAYS FOR THE NEIGHBORHOOD SUPERVISOR CHEN
CHAI NO, HOLD ON. OKAY.
OKAY AWAY SUPERVISOR CHEN FOR AAPI HERITAGE MAN I AM VERY
PROUD TO HONOR NOEL ORIEL, EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR OF EXCELSIOR
AWARDS FOR A DECADE EXCELSIOR AWARDS HAS BEEN A VITAL
DISTRICT 11 INSTITUTION. >> IT BEGAN AS A COMMUNITY
DRIVEN EFFORT TO PROVIDE WORKFORCE DEVELOPMENT
AND EQUITABLE EMPLOYMENT PATHWAYS FOR THE NEIGHBORHOODS
HISTORICALLY IMMIGRANT AND WORKING CLASS POPULATION
DURING THE PANDEMIC THE CENTER PIVOT TO A SERVE AS THE CRUCIAL
HUB DISTRIBUTING GROCERIES, HELPING RESIDENTS NAVIGATING
UNEMPLOYMENT AND BENEFITS AND CO-FOUNDING THE EXCELSIOR
STRONG COLLABORATIVE TO COORDINATE PUBLIC HEALTH
OUTREACH AND VACCINATION SITES .
>> POST-PANDEMIC EXCELSIOR WAS RETURNED TO ITS WORKFORCE
DEVELOPMENT ROOTS OFFERING INTENSIVE EMPLOYMENT COACHING,
CASE MANAGEMENT AND WORKFORCE AND WORKSHOPS IN ENGLISH,
SPANISH, CANTONESE AND MANDARIN TRUE TO ITS ORIGIN, THE CENTER
ALSO SERVED AS A VIBRANT COMMUNITY HUB AND CO-WORKING
SPACE FOR KEY PARTNERS INCLUDING THE CHINESE
PROGRESSIVE ASSOCIATION POOR THERE THE FILIPINO COMMUNITY
CENTER AND UCSF CLINICA MY TEAM BARROW KNOWHOW HAS LET
EXCELSIOR WORK WITH A COMMITMENT TO LONG TERM
COMMUNITY RESILIENCE WITH OVER A DECADE OF NONPROFIT
MANAGEMENT'S SPENDING FROM PUBLIC BENEFITS ASSESSED FOR
SECURITY AND HEALTH AND HEALTH ADVOCACY AS AN EXECUTIVE
DIRECTOR NOW HAS STIRRED THE ORGANIZATION'S BACK TO ITS CORE
WORKFORCE DEVELOPMENT MISSIONS BUILDING A NETWORK OF COMMUNITY
PARTNERSHIPS AND COALITIONS AND HAS COMMITTED TO BUILDING A
SUSTAINABLE FOUNDATION TO ENSURE EXCELSIOR WORKS REMAINS
A PERMANENT RESOURCE FOR THE COMMUNITY.
THANK YOU NOEL FOR YOUR OUTSTANDING WORK OF SERVING OUR
IMMIGRANT COMMUNITY. >> THANK YOU SUPERVISOR CHEN
AND MEMBERS OF THE BOARD. MY NAME IS NOEL HORARIO I'M THE
EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR OF EXCELSIOR WORKS AND ON BEHALF OF OUR
TEAM, OUR COMMUNITY MEMBERS AND OUR ORGANIZATIONAL PARTNERS
AT OUR BELOVED FIVE K MISSION OFFICE, I WANT TO EXTEND OUR
DEEPEST GRATITUDE TO SUPERVISOR CHEN FOR THIS COMMENDATION
AND SINCE ITS FOUNDING EXCELSIOR WORKS HAS BEEN A
SANCTUARY AND A STEPPING STONE FOR THE IMMIGRANT AND WORKING
CLASS FAMILIES OF DISTRICT 11. >> MOST OF OUR CLIENTS THEY
COME TO US THROUGH WORD OF MOUTH SEEKING THE COMFORT OF
NAVIGATING COMPLEX SYSTEMS AND THEIR OWN LANGUAGE AT
EXCELSIOR WORKS CULTURAL COMPETENCY IS THE VERY FABRIC
OF OUR SUCCESS. >> WE REDUCE ISOLATION BY BEING
THE TRUSTED FACES OUR COMMUNITY TURNS TO FIRST FOR ACCURATE
INFORMATION AT OUR OFFICE THOSE FRIENDLY FACES BELONG TO LINDA
,SERGIO AND PEDRO. >> THEY'RE THE ESSENTIAL GUIDES
AND A FORMAL PART OF SUPPORTING OUR NEIGHBORS TO BUILD THEIR
LIVES HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO. >> BUT OUR OFFICE IS MORE THAN
JUST A SERVICE CENTER. >> IT IS A CENTER FOR
GATHERING. IT'S WHERE A NEIGHBORHOOD COMES
TOGETHER FOR KNOW YOUR RIGHTS WORKSHOPS, COMMUNITY ACTION
TEAMS HEALING CLINICS, LEGAL SUPPORT AND ART BUILDS.
>> IT'S A PLACE OF JOY WHERE OUR ANNUAL LUNAR NEW YEAR
GATHERINGS BRING TOGETHER A FULL HOUSE TO CELEBRATE OUR
ASIAN COMMUNITY AND IT IS A PLACE OF FRONTLINE SOLIDARITY
MOST RECENTLY DEMONSTRATED WHEN WE OPENED OUR DOORS TO HOST THE
HUMMINGBIRD FARM AND FILIPINO COMMUNITY CENTER COMMUNITY
SCHOOLS DURING THE EDUCATOR STRIKE EARLIER THIS YEAR
RECEIVING THIS HONOR DURING API HERITAGE MONTH IS INCREDIBLY
MEANINGFUL. >> IT SERVES AS A POWERFUL
REMINDER OF OUR DEEP INTERCULTURAL SOLIDARITY TRUE
COMMUNITY RESILIENCE ISN'T BUILT IN ISOLATION IT LIVES
IN THE PARTNERSHIP SHARED BETWEEN OUR ASIAN LATINO
AND DIVERSE IMMIGRANT COMMUNITIES WHO SHOW UP FOR ONE
ANOTHER. >> AND WHILE WE CELEBRATE THIS
COLLECTIVE STRENGTH, WE KNOW THAT TRUE RESILIENCE THRIVES
WHEN IT IS BACKED BY PROACTIVE AND SYSTEMIC INVESTMENT.
SO THANK YOU AGAIN SUPERVISOR CHEN FOR MAKE FOR MEETING THIS
MOMENT FOR PARTNERING WITH US AND FOR CHAMPIONING THE VISION
TO BUILD A FOUNDATION WHERE ALL WORKING CLASS AND IMMIGRANT
FAMILIES IN DISTRICT 11 CAN THRIVE.
>> THANK YOU AGAIN AGAINST
ALL RIGHT DISTRICT TWO SUPERVISOR CHERYL COLLEAGUES
TODAY IT IS MY HONOR TO RECOGNIZE JACK GRILLO.
JACK, WOULD YOU PLEASE COME UP TO THE FRONT?
>> TODAY I GET TO RECOGNIZE JACK THE EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR
AND A TEACHER AT THE LONE MOUNTAIN CHILDREN'S CENTER FOR
HIS 49 YEARS OF DEDICATION TO THE FAMILIES OF SAN FRANCISCO.
>> OVER THE LAST FIVE DECADES, JACK HAS BECOME SYNONYMOUS NOT
ONLY WITH LONE MOUNTAIN BUT WITH INDEPENDENT EARLY
CHILDHOOD EDUCATION. TODAY WE HONOR AN ICON A
STAUNCH ADVOCATE FOR EDUCATION AND A CHERISHED LEADER.
JACK'S ORIGINALLY FROM THE NORTH SHORE OF BOSTON.
HE HOLDS A BACHELOR'S IN HUMAN DEVELOPMENT WITH A SPECIALTY
IN EARLY CHILDHOOD FROM THE UNIVERSITY OF MASSACHUSETTS.
A MASTER'S IN COUNSELING PSYCHOLOGY FROM JOHN F KENNEDY
UNIVERSITY AND HIS VERY FIRST TEACHING JOB WAS IN A
LABORATORY PRESCHOOL AT HARVARD.
BUT JACK HAS CALLED SAN FRANCISCO HOME SINCE 1977 THE
SAME YEAR HE JOINED LONE MOUNTAIN AS A TEACHER.
FOUNDED IN 1974, LONE MOUNTAIN CHILDREN'S CENTER IS AN
INDEPENDENT NONPROFIT NONDENOMINATIONAL PRESCHOOL
LOCATED IN THE PRESIDIO IN DISTRICT TWO.
NOW JACK IS A UNICORN BECAUSE HE IS ALSO A LICENSED MARRIAGE
AND FAMILY THERAPIST. AND FOR OVER 25 YEARS HE
MAINTAINED A PRIVATE COUNSELING AND PSYCHOTHERAPY PRACTICE
ALONGSIDE HIS WORK AT LONE MOUNTAIN.
SO OF COURSE THE QUESTION REALLY IS WHETHER PARENTS
CHOOSE LONE MOUNTAIN FOR THE CHILDREN OR DO THEY REALLY
CHOOSE IT FOR THEMSELVES? >> NOW FOR THE PAST 30 YEARS AS
EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR OF LONE MOUNTAIN YOU HAVE SHAPED THE
SCHOOL INTO THE BELOVED INSTITUTION IT IS TODAY.
YOU HAVE HELPED REAR WELL OVER 2000 PRESCHOOLERS SHAPING NOT
JUST YOUNG CHILDREN BUT THE PERSONS THEY MAY BECOME.
YOU BUILT A CHERISHED COMMUNITY WHERE CHILDHOOD IS HONORED, JOY
IS PRIORITIZED AND LONG TENURED DEVOTED TEACHERS.
I SEE SOME OF YOU BACK HERE BUILD MEANINGFUL RELATIONSHIPS
WITH EVERY CHILD THEY TEACH AND THOSE TEACHERS ARE A
TESTAMENT TO JACK'S LEADERSHIP THE EXTRAORDINARY EDUCATORS HE
RECRUITED AND TRAINED OVER THE YEARS DIDN'T END UP AT LONE
MOUNTAIN BY ACCIDENT. >> THEY WERE DRAWN BY HIS
VISION AND THEY STAYED BECAUSE OF THE CULTURE HE BUILT YOUR
RETIREMENT IS A PERFECT EXAMPLE OF YOUR LEADERSHIP NOW JACK IS
AT THE HEIGHT OF HIS POWERS YET HE CHOSE PROACTIVELY TO STEP
DOWN IN ORDER TO ENSURE THE SCHOOL'S FUTURE AND TO SUPPORT
HIS SUCCESSOR THROUGH THE TRANSITION THAT TAKES
FORESIGHT, THAT TAKES SACRIFICE NOW TODAY IS AN HONOR FOR ME
BECAUSE SARAH AND I LIKE ALL THE OTHER PARENTS KNOW THAT THE
STUDENTS WHO LEARN THE MOST FROM YOU ARE NOT THE CHILDREN.
THEY ARE US THE PARENTS. AND I'LL ADMIT AND I KNOW I'M
NOT ALONE IN THIS THAT WHEN I FIRST MET YOU MY REACTION WAS
ONE OF INTIMIDATION AND BUT IT WORKED.
BUT YOUR QUIET CONFIDENCE, YOUR INNATE LEADERSHIP GAVE US THE
CLEAREST MESSAGE. I KNOW WHAT I'M DOING.
I'M VERY GOOD AT THIS. AND BY THE WAY, DO YOU SEE HOW
MUCH FUN THE CHILDREN ARE HAVING NOW I'M GOING TO STEAL
FOR LAUREN GROSS HERE BECAUSE SHE SAID IT BEST WE TRUSTED YOU
WITH THE MOST SACRED SLICE OF OURSELVES OUR KIDS YEAR AFTER
YEAR YOU ENJOYED AND LOVED EACH OF THEM EVEN WHEN PERHAPS YOU
FELT LESS COMPELLED BY THEIR ADULT COUNTERPARTS.
WE CAME TO YOU SOME AS FIRST TIME PARENTS OR EXPERIENCED
PARENTS DEFINITELY WORRIED PARENTS AND SOMETIMES LESS THAN
GRACEFUL PARENTS. YOU ALWAYS MET US IN YOUR
DIRECT POIGNANT WAY YOU NEVER SHIED FROM THE TRUTH EVER BLUNT
OFTEN HUMOROUS, RARELY INCORRECT BECAUSE JACKIE BABY
AND YES THAT IS WHAT THE KIDS CALL HIM THE FACT THAT HE WEARS
THAT NICKNAME WITH PRIDE TELLS YOU EVERYTHING YOU NEED TO KNOW
ABOUT THE MAN JACKIE BABY KNOWS THAT KIDS WITH TYPE-A SENIOR
FRANCISCO PARENTS SOMETIMES NEED A DOSE OF HUMBLING.
TAKE ONE BOY'S DRAWING FOR INSTANCE.
DO YOU LIKE IT, JACK? I THINK IT NEEDS A LITTLE WORK
OR THE LOVELY YOUNG LADY WHO ASKED IF YOU LIKED YOUR DRESS.
IT'S NOT MY FAVORITE. >> YOU ARE A STRAIGHT SHOOTER
AND THE CHILDREN LOVE YOU. >> THEY LOVE YOU.
>> JACK YOU ALWAYS SAID THAT KIDS FIND THE FUN AND THEY
ALWAYS FIND YOU AND YOU WELL WITH TEACHING YOU FOUND YOUR
CALLING AND THANK GOD YOU DID. IN APRIL YOU SHARED A POEM BY
FATHER PEDRO ARUP WITH US WHAT YOU ARE AND WHAT YOU ARE
IN LOVE WITH WHAT SEIZES YOUR IMAGINATION WILL AFFECT
EVERYTHING. IT WILL DECIDE WHAT WILL GET
YOU OUT OF BED IN THE MORNING, WHAT YOU DO WITH YOUR EVENINGS,
HOW YOU SPEND YOUR WEEKENDS, WHAT YOU READ, WHOM YOU KNOW,
WHAT BREAKS YOUR HEART AND WHAT AMAZES YOU WITH JOY
AND GRATITUDE. FALL IN LOVE STAY IN LOVE
AND IT WILL DECIDE EVERYTHING. JACK YOUR LAST WISH FOR US WAS
TO FALL IN LOVE. BUT JACK, WE ARE ALREADY
IN LOVE WITH YOU. YOU INSPIRE ME.
YOU SHOW THAT LOVE AND FIRMNESS GO HAND IN HAND THAT THERE IS
RIGHT AND THERE IS WRONG. THAT EXPECTATIONS ARE GOOD
BECAUSE WE ARE CAPABLE THAT YOU CAN TAKE YOUR WORK INCREDIBLY
SERIOUSLY WITHOUT TAKING YOURSELF TOO SERIOUSLY.
AND THAT HUMOR BELONGS IN EVERYTHING BECAUSE AT THE
END OF THE DAY IF WE'RE NOT HAVING FUN, WHAT'S THE POINT?
>> YOUR RETIREMENT IN JUST A FEW WEEKS WILL BRING YOU CLOSE
TO AN EXTRAORDINARY 49 YEAR TEACHING CAREER.
AND TO THOSE OF YOU IN THE AUDIENCE WHO JOINED US TO HONOR
JACK TODAY, THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR BEING HERE.
JACK, NEARLY 100 PEOPLE RSVP TO COME HERE FOR YOU TODAY.
AND THAT'S A DROP IN THE BUCKET OF THE LIVES THAT YOU'VE
TOUCHED. SO PLEASE LOOK BEHIND YOU.
LOOK AT THE CHILDREN, THE PARENTS, THE ALUMS.
>> ON BEHALF OF THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS OF THE CITY OF
COUNTY OF SAN FRANCISCO BUT MORE IMPORTANTLY FOR ME FROM
SARAH FROM ALL THE FAMILIES HERE, THANK YOU FOR YOUR LOVE,
FOR YOUR WARMTH, FOR YOUR WISDOM AND FOR BEING YOU.
>> THANK YOU. THANK YOU.
>> HOLD ON. SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD JACK I DON'T
KNOW YOU BUT I KNOW YOU THROUGH SUPERVISOR CHERYL AND I HEARD
SO MANY GOOD THINGS BUT I WOULDN'T LET UP THIS
OPPORTUNITY TO ASK A QUESTION WHICH IS IN SERVICE OF ALL
THESE KIDS. IT IS AMAZING THE PROFOUND
IMPACT CLEARLY THAT YOU'VE HAD ON GENERATIONS OF SAN
FRANCISCANS AND THEY'RE GOING TO REMEMBER YOU FOR YEARS
AND DECADES TO COME. >> BUT I ALWAYS LIKE TO TEASE
MY COLLEAGUE. >> SO WHAT GRADE WOULD YOU GIVE
SUPERVISOR CHERYL AS AS ONE OF THE PARENTS THAT COME TO YOUR
FACILITY AS A PARENT? YEAH, B-PLUS BUT IMPROVING.
>> KEEP THEM ON THEIR TOES. >> THE FLOOR IS YOURS.
I WAS ONLY TOLD ABOUT TEN MINUTES AGO THAT I HAVE AN
OPPORTUNITY TO TALK HERE TODAY AND WAS TOLD THAT I HAD TWO
MINUTES. SO THOSE OF YOU WHO KNOW ME SO
MANY HERE IN THIS ROOM KNOW THAT ONCE I GET IN FRONT OF A
MICROPHONE IT'S A LITTLE HARD FOR ME TO LIMIT MYSELF TO TWO
MINUTES SO I'LL ASK YOUR INDULGENCE BEFORE I EVEN BEGIN.
THANK YOU SO MUCH TO THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS ESPECIALLY TO
SUPERVISOR CHERYL AND HIS WIFE SARA FOR THIS HONOR.
I AM DEEPLY, DEEPLY TOUCHED BY THE PRESENCE OF ALL OF YOU WHO
ARE HERE TODAY. WHAT CAN I SAY?
IT'S I ARRIVED FROM BOSTON TO SAN FRANCISCO IN THE SUMMER OF
1977 AND VERY QUICKLY FELT THAT I WAS AT HOME AND I FELT
WELCOMED AND EMBRACED IN A DEEP SENSE OF BEING AT HOME IN THIS
BEAUTIFUL CITY. AND I WAS FORTUNATE THAT JUST A
FEW WEEKS AFTER ARRIVING TO COME TO LONE MOUNTAIN
CHILDREN'S CENTER AND VERY QUICKLY FELT THIS WAS HOME AS
WELL. SO HOME IS WHERE YOUR HEART IS.
HOME IS WHAT YOU INVEST IN. HOME IS WHERE YOU LOVE AND ARE
LOVED. AND ALL OF YOU REPRESENT HOME
TO ME. AND IT'S HARD TO LEAVE HOME.
I'M SO I'M NOT LEAVING. I CARRY ALL OF YOU WITH ME
IN MY HEART. THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR THE
PRIVILEGE OF ASSOCIATING WITH YOU OVER THESE 49 YEARS.
THANK YOU FOR SHARING THAT WHICH IS MOST BELOVED TO YOU
WITH ME. >> IT'S THOSE CHILDREN IN MY
EXPERIENCE OF BEING WITH THEM EACH DAY.
OVER THESE LAST 49 YEARS THEN I'M GOING TO MISS THE MOST
BECAUSE TRULY THAT'S WHERE I TOUCH INTO MY HEART.
SO AGAIN, THANK YOU FOR THIS WONDERFUL HONOR.
THANK YOU, STEPHEN. THANK YOU, SARAH.
THANK YOU TO THE ENTIRE BOARD. THANK YOU TO ALL OF YOU WHO ARE
HERE TODAY AND LET'S STAY IN TOUCH.
>> THANK YOU
. >> SUPERVISOR SHERYL IS
ENCOURAGING FOLKS TO GO OUTSIDE FOR A PHOTOGRAPH.
I GREW
IF ANYONE WANTS TO SIT DOWN WE DO HAVE SEATS AND WE ARE
NOWHERE NEAR GENERAL PUBLIC COMMENT.
I WOULD LIKE TO INVITE DENISON ANNIE HUANG AND THEIR KIDS
BIANCA AND CANDICE TO COME UP SO THEY STARTED OFF WITH DOING
IT ALL RIGHT. >> WE GOT THE WANG FAMILY TODAY
FOR THIS AND THANK YOU FOR YOUR PATIENCE FOR THIS.
2026 AAPI HERITAGE MONTH. IT IS MY GREAT PRIVILEGE TO
PRESENT A SPECIAL COMMENDATION TO LESLIE AND THE WONG FAMILY.
>> FOR MORE THAN THREE DECADES SINCE DENNIS AND ANNIE OPENED
IT, LESLIE HAS BEEN A FIXTURE IN SAN FRANCISCO'S FOOD SCENE
SERVING SAN FRANCISCANS. THE FLAVORS DENNIS CARRIED WITH
HIM FROM VIETNAM. DENNIS WAS 19 WHEN THE
VIETNAMESE GOVERNMENT SEIZED HIS FAMILY'S NOODLE BUSINESS
IN CHI MINH CITY. THEIR LIVELIHOOD DISAPPEARED
OVERNIGHT. HE AND HIS BROTHER BRIBED
OFFICIALS, BOARDED A BOAT AND FLED.
>> PIRATES AMBUSHED THEM IN OPEN WATER AND TOOK
EVERYTHING INCLUDING THE GOLD BARS THAT HIS MOTHER HAD
PRESSED INTO HIS HANDS AS HE ESCAPE.
>> HE SPENT TWO YEARS IN A REFUGEE CAMP IN MALAYSIA BEFORE
ARRIVING IN SAN FRANCISCO IN 1981.
>> HERE HE TOOK ENGLISH CLASSES BY DAY AND WASH DISHES AT NIGHT
SENDING WHAT MONEY HE COULD BACK TO VIETNAM FOR HIS PARENTS
WHOM HE WOULD NOT SEE AGAIN FOR MORE THAN A DECADE.
>> EVENTUALLY HE WAS PROMOTED TO LINE COOK AND DEVELOPED HIS
CULINARY SKILLS. IN 1993 HE AND ANNIE, A HONG
KONG NATIVE AND FORMER INTERIOR DESIGN STUDENTS, OPENED LA SOUL
AT 133 CLEMENT STREET. THERE DENNIS RAN THE KITCHEN
WHILE ANNIE DESIGNED THE SPACE AND MANAGED THE FRONT OF THE
HOUSE. >> THEIR DAUGHTERS BIANCA
AND CANDICE GREW UP AT THE RESTAURANT AND ALTHOUGH THEY
DID INITIALLY GO THEIR OWN WAYS BIANCA TO PROFESSIONAL KITCHENS
AND CANDIES TO ART AND DESIGN. THEY WOULD RETURN WHEN THE
FAMILY OPENED A SECOND LOCATION CONGRATULATE ASIANS SUPERVISOR
MELGAR AT STONE'S TOWNE GALLERIA LAST SUMMER TO A FULL
HOUSE WITH WITH MAYOR LURIE THERE AS WELL.
>> AT STONE'S SOUND ANNIE WAS ABLE TO REALIZE A MORE
EXPANSIVE CREATIVE VISION 88 SEATS WITH A SPACE FEATURING
LIVE TREES AND FLOWERS. BIANCA WORKED WITH DENNIS TO
CREATE NEW MENU ITEMS BLENDING CLASSICS WITH CONTEMPORARY
DISHES INCLUDING A FOR RISOTTO THAT BECAME ONE OF THE
RESTAURANT'S MOST POPULAR ITEMS .
CANDICE DRAWING ON THE CHINESE BRUSH PAINTINGS SHE PRACTICED
GROWING UP, DESIGNED THE MENUS AND UNIFORMS AND TOGETHER THE
STONE'S TOWN LOCATION REFLECTS THE WHOLE FAMILY.
>> BUT LISA LEE'S REACH EXTENDS BEYOND SAN FRANCISCO.
IN 2007, REPRESENTATIVES OF A HONG KONG REAL ESTATE DEVELOPER
DINED AT LA SILLA AND WERE SO IMPRESSED THEY ASKED DENNIS TO
LICENSE THE CONCEPT FOR A RESTAURANT IN HONG KONG.
DENNIS AGREED AND THE HONG KONG LOCATION IS NOW CELEBRATING 19
YEARS OF SUCCESS. AND THEN ON JUNE 25TH A SECOND
INTERNATIONAL LOCATION IS SCHEDULED TO OPEN IN CHINA'S
YUNNAN PROVINCE. IT WAS MY GREAT PRIVILEGE
TRAVELING WITH SUPERVISOR CHAN BACK IN NOVEMBER TO ACTUALLY
SEE THE SITE WHERE ALL THE RESORT THAT'S BEING BUILT THAT
THIS RESTAURANT IS GOING TO BE PART OF AND I'M SO EXCITED FOR
THAT TO HAPPEN FOR YOU ALL AND FOR ALL THE FUTURE
SUCCESSES SO AND OTHER SUPERVISORS ARE GOING TO WANT
TO SPEAK BUT DENNIS, ANNIE, BIANCA AND CANDICE AND TO THE
WHOLE THE SELECT TEAM. ON BEHALF OF THE BOARD OF
SUPERVISORS AND THE CITY OF COUNTY CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN
FRANCISCO, I WANT TO EXTEND MANY, MANY CONGRATULATIONS ON
ALL YOUR SUCCESSES AND BEST WISHES FOR MANY, MANY MORE.
AND NOW SUPERVISOR CHEN, THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU BOARD PRESIDENT MANDO MAN I THINK I JUST WANT
TO OBSERVE THAT DENNIS AND HIS JOURNEY IS TRULY AN AMERICAN
STORIES LEARNING FROM FROM DENNIS FROM LEARNING HOW TO
CODE TO WORKING TIRELESSLY DAY AND NIGHT TO EVENTUALLY
BUILDING A RESTAURANT OF THEIR OWN.
THEIR JOURNEY WAS FILLED WITH STRUGGLES, UNCERTAINTIES
AND COUNTLESS SACRIFICES THAT MANY MAY NEVER HAVE SEEN.
AT THE SAME TIME. THEY WERE RIGHT.
THEY WERE RAISING THREE BEAUTIFUL KIDS BUILDING NOT
JUST A BUSINESS IN SAN FRANCISCO BUT A FAMILY AND A
FUTURE THROUGH HOTWIRE PERSEVERANCE, PERSEVERANCE
AND A COMMITMENT TO EXCELLENCE. LE SOLEIL GREW FROM BELOVED
IN SAN FRANCISCO RESTAURANT INTO INTERNATIONAL PRESENCE
EXPANDING FROM SAN FRANCISCO TO HONG KONG AND NOW IN MAINLAND
KUNMING YUNNAN, CHINA. >> THAT IS SOMETHING THAT OUR
ENTIRE COMMUNITY CAN BE VERY PROUD OF.
>> AND YOUR STORY REMINDS US THAT IMMIGRANT STORIES ARE NOT
SMALL STORIES AND THEY HELP SHAPE OUR CITIES, OUR CULTURE
AND OUR FUTURE GENERATIONS. AND CONGRATULATION LESLIE.
CONGRATULATION ANY AND DENNIS AND MAY YOUR STORY CONTINUE TO
INSPIRE GENERATIONS TO COME. >> CONGRATULATION CANDICE
AND BIANCA. THANK YOU, NATHAN.
>> AND NOW THE FLOOR IS YOURS. >> I'M NERVOUS AND I SPEAKING
TOPIC. >> OH, OKAY.
OKAY. >> GOOD AFTERNOON EVERYONE.
THANK YOU FOR HAVING US. FIRST OF ALL, THANK YOU SO MUCH
TO BEST THAN BENJAMIN AND THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS FOR THIS
INCREDIBLE HONOR RECEIVING THIS COMMENDATIONS.
IT MEANS A LOT TO US OUR RESTAURANTS LASTLY HAS BEEN
SERVICE COMMITTEE FOR 33 YEARS ME, CHRISTINE RESTAURANTS TWO
YEARS OF POVERTY MEANS ABOUT 100 YEARS.
SOMEHOW WE SURVIVE CHANTING LABORERS RISING PRICES LONG
HOURS AND CUSTOMERS WHO STILL ASK WHY DOES FOOD TAKES TIME TO
CALL? >> BUT HONESTLY WE WOULD NOT
STILL BE HERE. WE OUR AMAZING STAFF IS LOYAL
CUSTOMERS FRIENDS AND FAMILIES THEN VACCINATIONS THEN BELONGS
TO ALL OF THEM TOO. >> OVER THE PAST 33 YEARS WE
HAVE WATCHING FAMILIES GROW OUR KIDS BECOME ADULTS AND SOME
CUSTOMERS PRACTICALLY BECOME PART OF OUR OWN FAMILY THAT IS
THE MOST REWARDING PART OF WHAT WE DO.
>> ONE THING OF RESTAURANTS THAT IS HEARTWARMING BUT BEEN
ABLE TO SERVE THIS COMMUNITY HAS ALWAYS AND MEGHAN WOLF,
WHILE WE ARE DEEPLY GRATEFUL FOR ALL THE SUPPORT, KINDNESS
AND LOVE, WE WILL SEE TO ALL OF THIS OUT THROUGHOUT THE YEARS.
>> THANK YOU AGAIN FOR THIS RECOGNITION AND THANK YOU
EVERYONE FOR CONTINUE TO SUPPORT SMALL LOCAL BUSINESS
LIKE US LOCAL BUSINESS ALLOWS AND OF COURSE PEACE COMING KEEP
COMING BACK HUNGRY. >> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
WELL THANK YOU. THANK YOU.
THANK YOU. WE'LL THANK YOU EVERY TIME SHE
SAYS THIS. OKAY, MADAM CLERK, LET'S GO TO
OUR 3 P.M. SPECIAL ORDER PLEASE CALL ITEMS 15 AND 16 ITEMS 15
AND 16 ARE COME COMPRISE OF A PUBLIC HEARING AND RESOLUTION
TO CONSIDER OBJECTIONS TO A REPORT CONTAINED IN ITEM 16.
>> DELINQUENT CHARGES FOR CODE ENFORCEMENT CASES WITH
DELINQUENT ASSESSMENT OF COSTS AND FEES SUBMITTED BY THE
DIRECTOR OF THE DEPARTMENT OF BUILDING INSPECTION FOR
SERVICES RENDERED. THIS SPECIAL ORDER WAS
SCHEDULED PURSUANT TO A MOTION APPROVED ON APRIL 7TH, 2026.
>> THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK. COLLEAGUES, WE'RE NOW SITTING
AS A COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE TO HOLD A HEARING ON THE REPORT OF
ASSESSMENT COSTS FOR BUILDING CODE ENFORCEMENT VIOLATIONS.
AND THE HEARING IS NOW OPEN AND WE'RE GOING TO START WITH
THE DEPARTMENT OF BUILDING INSPECTION.
>> WELCOME. THANK YOU.
PRESIDENT AND THE MEN MEMBERS OF THE BOARD.
GOOD AFTERNOON. MY NAME IS MATT LUTON.
I'M A SENIOR HOUSING INSPECTOR .
THIS IS THE 29TH YEAR THE DEPARTMENT OF BUILDING
INSPECTION IS BEFORE THIS BOARD REQUESTING THE IMPOSITION OF
SPECIAL ASSESSMENT LIENS. >> SO THIS IS THE 29TH YEAR THE
DEPARTMENT OF BUILDING INSPECTION IS BEFORE THIS BOARD
REQUESTING THE IMPOSITION OF SPECIAL ASSESSMENT LANDS ON
PROPERTIES FOR CODE ENFORCEMENT CASES.
PREVIOUSLY TRANSMITTED TO YOU IS THE REPORT OF DELINQUENT
CHARGES DATED APRIL 20TH, 2026. PRIOR TO TODAY'S HEARING TVI
HAS NOTICE THE LISTED PROPERTY OWNERS ON TWO SEPARATE
OCCASIONS AND HELD TWO IN-HOUSE HEARINGS FOR OWNERS TO DISCUSS
THEIR OUTSTANDING FEES. THE DEPARTMENT APPRECIATE YOUR
SUPPORT IN APPROVING THE REPORT OF DELINQUENT CHARGES AS THIS
IS A VERY IMPORTANT AND EFFECTIVE TOOL FOR COST
RECOVERY FOR TIME SPENT. ADDITIONALLY, I'D LIKE TO THANK
THE CLERK OF THE BOARD'S OFFICE FOR YOUR ASSISTANCE.
>> THANK YOU. ALL RIGHT.
>> THANK YOU. WE'RE NOW GOING TO OPEN THIS UP
TO PUBLIC COMMENT. IF YOU'RE A MEMBER OF THE
PUBLIC WHO WOULD LIKE TO SPEAK ON ITEM 15 AND 16 THE LEAN
MATTER YOU CAN COME UP TO THE PODIUM OR LINE UP OVER TO YOUR
RIGHT OR LEFT MY LEFT. >> IF YOU'RE HERE TODAY FOR
THESE ITEMS BUT YOU DO NOT WANT TO PROVIDE PUBLIC TESTIMONY YOU
WILL HAVE THE OPPORTUNITY TO SPEAK WITH GBI STAFF OUTSIDE
THE CHAMBER TO RESOLVE YOUR ISSUE.
PUBLIC COMMENT IS NOW OPEN. ALL SPEAKERS ARE GOING TO BE
ALLOTTED TWO MINUTES TO PROVIDE THEIR COMMENTS.
MADAM CLERK, WILL YOU PLEASE CALL THE FIRST SPEAKER?
>> LET'S WELCOME OUR FIRST SPEAKER.
PLEASE COME ON UP TO THE PODIUM .
>> I'M A HALL NUMBER TEN. I OWN 201 ASHTON AVENUE ON THE
LIST NOT ON THE LIST. >> IN 2017 WE REPAIRED OUR
DILAPIDATED FENCE. WE ADDED SAFETY LIGHTING TO
ENHANCE NIGHTTIME PEDESTRIAN SAFETY ALONG THE SIDEWALK.
THE STYLE OF THE FENCE WAS CHOSEN TO PREVENT NUISANCE
VEGETABLE MATTER GRASS, WEEDS AND VEGETATION OVERGROWTH FROM
IMPINGING THE SIDEWALK AND THE INCREASED VISIBILITY AND SAFETY
OF THE REPAIRED FENCE. ALSO PROTECTS THE INGLESIDE
TERRACES LANDMARK PILLARS DURING THE FINAL STAGES OF THE
FENCE REPAIR. >> WHILE WE WERE STAINING THE
FENCE A NEIGHBOR FILED A311 COMPLAINT QUOTE THE RESIDENT AT
THIS ADDRESS HAS BEEN CONSISTENTLY DOING CONSTRUCTION
AND PLAYING LOUD MUSIC FROM 10 A.M. TO 6 TO 7 P.M. MOST DAYS
OF THE WEEK I WOULD LIKE TO REQUEST THE MUSIC VOLUME BE
LOWERED OR TURNED OFF. >> I CAN HEAR IT IN MY
APARTMENT ALL DAY. >> DV I USE THIS MUSIC
COMPLAINT TO CONDUCT AN UNCONSTITUTIONAL SEARCH OF OUR
PROPERTY AND FILED A NOTICE OF VIOLATION REQUIRING A PERMIT TO
REPAIR THE FENCE. WE SUBMITTED THE MANDATED FENCE
REPAIR PERMIT BUT A VARIANCE WAS THEN MANDATED TO ALLOW THE
FOUR FOOT HEIGHT OF THE HISTORICALLY FOUR FOOT FENCE
AFTER THE VARIANCE WAS APPROVED.
DB I AM PLANNING APPROVED THE PERMIT BUT DPW PLACED A HOLD ON
THE PERMIT CLAIMING OUR PUBLIC UTILITY EASEMENT WAS INSTEAD AN
UNPAVED CITY SIDEWALK. IN ORDER TO MANDATE ONE A MINOR
SIDEWALK ENCROACHMENT PERMIT TO A BUILDING PLUMBING AN
EXCAVATION PERMIT TO REMOVE THE PERMITTED FIRE TABLE.
>> AND THREE AN EXCAVATION PERMIT TO REMOVE OUR ARBOR.
>> WHILE BUILDING CODE REQUIRES UNSAFE PROPERTY TO JUSTIFY A
NOTICE OF VIOLATION. DB I FILED A NOTICE OF
VIOLATION FOR SAFE PROPERTY AND THEN ISSUED AN ORDER OF
ABATEMENT FOR DPW WHOSE ILLEGAL HOLD ON THE FENCE REPAIR PERMIT
BASED ON DPW CLAIM OF AN INCONSISTENT THREE TIMES
CONCLUDED AND TO THE MEMBERS AT THE DEPARTMENT OF BUILDING
INSPECTION HAS REPORTED TO US THAT THAT ADDRESS HAS BEEN
REMOVED FROM THE LIST. WELCOME TO OUR NEXT SPEAKER.
THANK YOU. MY NAME IS NOELLE CARRASCO.
I'M THEIR PROPERTY OWNER OF THREE TOURS.
>> CAN YOU LIFT THAT THE MICROPHONE AND JUST SPEAK INTO
IT CLEARLY? THANK YOU.
MY PROPERTY IS 336338 PARNASSUS AVENUE.
I'M HERE BECAUSE MY CASE I BELIEVE THERE IS A CLEAR
VIOLATION OF DUE PROCESS. I HAVE BEEN ASSESSED FEES FOR A
FOR SOMETHING THAT IS NOT ON MY PROPERTY.
I HAVE PROVIDED SURVEYORS REPORT TO THE CITY.
I HAVE A SIGNED MOTION BY A JUDGE SAYING THAT IT'S NOT ON
MY PROPERTY AND STILL AFTER FOUR YEARS I'M STILL GETTING
ASSESSMENT FEES. I ALWAYS SAY I ALWAYS GET FROM
THE BUILDING DEPARTMENT THEY SAY IT'S IN THE PROPERTY LINE.
DESPITE ME SHOWING THEM MY SURVEYORS REPORT AND THIS PART
OF ME HAVING A JUDGE RULING THAT IS NOT ON MY PROPERTY HAS
BEEN FOR YEARS. I DON'T KNOW WHAT TO MAKE OF
THIS. THERE IS NO EVIDENCE AND CAN
CONVINCE ANYBODY. AND I'M HERE TO KNOW WHY AM I
HERE? IF NOT, I SHOULDN'T BE HERE TO
DEFEND MY INNOCENCE. THE ASSESSMENT FEES SHOULD BE
GIVEN WHEN THERE IS ENOUGH EVIDENCE TO ASSESS THEM.
OTHERWISE WE MIGHT AS WELL JUST I MEAN I DON'T WANT TO THINK OF
A SCENARIO WHERE THAT DOESN'T HAPPEN.
IF I DIDN'T COMMIT A VIOLATION ON MY PROPERTY I CANNOT ABATE
IT. I CANNOT ASK FOR A PERMIT FOR A
VIOLATION THAT IS NOT ON MY PROPERTY BECAUSE IT'S NOT ON MY
PROPERTY. IT'S REALLY GETTING A LITTLE
BIT REPETITIVE. >> BUT THAT HAS BEEN MY
SITUATION FOR THE LAST 40 YEARS.
>> THANK YOU SIR. CAN YOU JUST PUT TELL US YOUR
ADDRESS IN ON THE RECORD ONE MORE TIME?
WAS THAT HIGH STREET THREE 36 AND 338 PARNASSUS AVENUE.
PARNASSUS. OKAY.
THANK YOU. AND SO, SIR, YOU'RE WELCOME TO
GO INTO THE HALLWAY AND SPEAK WITH THE BUILDING INSPECTOR AS
THEY WILL ADDRESS YOUR ISSUES THERE.
>> WELCOME TO OUR NEXT SPEAKER .
>> WELL, GOOD AFTERNOON. MY NAME IS DARREN WINKY.
I'M HERE ON BEHALF OF MY MOTHER, SHELLY WINKY, THE
PROPERTY OWNER OF 2920 24TH AVENUE.
SHE IS UNABLE TO ATTEND TODAY DUE TO A MEDICAL APPOINTMENT
OUTSIDE THE COUNTRY. I HAVE HER WRITTEN
AUTHORIZATION TO REPRESENT HER. >> MY MOTHER RESPECTFULLY
REQUEST WAIVER OR SUSPENSION OF THE ASSESSMENT COSTS.
THE CIRCUMSTANCES LEADING TO THE VIOLATIONS WERE OUTSIDE HER
CONTROL. SHE WAS MEDICALLY INCAPACITATED
DURING THE COMPLIANCE PERIOD UNDERGOING MULTIPLE EYE
SURGERIES. >> THE DOWNSTAIRS TENANT
OBSTRUCTED ACCESS, DEMANDED PAYMENT FOR ENTRY AND FILED
FALSE COMPLAINTS WHICH DEBBIE LATER CONFIRMED WERE UNFOUNDED.
THE MANAGEMENT COMPANY TERMINATED ITS CONTRACT AFTER A
FALSE POSITIVE ACCUSATION LEAVING HER WITHOUT
REPRESENTATION WHILE SHE WAS INCAPACITATED.
ALL TENANTS HAVE NOW VACATED AND SHE IS PURSUING LEGAL
POSSESSION OF THE PROPERTY TO COMPLETE CORRECTIVE WORK.
>> GIVEN THESE CIRCUMSTANCES WE ASK THAT THE BOARD WAIVE OR
SUSPEND THE ASSESSMENT AND CONFIRM THAT NO LEAN WILL
BE RECORDED UNTIL LAWFUL POSSESSION IS RESTORED
AND REPAIRS CAN BE COMPLETED. MY MOTHER IS COMMITTED TO
BRINGING THE PROPERTY IN THE FULL COMPLIANCE ONCE ACCESS IS
AVAILABLE. >> THANK YOU FOR YOUR TIME.
>> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. OKAY.
WELCOME TO THE NEXT SPEAKER. >> HI.
MY NAME IS JEAN CATANIA. I'M HERE ON BEHALF OF GERARD
GOETZE. HE'S THE OWNER OF 83 SUTTER
STREET. I'M HERE TODAY TO KIND OF
PROTEST THE WAY THIS NOTICE OF VIOLATIONS IN THE HOME DEALING
WITH THE BUILDING DEPARTMENT HAS TRANSPIRED.
I HAVE DOCUMENTATION AND WHERE THERE IS THERE WAS A NOTICE OF
VIOLATIONS FOR PLUMBING WORK WITHOUT A PERMIT WHICH WAS DONE
BY ANOTHER CONTRACTOR AND IT WAS DONE AND THE NOTICE OF
VIOLATIONS GO BACK TO DECEMBER OF PRIOR TO DECEMBER OF 2024.
SO IN AN ATTEMPT TO RECTIFY THIS PROBLEM THAT THE OWNER
HIRED ME WHICH I ATTEMPTED TO PULL PERMIT I HAVE
DOCUMENTATION THAT I TRIED SINCE DECEMBER OF 2024 TO PULL
PERMITS. HOWEVER, WHEN I WENT THROUGH
THE WHOLE PROCESS OF EVERY STATION AT THE BUILDING
DEPARTMENT AND I GET TO WHERE TO PAY FOR THE PERMIT I WAS
TOLD THAT THAT THE USAGE WAS NOT CORRECT.
IT WAS IT WAS IN THE COMPUTER FROM THE BUILDING DEPARTMENT AS
A RESIDENTIAL. BUT WHEN I GOT TO PAY THEY SAID
NO, IT'S THE USAGE IS FOR OFFICE RETAIL.
SO I HAD TO GO BACK AND HAVE THAT HAVE AN ARCHITECT CHANGE
THE PLANS COME BACK WHICH TAKES TIME AND THERE WAS A TOTAL OF
FIVE TIMES WHERE I HAD TO HAVE AN ARCHITECT CHANGE PLANS
BECAUSE OF ERRORS WITHIN THE COMPUTERS IN THE BUILDING
DEPARTMENT. >> THEY ASSESSED THESE
PENALTIES WHICH I FEEL THAT ARE NOT FAIR BECAUSE THERE WAS
PROACTIVE WE WERE PROACTIVE IN TRYING TO RECTIFY THIS
PROBLEM. HOWEVER, BECAUSE OF ERRORS
WITHIN THE COMPUTER OF THE BUILDING DEPARTMENT IT JUST
PROLONGED EVERYTHING TO WHERE THE ASSESSMENTS ARE NOW WE HAVE
LIKE THERE'S THREE DIFFERENT THERE'S THREE DIFFERENT
ASSESSMENTS OF VIOLATIONS ONCE FOR PLUMBING ONES FOR UP TO
$10,000 FOR ONE IS FOR PLUMBING WITHOUT A PERMIT FOR ELECTRICAL
WITHOUT A PERMIT AND THEN THANK YOU SIR.
>> THANK YOU BOTH FOR YOUR COMMENTS TODAY.
YOU'RE WELCOME TO GO OUT INTO THE HALLWAY AND SPEAK TO THE
BUILDING INSPECTOR MATT LUTON. >> OKAY.
WELCOME TO THE NEXT SPEAKER. YES, GOOD AFTERNOON.
>> MY NAME IS DMITRI DUPUIS AND I'M HERE ON BEHALF OF
SALVATORE LETTORI, OWNER OF 1700 LOMBARD STREET.
THERE WERE SOME PERMIT VIOLATIONS WHICH HAVE BEEN
CORRECTED FOR THE MOST PART. WE GOT TO SIGN OFF ON ALL OF
THEM MINUS HEALTH WHICH HAS BEEN CORRECTED AND THEY'RE
COMING BACK ON THURSDAY TO SIGN OFF ON THAT AND WE'LL HAVE
COMPLETION. >> SO JUST WANTED TO BRING THAT
TO THE ATTENTION. >> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS
. THANK YOU.
>> WELCOME TO THE NEXT SPEAKERS .
>> HELLO. MY NAME'S LOUIS VAUGHN.
I'M HERE ON BEHALF OF SAM TANNOCK REGARDING FILE NUMBER
260231. MR. TANNER OWNS A PROPERTY
IN SAN FRANCISCO. THERE WAS AN ISSUE REGARDING
THE LEGALITY OF A ADU UNIT IN THIS PROPERTY.
THIS STARTED I BELIEVE A YEAR AND A HALF OR TWO YEARS AGO
REGARDING THE NEED EITHER TO DEMOLISH UNIT OR TO MAKE IT
LEGAL. AND THIS A CANDIDATE TO BE
WORKING WITH THE BUILDING DEPARTMENT.
SINCE THAT TIME ORIGINALLY HE'S UNDERSTANDING THAT THE UNITS
WILL BE DEMOLISHED AND HE APPLIED FOR A PERMIT TO GET THE
PROPERTY DEMOLISHED AND HE HAS GOT THAT PERMIT.
NOW THEY'RE SAYING THAT IT SHOULD BE NOT DEMOLISHED
AND SAYING THEY SHOULD LEGALIZE THE UNITS AND AND ARE ASSESSING
PENALTY FEES AND COSTS BECAUSE HE'S ABLE TO COMPLY WITH THAT.
SO I BELIEVE HE RECEIVED THIS LATEST LETTER SAYING THAT THEY
CAN PUT A LIEN ON THIS PROPERTY.
BUT I BELIEVE THAT HE HIMSELF DID NOT RECEIVE OR PRIOR TO
NOTICE OF WHAT THIS THESE COSTS ARE WHY HOW THEY GENERATE THESE
COSTS. I WOULD LIKE A IF POSSIBLE
CONTINUOUS MAYBE 60 DAYS TO WORK WITH THE BUILD DEPARTMENT
AND SEE WHETHER WE CAN RESOLVE THIS OLINE ISSUE AND HOPEFULLY
WHETHER EITHER GET IT AMENDED OR VACATE IT OR OR PAID OFF.
>> HE NEEDS HELP. CAN YOU TELL US THE ADDRESS FOR
930 BRUSSELS. >> 930 INTO THE MICROPHONE
PLEASE. 930 BRUSSELS STREET, SAN
FRANCISCO 94134. >> ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU. AND IF YOU CAN GO OUT INTO THE
HALLWAY AND SPEAK TO THE BUILDING INSPECTOR MATT LUTON.
>> THANK YOU. SHOULD WE COME BACK AFTER WE'RE
DONE? MATT WILL RETURN THE BUILDING
INSPECTOR WILL RETURN WITH A WITH A REPORT THAT THE BOARD
WILL CONSIDER. THANK YOU.
THANK YOU. WELCOME TO THE NEXT SPEAKERS.
>> HELLO. MY NAME IS ABDULWAHAB AND I'M
HERE BEHAVIOR 26 AND 28 SIXTH STREET.
I'M THE BUSINESS OWNER FOR THE PLACE AND I'M HERE FOR THE
INSPECTION. THEY WANT TO LEND THE BUILDING
AND I BELIEVE SO VERY FAST THAT OLD TUNNEL HE STARTED WORKING
AND THEN HE SHUT DOWN THE BUSINESS AND THEN I GET THE
BUSINESS. WHEN I START I DID EVERYTHING
PERFECT. EVERYTHING WITH I HAVE
EVERYTHING DONE BUT I JUST RECEIVED THE VIOLATION AND I
HOPE THEY JUST TAKE IT AWAY. >> APOLOGIES SIR.
CAN YOU GIVE US THAT ADDRESS AGAIN?
>> IT'S 26 AND 26TH STREET SO IT'S TWO OTHER SPOTS ONE
BUILDING. >> THANK YOU, SIR.
WE'RE GOING TO COME TO YOU AND TRY TO GET A LITTLE CLARITY
ON THAT ADDRESS SO WE'LL SPEAK TO YOU AT THE AT THE O.
>> OKAY. HERE SHE COMES RIGHT NOW.
HI THERE. WELCOME.
OH, I'M FREDRICK CARDENAS. I'M HERE REPRESENTING BEL
PROPERTIES. >> WE HAVE TO WE HAVE QUITE A
BIT OF FEES AND FINES ON SOME PROPERTIES THAT THERE WAS NO
PEATOS PROMISE TO OPERATE BUT WE DO HAVE THE PROMISE TO
OPERATE SO WE WILL SEE IF WE COULD GET THOSE FEES REDUCED.
ALSO THERE'S A SECOND PROPERTY SAYING THERE WAS NO DEMO PERMIT
ALSO FEES AND FINES BUT WE DO HAVE THE DEMO PERMITS.
THEY'RE ON FILE. CAN YOU GIVE US THE ADDRESS?
YEAH, ONE OF THEM IS 1949 SUNNYDALE AVENUE.
>> SECOND ONE IS 1250 BUCHANAN STREET.
THANK YOU SO MUCH. >> OKAY.
>> HEY, WELCOME TO THE NEXT SPEAKER.
>> HELLO. GOOD AFTERNOON.
MY NAME IS WILLIE SANCHEZ AND REPRESENTING MARIA BELTRAN
FOR PROPERTY 426 EDINBURG STREET.
I'M HERE TO SEE IF WE CAN GO AHEAD AND WAIVE THE ASSESSMENT.
WE'VE BEEN GOING THROUGH THIS WHOLE THING WITH OUR
CONTRACTORS FOR FIRST TIME FOR EXPERIENCE OUR HOUSE BEING
BURNT DOWN. WE WANT TO MAKE SURE THAT WE
GET EVERYTHING UNDER CONTROL. I'VE BEEN GOING THROUGH A LOT
OF LOOPHOLES AND FAILURES AND FINALLY I GOT SOMEBODY WHO
AND CONTRACTOR TO HELP US OUT BASED ON OUR FAMILY
RECOMMENDATIONS. SO I WOULD LIKE TO SEE IF WE
CAN PROCEED WITH THAT AND GET OUR ASSESSMENT WAIVED AT THE
MOMENT I KNOW WE'VE BEEN GOING THROUGH THIS FOR MONTHS BUT I
THINK AT THIS POINT WE'RE AT THE RIGHT POINT TO KEEP GOING
NOW AND LIKE I SAID, I WOULD LIKE TO GO AHEAD AND HOPEFULLY
WE CAN GET THAT WAIVED OUT. >> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
YOU WANT TO GO BACK? >> ALL RIGHT.
WELCOME TO THE NEXT SPEAKER. WELCOME.
>> MY NAME IS OWEN SMITH AND THIS IS REGARDS TO MY
MOTHER LORRAINE SMITH TO ADDRESS 966 KEY AVENUE SAN
FRANCISCO, CALIFORNIA 94124. WE HAD A MEETING AT 49 SOUTH
VAN NESS. THERE WAS SOME WORK DONE BY A
PLUMBER BUT THAT DONE DIDN'T, YOU KNOW, GET A CHANCE TO LOOK
AT IT. I HAD THE CONCRETE OPENED UP.
THE INSPECTOR CAME OUT AND INSPECTED IT AT THE TIME I
HAD DIABETES I WASN'T THERE BUT THE INSPECTOR WAS THERE AND THE
PLUMBER THE WORK WAS ACTUALLY DONE BUT I STILL HAVE AN
ASSESSMENT FEE OF $4,900 AND YOU SAID 966 IT WAS EXCUSE
ME THIS WAS AT 970 QI AVENUE. I'M SORRY.
OKAY. 970 QI AVENUE, SAN FRANCISCO,
CALIFORNIA 94124 AND THE WORK IS COMPLETED AND THE INSPECTOR
WAS THERE LAST WEEK. LAST TUESDAY.
>> OKAY, GREAT. THANK YOU.
WE HAVE YOUR ADDRESS. AND SO IF YOU GO INTO THE
HALLWAY AND SPEAK TO THE INSPECTORS THERE THANK YOU VERY
MUCH. THANK YOU, SIR.
>> WELCOME TO THE NEXT SPEAKER .
>> GOOD AFTERNOON. MY NAME IS KWONG LEE.
I'M THE OWNER OF 229 LEE AVENUE.
THE REASON I COME IS THE ACCESS ME WITH THE 6740 PROPERTY BUT I
WOULD TRY TO FIX IT. THEY WON'T LET ME IN AND THEN
THE LAST SIX MONTHS SIX YEARS I DIDN'T COLLECT ANY RENT THE
TENANT GIVES STAY IN THERE AND THEY DON'T PAY ANY RENT
AND I COULD NOT GET THEM OUT AND THEN THEY FINALLY LEFT
ABOUT A YEAR AND A HALF AGO AND I STILL LEAVE THE DOCK
AND ALL THE CAR IN FRONT OF MY HOUSE AND THEN FINALLY I GOT
THEM OUT ABOUT FOUR MONTHS AGO. SO I WOULD APPRECIATE IT IF YOU
CAN HELP ME TO REDO THE ASSESSMENT OF THE COSTS.
THANK YOU, SIR. >> YOU INDICATED 2390 NO.
229 LEE AVENUE 229 LEE AVENUE. >> YES.
THANK YOU. AND WE HAVE YOUR ADDRESS IF YOU
CAN. THANK YOU TO THE HALLWAY
AND SPEAK TO THE GENTLEMAN OUT THERE.
>> THANK YOU. OKAY.
WELCOME, SIR. GOOD AFTERNOON.
MY NAME IS ARMAND PANTALEON AND I'M HERE WITH REGARDS TO
525 O'FARRELL. AND THIS IS A REQUEST TO WAIVE
PENALTIES THAT WE INCURRED JUST TO EXPLAIN WAY BACK IN OCTOBER
WE WERE WORKING WITH THE STATE TO GET AN OPERATOR UPGRADE
PERMIT FOR OUR ELEVATOR. AND DURING THAT TIME THE STATE
SHUT DOWN OUR LOAN ELEVATOR AND BUT IT WAS WORKING BEFORE
IT JUST FOR SAFETY REASON THEY ASKED US TO STOP USING IT UNTIL
WE CONDUCTED NECESSARY TEST WE WHICH WE DID BY NOVEMBER BUT
THERE WASN'T AN INSPECTOR FROM THE FBI THAT SHOWED UP SOMETIME
IN DECEMBER THROUGH I THINK THROUGH OUR COMPLAINT SUBMITTED
BY ONE OF OUR TENANTS. BUT HE DIDN'T TEST THE
ELEVATOR. THE ELEVATOR WAS WORKING.
IT WAS ALREADY WORKING DURING THAT TIME AND I THINK IT'S JUST
THE COMMUNICATION THING THAT YEAH I UNTIL NOW LIKE I'M STILL
WAITING UP FOR A RESPONSE TO THE EMAIL REQUEST.
>> I'VE SAID LIKE MORE THAN FIVE WEEKS AGO.
>> OKAY WELL THANK YOU FOR COMING DOWN TODAY.
CAN YOU GO INTO THE HALLWAY AND WORK WITH THE BUILDING
INSPECTOR THERE? THANK YOU.
>> YOU'RE WELCOME. ARE THERE ANY OTHER MEMBERS OF
THE PUBLIC WHO'D LIKE TO ADDRESS THE DEPARTMENT OF
BUILDING INSPECTION DELINQUENT CHARGES FOR CODE ENFORCEMENT
VIOLATIONS OR ANY ASSOCIATED FEES?
>> OKAY, MR. PRESIDENT. THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK.
PUBLIC COMMENT IS NOW CLOSED AND ITEM NUMBER 15 HAS BEEN
HEARD AND IS NOW FILED. >> SO IF THERE ARE PEOPLE WHO
WISH TO SPEAK WITH DBA STAFF REGARDING THE THE ASSESSMENT ON
THEIR PROPERTY, I'D ASK YOU TO GO OUT INTO THE HALLWAY NOW
AND STAFF IS THERE TO SPEAK WITH YOU AND WE WILL COME BACK
TO ITEM NUMBER 16 LATER IN THE MEETING.
>> AND WITH THAT, MADAM CLERK, I THINK WE GO BACK TO ROLL CALL
AND SUPERVISOR DORSEY YES MR. PRESIDENT.
>> EXCUSE ME SUPERVISOR DORSEY .
THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK. COLLEAGUES I HAVE AN
IN MEMORIAM TODAY FOR JACK DAVIS.
JACK WAS MANY THINGS TO MANY PEOPLE IN THIS CITY.
FEARED, ADMIRED, LOATHED. LOVED SOMETIMES ALL FOUR IN THE
SAME PERSON SOMETIMES ALL FOUR IN THE SAME WEEK.
HE ARRIVED IN SAN FRANCISCO IN 1972 THE WAY MANY OF US DO
WITH NOT MUCH MONEY A COMPLICATED FAMILY STORY
AND THE SENSE THAT THIS WAS ONE CITY IN THE WORLD WHERE HE
COULD BECOME EXACTLY WHO HE WAS HIS CAR WAS STOLEN HIS FIRST
NIGHT HERE OUTSIDE OF THE STUD ON FOLSOM STREET.
HE STAYED ANYWAY AND THAT PERHAPS TELLS YOU SOMETHING.
HE CAME TO THE CITY AS A GAY RIGHTS ACTIVIST AND AN IDEALIST
AND HE NEVER FULLY SHARED EITHER OF THOSE THINGS EVEN AS
HE BECAME SOMETHING MUCH HARDER TO CATEGORIZE A LEGENDARY BARE
KNUCKLED POLITICAL BRAWLER HE WORKED FOR CONSERVATIVES
AND LIBERALS FOR LANDLORDS AND LABOR FOR FRANK JORDAN
AND WILLIE BROWN SOMETIMES SEQUENTIALLY ALWAYS
STRATEGICALLY. SOME PEOPLE CALLED THAT
OPPORTUNISM. JACK CALLED IT UNDERSTANDING
HOW THE CITY ACTUALLY WORKS AND HE DID UNDERSTAND IT BETTER
THAN ALMOST ANYONE. HE WAS ALSO BY ALL ACCOUNTS A
HANDFUL. HE KNEW IT, HE SAID SO HE NAMED
HIS BOAT ELECTION NIGHT. THAT'S NIGHT WITH THE K AND AS
HE SAID IN 2000 TO SAN FRANCISCO CHRONICLE REPORTER
SUSAN SWARD THOSE WERE THE WORDS HE'D PUT ON HIS TOMBSTONE
NOT BECAUSE HE WAS MODEST BUT BECAUSE HE WAS HONEST.
WINNING WAS THE THING AND HE WANTED CREDIT FOR IT.
I MET JACK DAVIS ONLY ON A FEW OCCASIONS DURING MY OWN EARLY
YEARS IN SAN FRANCISCO POLITICS AND I HAD A LOT MORE
FAMILIARITY WITH THIS REPUTATION THAN I DID WITH HIM
PERSONALLY. BUT WHAT CONSISTENTLY EMERGES
FROM THE REMEMBRANCES I HAVE HEARD OF HIM IS THAT JACK DAVIS
ALWAYS SHOWED UP. HE SHOWED UP FOR WILLIE BROWN
WHEN IT WAS A RISK HE SHOWED UP FOR GAVIN NEWSOM WHEN THE MATH
DIDN'T LOOK GOOD HE SHOWED UP FOR CAUSES HE BELIEVED IN IN
THE ANTI-DISCRIMINATION FIGHT IN FLORIDA, IN THE STADIUM
CAMPAIGNS, IN THE EARLY COALITIONS THAT HELPED TO MAKE
SAN FRANCISCO A CITY WHERE A MAN LIKE JACK DAVIS COULD LIVE
OPENLY AND BUILD SOMETHING REMARKABLE.
HE WAS NOT A SAINT AND HE WOULD HAVE BEEN THE FIRST TO TELL YOU
THAT PROBABLY WITH SOME RELISH. BUT HE WAS OURS A GENUINE SAN
FRANCISCO ORIGINAL A KIND OUR CITY DOESN'T SEEM TO PRODUCE
MANY OF THESE DAYS AND PERHAPS THAT'S NOT AN ENTIRELY BAD
THING WHEN HE PASSED AWAY LAST WEEK, JACK DAVIS HAD JUST
TURNED 79 YEARS OLD. HE SPENT THE MAJORITY OF THOSE
YEARS SHAPING OUR CITY DIRECTLY OR INDIRECTLY AND HOWEVER 1ST
MAY FEEL ABOUT HIS METHODS, THE RESULTS OF HIS POLITICAL
EFFORTS ARE WRITTEN INDELIBLY IN THE STREETS NEIGHBORHOOD
AND SKYLINE OF THE CITY WE LOVE.
REST IN PEACE ELECTION NIGHT AND MAY YOUR MEMORY BE A
BLESSING AND THE REST I SUBMIT .
THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR DORSEY, PLEASE HOLD
YOUR APPLAUSE THERE. WE DO HAVE A BOARD RULE THAT
WHEN WE'RE CONDUCTING ROUTINE BUSINESS WE DO NOT APPLAUSE.
THAT ONLY HAPPENS DURING COMMENDATIONS.
THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD.
COLLEAGUES ACROSS THE COUNTRY WE ARE WATCHING POLITICIANS
TURN HEALTH CARE IDENTITY AND SELF-EXPRESSION INTO
GROUNDS FOR PUNISHMENT. >> AND AT LEAST 13 STATES
ABORTION IS NOW BANNED ENTIRELY AND ENFORCED WITH CRIMINAL
PENALTIES. ACROSS THE COUNTRY PEOPLE ARE
BEING INVESTIGATED, PROSECUTED AND CRIMINALIZED FOR SEEKING
REPRODUCTIVE HEALTH CARE, EXPERIENCING MISCARRIAGE OR
SIMPLY HELPING SOMEONE ACCESS CARE.
>> AT THE SAME TIME, MORE THAN 28 ANTI-TRANS BILLS HAVE
ALREADY BEEN PASSED IN 2026 ALONE TARGETING GENDER
AFFIRMING CARE. DRAG PERFORMANCE AND LGBTQ PLUS
EXPRESSION. >> AND WHEN PEOPLE ARE
CRIMINALIZED UNDER THESE DISCRIMINATORY LAWS THOSE
CONVICTIONS CAN FOLLOW THEM LONG AFTER THEY LEAVE THOSE
STATES. THEY CAN FOLLOW SOMEONE INTO A
JOB INTERVIEW, INTO AN AFFORDABLE HOUSING APPLICATION
INTO EVERY ATTEMPT TO REBUILD THEIR LIFE SAFELY AND WITH
DIGNITY. SAN FRANCISCO HAS LONG BEEN A
REFUGE FOR PEOPLE SEEKING FREEDOM, SAFETY AND OPPORTUNITY
. AND WE MUST ENSURE THAT
DISCRIMINATORY LAWS FROM OTHER STATES DO NOT CONTINUE HARMING
PEOPLE ONCE THEY ARRIVE HERE. THAT'S WHY TODAY I AM
INTRODUCING LEGISLATION TO STRENGTHEN AND EXPAND SAN
FRANCISCO'S FAIR CHANCE ORDINANCE.
THE CURRENT FAIR CHANCE ORDINANCE LIMITS HOW EMPLOYERS
EMPLOYERS IN AFFORDABLE HOUSING PROVIDERS CAN USE CRIMINAL
HISTORY IN EMPLOYMENT AND HOUSING DECISIONS.
>> THIS LEGISLATION UPDATES THAT FRAMEWORK TO RESPOND TO
THE CHANGING LEGAL LANDSCAPE THAT WE SEE ACROSS THE COUNTRY.
>> SPECIFICALLY THIS LEGISLATION MAKES CLEAR THAT
EMPLOYERS AND AFFORDABLE HOUSING PROVIDERS IN SAN
FRANCISCO CANNOT USE OUT OF STATE CONVICTIONS RELATED TO
REPRODUCTIVE HEALTH CARE, GENDER AFFIRMING CARE, DRUG
PERFORMANCE OR GENDER EXPRESSION AS A BASIS TO DENY
SOMEONE EMPLOYMENT OR AFFORDABLE HOUSING WHEN THAT
CONDUCT IS LAWFUL IN CALIFORNIA .
>> THIS LEGISLATION STRENGTHENS DUE PROCESS PROTECTIONS FOR
APPLICANTS OR CLARIFIES TIMELINES FOR RECONSIDERATION
WHEN BACKGROUND CHECKS ARE INACCURATE OR IMPROPERLY USED
AND STRENGTHENS PENALTIES FOR VIOLATIONS.
>> AND IT SHOULD BE NOTED THAT WE ARE ALREADY SEEING MORE
TRANSGENDER PEOPLE LGBTQ PLUS PEOPLE AND WOMEN RELOCATE TO
CITIES LIKE SAN FRANCISCO BECAUSE OF ESCALATING ATTACKS
ON THEIR RIGHTS IN OTHER STATES.
A RECENT NATIONAL SURVEY ESTIMATED THAT MORE THAN
400,000 TRANSGENDER AMERICANS HAVE RELOCATED SINCE THE 2024
ELECTION DUE TO ANTI-TRANS LAWS AND POLICIES IN THEIR HOME
STATES. THUS THAT DISCRIMINATION SHOULD
NOT FOLLOW PEOPLE HERE. AT ITS CORE THIS LEGISLATION IS
ABOUT DIGNITY. IT IS ABOUT MAKING SURE THAT
PEOPLE ARE NOT PERMANENTLY PUNISHED FOR WHO THEY ARE, HOW
THEY IDENTIFY OR THE HEALTH CARE THAT GAVE OR SOUGHT OR THE
WAY THEY EXPRESS THEMSELVES. >> THIS LEGISLATION WAS
DEVELOPED IN CLOSE PARTNERSHIP WITH THE HUMAN RIGHTS
COMMISSION AND THE OFFICE OF TRANSGENDER INITIATIVES.
I WANT TO SPECIALLY THANK HONEY MAHOGANY FOR HER LEADERSHIP
AND ADVOCACY AND CONTINUED WORK FIGHTING FOR TRANSGENDER SAN
FRANCISCANS AND THE BROADER LGBTQ COMMUNITY DURING THIS
INCREDIBLY DIFFICULT MOMENT NATIONALLY.
ALSO WANT TO THINK MOLEY AND THE HUMAN RIGHTS COMMISSION
FOR THEIR COLLABORATION IN SHAPING THIS LEGISLATION
AND FOR THEIR CONTINUED COMMITMENT TO ADVANCING CIVIL
RIGHTS PROTECTIONS IN SAN FRANCISCO AS WELL AS OUR
DRAFTING ATTORNEY DEPUTY CITY ATTORNEY BRIANNA VOSS.
A VERY SPECIAL THANK YOU TO JUDE DIEBOLD FOR BEING THE
PRIMARY DRAFTER OF THIS LEGISLATION AND FOR THE
TREMENDOUS AMOUNT OF LEGAL AND POLICY WORK THAT THEY
DEDICATED LEADING UP TO TODAY. >> FOR SEVERAL YEARS.
>> THANK YOU AS WELL TO OUR COMMUNITY PARTNERS
AND ADVOCATES WHO HELPED INFORM THIS EFFORT INCLUDING PLANNED
PARENTHOOD LEGAL SERVICES FOR PRISONERS WITH CHILDREN, THE
TRANS LAW CENTER AND THE TRANSGENDER DISTRICT.
I ALSO WANT TO ACKNOWLEDGE THE DEPARTMENT ON THE STATUS OF
WOMEN AND ALL OF THE ORGANIZERS ,ADVOCATES, LEGAL EXPERTS
AND IMPACTED COMMUNITY MEMBERS WHO HAVE PUSHED THE CITY TO
MODERNIZE AND STRENGTHEN THE FAIR CHANCE ORDINANCE.
AND I WANT TO RECOGNIZE FORMER SUPERVISOR JANE KIM AND HER
OFFICE FOR THEIR LEADERSHIP IN HELPING ESTABLISH THE
ORIGINAL FAIR CHANCE ORDINANCE FRAMEWORK YEARS AGO.
THANK YOU TO MY COLLEAGUE SUPERVISOR DORSEY FOR YOUR
EARLY CO-SPONSORSHIP. AND I WANT TO THANK MY STAFF
WILL MACPHEE AND CASSANDRA MOTTER FROM MY OFFICE FOR THEIR
WORK ON THIS LEGISLATION. >> BECAUSE SAN FRANCISCO SHOULD
BE A PLACE WHERE PEOPLE CAN REBUILD THEIR LIVES WITH
DIGNITY AND OPPORTUNITY, NOT CONTINUE TO FACE DISCRIMINATION
BECAUSE OF EXTREMIST LAWS SOMEWHERE ELSE IN THE COUNTRY.
COLLEAGUES, I URGE YOUR SUPPORT NOT JUST FOR THIS LEGISLATION
BUT TO ENSURE THAT SAN FRANCISCO REMAINS A CITY WHERE
EVERYONE CAN LIVE OPENLY, SAFELY AND FREE FROM
DISCRIMINATION. >> SECOND, COLLEAGUES, I WANT
TO TURN TO HOUSING BECAUSE HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO UNFORTUNATELY
IT SEEMS WE OFTEN LIKE TO DO THINGS A LITTLE BIT DIFFERENT.
WE TOOK NORMAL BREAD AND MADE IT SOUR.
WE USED MILE LONG CABLES TO DRAG CARS OVER THE HILLS
AND OVER THE WEEKEND WE EVEN TURNED A NORMAL ROAD RACE
ACROSS THE CITY INTO A MOBILE COSTUME PARTY.
>> AND WE COULDN'T JUST IMPLEMENT UNFORTUNATELY THE
SEQUEL ACT AS IT WAS WRITTEN. >> NO, WE HAD TO PUT OUR OWN
SAN FRANCISCO FLOURISH ONTO IT. >> WHILE THE STATE SAYS
PROJECTS HAVE TO BE HAVE A HEARING FOR FINAL ENVIRONMENTAL
IMPACT REPORTS, SAN FRANCISCO SAID THAT DRAFT REPORT SHOULD
NEED A HEARING TO IN SAN FRANCISCO MAILINGS AND ONLINE
POSTINGS APPARENTLY ARE NOT ENOUGH NOTIFICATION.
THE CITY NEEDS TO RUN ADS IN THE NEWSPAPER EVERY TIME THE
PLANNING DEPARTMENT DETERMINES THAT A PROJECT NEEDS TO FILE AN
AIR. AND THE STATE SAYS THAT SHADOWS
AREN'T PART OF THE ENVIRONMENT .
BUT HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO, PROJECTS HAVE TO TREAT THE
SHADE A BUILDING CREATES JUST LIKE WE WOULD HAVE TO TREAT
TOXIC SOIL OR ANY OTHER SERIOUS ENVIRONMENTAL HAZARD.
AND THOSE WHO WISH TO SLOW OR STOP A PROJECT HAVE LEGITIMATE
GROUNDS FOR APPEAL IF THEY'RE NOT SUFFICIENTLY ADDRESSED.
>> THESE SPECIAL RULES AND PROCEDURES MAKE SAN
FRANCISCO STAND OUT IN ALL THE WRONG WAYS AND CONTRIBUTE TO A
BUILDING ENVIRONMENT THAT IS ALLERGIC TO NEW HOUSING.
>> THE SLASHING HOUSING APPEALS AND DELAYS EVERYWHERE ACT OR
SHADE ACT FOR SHORT BRINGS APPEAL TIMELINES, HEARING
FREQUENCY AND NOTIFICATION REQUIREMENTS IN LINE WITH STATE
LAW. >> PROJECTS CAN TAKE A FEW
STEPS OUT OF THEIR APPROVAL TIMELINES WHILE NOT SACRIFICING
THE BEDROCK PRINCIPLES THAT UNDERLINE SEQUA.
PERHAPS MOST IMPORTANTLY, IT ALSO TAKES SHADE OUT OF THE
ENVIRONMENTAL REVIEW PROCESS THUS REDUCING THE EFFICACY
AND THEREFORE LIKELIHOOD OF LENGTHY APPEALS.
>> SINCE 2017 SIX APPEALS INVOLVING SHADOW ANALYSIS HAVE
LED TO DELAYING OR STALLING 2195 USING ITS HOUSING CITYWIDE
OVER A DOZEN PROJECTS. WHEN PROJECTS HAVE TO NAVIGATE
THESE EXTRA LAYERS OF PROCESS AND ARE INVITED TO BE APPEALED
OVER HOW MUCH SHADE THEY CREATE, WE LOSE AS A CITY
HOUSING THAT CAN HELP TACKLE OUR AFFORDABILITY CRISIS GET
STOPPED OR FACES COSTLY DELAYS. >> WHAT'S MORE IS THAT WHEN WE
CONTRIBUTE TO MAKING SAN FRANCISCO A HARDER CITY TO
BUILD IN, WE'RE PUSHING DEVELOPMENT ONTO THE UNSPOILED
CALIFORNIA GREEN SPACE THAT CEQA WAS DESIGNED TO PROTECT
OUR OWN HOUSING ELEMENT AND GUIDANCE FROM THE
CALIFORNIA DEPARTMENT OF HOUSING AND COMMUNITY
DEVELOPMENT AGREE IT'S TIME TO PEEL BACK THE LAYERS OF LOCAL
PROCESS IN OUR LOCAL IMPLEMENTATION OF SEQUA.
>> I WANT TO THANK LISA GIBSON AND THE REST OF THE
ENVIRONMENTAL PLANNING TEAM AND LISA GLUCKSTEIN FROM THE
GOVERNMENT AFFAIRS AT THE PLANNING DEPARTMENT AS WELL AS
OUR DRAFTING ATTORNEY DEPUTY CITY ATTORNEY ANDREA RUIZ
ESQUEDA. I ALSO WANT TO THANK RENO
COOPER FOR MY OFFICE FOR HIS WORK ON THIS AND SUPERVISORS
DORSEY AND SADR FOR THEIR EARLY CO-SPONSORSHIP.
COLLEAGUES I ASK FOR YOUR SUPPORT AND HELPING SAN
FRANCISCO GET OVER THE FEAR OF ITS OWN SHADOW AND PROCESS.
>> THE REST I SUBMIT. THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD SUPERVISOR OF RANDLEMAN.
THANK YOU MADAM CLERK AND COLLEAGUES TODAY ALONG WITH
CO-SPONSORS. >> WELL ACTUALLY BEFORE I DO
THAT I WOULD LIKE TO BE ADDED IF SUPERVISOR DORSEY DOES NOT
MIND TO HIS IN MEMORIAM FOR JACK DAVIS BUT ALSO TODAY ALONG
WITH CO-SPONSORS BELAL MAHMOOD AND MYRNA MELGAR I AM
INTRODUCING A CHARTER AMENDMENT TO MAKE APPROXIMATELY 110
DISCRETE, TECHNICAL AND PRACTICAL REFORMS TO OUR
CITY CHARTER. SOME OF THESE CHANGES CAME
DIRECTLY FROM THE CITY DEPARTMENTS WHICH AFTER ALL ARE
MADE UP OF THE PEOPLE WHO DO THE WORK OF DELIVERING FOR OUR
PUBLIC EVERY DAY AND KNOW BETTER THAN ANYONE WHERE THE
CHARTER IS CREATING FRICTION AND WHERE IT CAN BE CHANGED FOR
BETTER OPERATIONS. SOME RECOMMENDATIONS CAME FROM
THE PROPOSITION E COMMISSION STREAMLINING TASK FORCE WHICH
AS YOU KNOW SPENT A LOT OF TIME AND CONCENTRATED EFFORT
EVALUATING THE CITY'S BOARDS AND COMMISSIONS AND MAKING
RECOMMENDATIONS ABOUT WHICH OF THEM BELONG IN THE CHARTER,
WHICH BELONG IN THE ADMINISTRATIVE CODE AND WHICH
SHOULD BE ELIMINATED ALTOGETHER .
>> WE DID NOT ACCEPT ALL OF THEIR RECOMMENDATIONS BUT WE
ARE GRATEFUL FOR THEIR WORK. >> I WANT TO THANK SUPERVISORS
MAHMOOD AND CHEN FOR THEIR PARTICIPATION IN THE CHARTER
REFORM WORKING GROUP WHICH BROUGHT TOGETHER STAKEHOLDERS
FROM ACROSS THE CITY TO CONSIDER A NUMBER OF CHALLENGES
IN OUR CHARTER AND POSSIBLE RESPONSES TO THOSE CHALLENGES.
AND THAT WORK HAS ALSO INFORMED THE MEASURE WE'RE INTRODUCING
TODAY. I WANT TO RECOGNIZE SUPERVISOR
MAHMUD IN PARTICULAR FOR HIS PARTNERSHIP AND THINKING
THROUGH SOME OF THE POSSIBILITIES FOR DEPARTMENTAL
REFORM. WE'VE EVALUATED THROUGH THIS
PROCESS AND I WANT TO THANK SUPERVISOR MELGAR IN PARTICULAR
FOR HER LEADERSHIP AROUND A SET OF CHANGES FOCUSED ON HOW
DEPARTMENTS AND COMMISSIONS SERVING CHILDREN AND YOUTH CAN
DO SO BETTER. >> THE MEASURE IS BETTER FOR
THEIR WORK AND THEIR TEAMS WORK ON IT.
>> THE CHANGES WE ARE PROPOSING FALL INTO THREE BROADER BROAD
CATEGORIES. THE FIRST I WOULD SAY IS
MODERNIZATION AND CLEANUP. THESE AMENDMENTS ARE TRULY
CLEAN UP UPDATING THE CHARTER TO REFLECT CURRENT CONDITIONS
INCORRECT REFERENCES AND MANY OUT-OF-DATE PROVISIONS.
HERE'S AN EXAMPLE. THE CHARTER CURRENTLY INCLUDES
A SECTION THAT MANDATES THAT THERE BE A BOOKBINDER POSITION
IN THE LAW LIBRARY. THAT DOES NOT MAKE SENSE
IN 2026 AND IT ALTHOUGH IT DOES MAKE SENSE PERHAPS TO HAVE
LANGUAGE FOR SOMETHING MORE EVERGREEN LIKE A TECHNICAL
SERVICES MANAGER. SO THAT'S WHAT WE'VE DONE.
A SECOND CATEGORY OF CHANGES ADDRESSES DEPARTMENT SPECIFIC
PAIN POINTS. AND AS I SAID, THESE ARE BASED
ON FEEDBACK FROM DEPARTMENTS ON THEIR SPECIFIC SECTIONS IN THE
CHARTER. WE HAVE WORKED WITH THEM TO
DETERMINE WHERE WE COULD MAKE SOME OPERATIONAL IMPROVEMENTS
REQUESTED THAT THEY'D REQUESTED TO BETTER ENABLE SERVICE
DELIVERY AND THAT COULD IN ONE EXAMPLE LOOKS LIKE UPDATING
MUNI'S CHARTER MANDATED SERVICE STANDARDS TO REFLECT HOW MODERN
TRANSIT AGENCIES MEASURE PERFORMANCE.
THE CURRENT ON TIME PERFORMANCE METRIC IN THE CHARTER HAS BEEN
INCREASINGLY RECOGNIZED AS AN INCOMPLETE MEASURE OF WRITER
EXPERIENCE. THE AMENDMENT INCLUDED IN THIS
CHARTER REFORM MEASURE ALLOWS MTA TO ADOPT OTHER STANDARDS
SUCH AS WEIGHT ASSESSMENTS WHICH MEASURE HOW LONG RIDERS
WAIT BETWEEN VEHICLES PROVIDING A MORE ACCURATE PICTURE OF
SERVICE QUALITY. >> THIRD AND FINALLY WE DID
DRAW FROM THE WORK OF THE COMMISSION'S STREAMLINING TASK
FORCE WHICH AS I SAID SPENT MONTHS CONDUCTING A
COMPREHENSIVE EVALUATION OF THE STRUCTURE PERFORMANCE
AND EFFECTIVENESS OF THE CITY'S BOARD BOARDS AND COMMISSIONS.
AND IN THIS CATEGORY AS EXAMPLES ARE THE ELIMINATION OF
THE STREETS AND SANITATION COMMISSION, THE PUBLIC WORKS
COMMISSION. WE'RE ALSO PROPOSING MOVING
BODIES LIKE THE PUBLIC UTILITIES COMMISSION'S CITIZEN
ADVISORY COMMITTEE AND THE PARKS AND RECREATION OPEN SPACE
ADVISORY COMMITTEE OUT OF THE CHARTER AND INTO THE
ADMINISTRATIVE CODE WHERE THEY COULD BE UPDATED AND CHANGED BY
THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS THROUGH THE LEGISLATIVE PROCESS
IN THE FUTURE INSTEAD OF HAVING TO GO BACK TO THE VOTERS EVERY
TIME YOU WANT TO MAKE A CHANGE EVEN A SMALL CHANGE TO ANY OF
THESE BODIES MANY OPERATIONAL RULES, PROCEDURES
AND COMMISSIONS ARE EMBEDDED IN THE CHARTER NOT BECAUSE THEY
HAVE TO BE THERE BUT BECAUSE THAT'S WHERE THEY ENDED UP AS A
RELIC OF PREVIOUS VOTER APPROVED CHARTER AMENDMENTS.
AND I THINK IT IS WORTH REMEMBERING THAT THE
ADMINISTRATIVE CODE EXISTS FOR A REASON AND PROVISIONS THAT
LIVE THERE CAN BE UPDATED TO THE NORMAL LEGISLATIVE PROCESS
AS CONDITIONS CHANGE AND AS PRIORITIES EVOLVE THAT
FLEXIBILITY IS NOT POSSIBLE WHEN THESE PROCEDURES ARE
LOCKED INTO THE CHARTER. SO WHERE WE CAN WHERE THERE'S
CONSENSUS THAT IT MAY MAKE SENSE I DO STRONGLY SUPPORT
MOVING THEM OUT OF THE CHARTER AND BELIEVE THAT THAT DOES NOT
YOU KNOW, CERTAINLY DOES NOT ELIMINATE THEM BUT DOES ENABLE
ELECTED OFFICIALS TO ADAPT ADAPT THEM OVER TIME.
>> THERE ARE LOTS OF PEOPLE TO THANK FOR THE CONTRIBUTIONS
THEY'VE MADE TO THE CHARTER MEASURE I'M INTRODUCING TODAY.
THAT INCLUDES THE MEMBERS OF THE CHARTER REFORM WORKING
GROUP. THE MEMBERS OF THE COMMISSION,
THE STREAMLINING TASK FORCE CHAIR AT HARRINGTON AND MEMBER
SOPHIE HAYWARD ANDREA BRUCE NATASHA MITCHELL SOPHIA KETTLER
AND GENE FRAZIER OF THE EXCELLENT CITY STAFF WHO
SUPPORTED THESE EFFORTS AND OUR WORK OVER THE PAST YEAR
AND THAT INCLUDES OF COURSE OUR COMPTROLLER GREG WAGNER.
HENRY O'CONNELL, JOANNA BELL JANICE LEVY IN HIS OFFICE.
OUR CITY ADMINISTRATOR CARMEN CHIU AND SOPHIE HAYWARD
AND RACHEL ALONZO IN HER OFFICE .
>> I WANT TO THANK THE MAYOR'S TEAM THAT'S ESPECIALLY ALICIA
JEAN-BAPTISTE AND AMIR BHARDWAJ FOR THEIR PARTNERSHIP AND THEN
WE HAVE GIVEN OUR ATTORNEYS A TON OF WORK.
NOT JUST BRAD RUSSI BUT IN PARTICULAR ANDREA BROSS,
SARAH CROWLEY, HEATHER GOODMAN AND JOHN GOVERNOR HAS BEEN
THERE THROUGHOUT OFFERING OUR WISE COUNSEL AND HELP.
THEY HAVE BEEN VERY PATIENT WITH US THROUGH A PROCESS THAT
I KNOW HAS AT TIMES BEEN FRUSTRATING.
AND I DO WANT TO THANK THE MANY STAKEHOLDERS WHO'VE CARED
ENOUGH OVER THIS LAST YEAR TO MAKE THEMSELVES HEARD OFTEN
LOUDLY BUT AND PERSISTENTLY WE'VE HEARD THEM AND I THINK
THIS MEASURE REFLECTS A LOT OF THAT FEEDBACK.
FINALLY, I WANT TO THANK MELANIE MATHESON, FORMERLY OF
MY OFFICE OF SCULLY, CURRENTLY OF MY OFFICE FOR ALL OF THEIR
WORK ON THIS AS WELL. >> SECONDLY, COLLEAGUES, I'M
ASKING THAT WE ADJOURN TODAY'S MEETING IN MEMORY OF RITA
SEMMEL LONG TIME CIVIC LEADER DESCRIBE THE SAN FRANCISCO
INTERFAITH COUNCIL AS THE MATRIARCH OF INTERFAITH
RELATIONSHIPS WHO DIED ON MAY 13TH, 2026 AT THE AGE OF 104.
>> RITA WAS BORN NOVEMBER 15TH, 1921 INTO A SECULAR JEWISH
FAMILY IN NEW YORK CITY. SHE ATTENDED BARNARD COLLEGE
MAJORING IN POLITICAL SCIENCE IN 1941 FOLLOWING THE OUTBREAK
OF WORLD WAR TWO. SHE AND HER HUSBAND MAXIMO
RELOCATED TO A MILITARY BASE IN MISSISSIPPI WHERE HER
HUSBAND WAS SERVING AS AN ARMY OFFICER.
WHILE LIVING IN MISSISSIPPI, RITA WITNESSED THE EVILS OF
SEGREGATION FIRSTHAND EXPERIENCES THAT HELPED INSPIRE
HER LIFELONG PURSUIT OF SOCIAL JUSTICE.
BUT IT WAS ALSO DURING THIS TIME THAT RITA RECALLED
EXPERIENCING ONE OF HER EARLIEST MOMENTS OF INTERFAITH
CONNECTION WHILE SEARCHING FOR HOUSING IN MISSISSIPPI.
SHE MET WITH A METHODIST MINISTER WHO HAD A ROOM
AVAILABLE TO THEM TO RENT. WHEN SHE CAUTIOUSLY TOLD HIM
THAT SHE AND HER HUSBAND WERE JEWISH, HE REPLIED I'M SO GLAD
I SEE ENOUGH METHODISTS ON SUNDAY.
WHEN HER HUSBAND WENT OVERSEAS TO FIGHT IN THE WAR, RITA
LANDED A JOB AT THE SAN FRANCISCO CHRONICLE AS WHAT WAS
THEN CALLED A COPY BOY. >> SHE LATER BECAME ASSOCIATE
EDITOR FOR THE JEWISH COMMUNITY BULLETIN AND BEGAN DOING PUBLIC
RELATIONS WORK FOR THE SAN FRANCISCO BASED JEWISH
COMMUNITY FEDERATION. AFTER TAKING TIME OFF TO CARE
FOR HER TWO YOUNG DAUGHTERS JANE AND ELIZABETH, RITA DOVE
RIGHT BACK INTO HER WORK. IN 1964 SHE HELPED ORGANIZE THE
SAN FRANCISCO CONFERENCE ON RELIGION AND RACE.
OUT OF THAT CONFERENCE CAME A NEW INTERFAITH TASK FORCE THE
SAN FRANCISCO COUNCIL ON RELIGION AND RACE AND RITA RITA
REPRESENTED THE JEWISH COMMUNITY ON THE COUNCIL.
THAT SAME YEAR SHE BECAME ASSOCIATE DIRECTOR OF THE
JEWISH COMMUNITY RELATIONS COUNCIL, WHICH REPRESENTS
SYNAGOGUES, JEWISH ORGANIZATIONS AND JEWISH
INDIVIDUALS AND FAMILIES ACROSS THE BAY AREA COMBATING
ANTI-SEMITISM AND ADVOCATING ON ISSUES OF CONCERN TO THE JEWISH
COMMUNITY. IN 1987 SHE BECAME THE
EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR OF JCR AND SHE SERVED IN THAT ROLE FOR
TWO YEARS. AFTER THE 1989 LOMA PRIETA
EARTHQUAKE, THE RELIEF AGENCY CHURCH WORLD SERVICE FORMED AN
INTERFAITH COMMITTEE TO AID THOSE AFFECTED.
SHE WAS A MEMBER OF THAT COMMITTEE AND SAW THE POTENTIAL
IN A PERMANENT INTERFAITH ORGANIZATION THAT COULD ADDRESS
ISSUES OF SHARED CONCERN AND EXPAND ITS SCOPE.
SO SHE HELPED FOUND THE SAN FRANCISCO INTERFAITH COUNCIL
AND THE WORK OF THE INTERFAITH COUNCIL ESPECIALLY ITS
EXPANSIVE NETWORK OF HOMELESS SHELTERS WOULD BECOME ONE OF
HER PROUDEST ACHIEVEMENTS. AMONG HER MANY OTHER
ACCOMPLISHMENTS, RITA CHAIRED THE GLOBAL COUNCIL FOR THE
UNITED RELIGIONS INITIATIVE AND SERVED ON THE BOARDS OF
CATHOLIC CHARITIES FAMILY SERVICES AMERICA FRIENDS OF THE
SAN FRANCISCO HUMAN RIGHTS COMMISSION.
JEWISH FAMILY CHILDREN'S SERVICES.
SAN FRANCISCO CHILDREN'S RIGHTS COALITION, THE INTERFAITH
CENTER AT THE PRESIDIO AND THE SAN FRANCISCO HOMELESSNESS
BOARD. IN 1995 SHE SERVED AS A
DELEGATE TO THE FOURTH U.N. WORLD CONFERENCE ON WOMEN
IN CHINA. RITA EARNED WELL-DESERVED
RECOGNITION FOR HER WORK, INCLUDING THE JUDITH CHAPMAN
AWARD FROM THE SAN FRANCISCO BASED JEWISH COMMUNITY
FEDERATION. THE WOMEN'S ALLIANCE WON A
WOMAN OF THE YEAR AWARD FROM THE CALIFORNIA STATE ASSEMBLY.
AND THE ROSA PARKS AWARD FOR WOMEN IN COMMUNITY SERVICE.
IN 2008 THE ISLAMIC SOCIETY OF SAN FRANCISCO AND UNITED
MUSLIMS OF AMERICA HONORED RITA AS AN INTERFAITH PIONEER.
RITA TOLD GAY WEEKLY THE SUCCESSOR TO THE JEWISH
BULLETIN SHE ONCE EDITED THAT SHE BELIEVED THERE'S NO SUCH
THING AS RETIREMENT. IN 2009 A MASS SHOOTING
IN TEXAS BY A MUSLIM BY A MUSLIM-AMERICAN SPARKED
WIDESPREAD BACKLASH. IT WIDESPREAD FEAR OF BACKLASH
AGAINST MUSLIM COMMUNITIES. THE NEXT DAY, RITA, NEARLY 90
YEARS OLD, DROVE OUT TO A BAY AREA UNITED MUSLIMS OF AMERICA
MEETING IN FREMONT AND READ ALOUD A STATEMENT OF SUPPORT
FOR THE MUSLIM COMMUNITY SIGNED BY THE NORTHERN CALIFORNIA
BOARD OF RABBIS AND OTHER RELIGIOUS LEADERS.
RITA'S DEATH IS A LOSS FOR THE WORLD.
SHE WAS TRULY AN EXTRAORDINARY WOMAN REST IN PEACE AND POWER
RITA SAM AND THEIR MEMORY BE A BLESSING AND THE REST I SUBMIT
THANK YOU, MR. PRESIDENT. NEXT TO SUPERVISOR MELGAR.
THANK YOU. AND I'D LIKE TO BE ADDED TO
RITA, SOME MUSLIM. >> I AM ALSO PLEASED.
THANK YOU. COLLEAGUES, WE ARE IN THE
MIDDLE OF MAY WHICH IS AFFORDABLE HOUSING MONTH SO I
AM EXCITED TO INTRODUCE TODAY A CHARTER AMENDMENT ALONG WITH
SUPERVISORS WALTON SAUDER, CHERYL DORSEY AND WONG TO
EXTEND AND TO RENEW THE HOUSING TRUST FUND.
>> THE AFFORDABLE HOUSING TRUST FUND WAS ORIGINALLY PASSED
IN 2012 TO SUPPORT CREATING ACQUIRING PRESERVE
AND REHABILITATING HOUSING, AFFORDABLE HOUSING
AND PROMOTING AFFORDABLE HOMEOWNERSHIP PROGRAMS.
THE LAST SEVERAL YEARS HAVE BEEN DIFFICULT FOR EVERYONE
FROM THE PANDEMIC TO THE AILING ECONOMY TO THE SLASHING OF
FEDERAL AND STATE FUNDS FOR HOUSING.
>> AND THE CONSEQUENCES ARE DIRE.
AT THE SAME TIME AS WE'RE SEEING FUNDS DRY OUT, RENTS ARE
ONLY RISING IN EVICTIONS RIGHT NOW AND ARE AT AN ALL TIME
HIGH. WE ARE IN AN AFFORDABLE HOUSING
CRISIS AND WE KNOW THAT WILL ONLY GET WORSE AS THERE IS A
KNOWN CLIFF. BY 2029 THERE WILL BE NO
FUNDING LEFT TO FULFILL ANY OF THE PRODUCTION OF UNITS IN THE
PIPELINE RIGHT NOW. WE ALL KNOW HOW IMPORTANT IT IS
FOR SOMEONE TO HAVE A DRY PLACE TO PLAY THEIR HEAD DOWN AT
NIGHT. >> WE KNOW THAT NOTHING ELSE
WORKS IF PEOPLE HAVE NO HOUSING .
WE HAVE ALWAYS NEEDED A LIFELINE A DEDICATED AND STABLE
SOURCE OF FUNDING FOR AFFORDABLE HOUSING THAT IS NOT
DEPENDENT ON THE WHIMS OF THE MARKET THAT IS STABLE, THAT
DOESN'T FLUCTUATE. IT IS ALSO A STARK REALITY THAT
THE INCLUSIONARY HOUSING TECHNICAL ADVISORY COMMITTEE
UNANIMOUSLY SUPPORTED A RECOMMENDATION TO UPDATE THE
INCLUSIONARY RATES BECAUSE MARKET RATE HOUSING IS ALSO AT
A STANDSTILL. >> NO HOUSING IS BEING PRODUCED
AND NO FEES ARE BEING PAID. THEY HAVE ALSO RECOMMENDED THE
NEED FOR A SEPARATE SOURCE OF FUNDING FOR AFFORDABLE HOUSING.
I'M CO-SPONSORING THE INTRODUCTION OF THE MAYOR'S
ORDINANCE TODAY TO SUPPORT THOSE RECOMMENDATIONS.
TODAY WE ARE ENERGIZED MORE THAN EVER TO MEET THE MOMENT.
OVER THE COURSE OF THE LAST FEW MONTHS WE CONVERGED A DIVERSE
COALITION OF AFFORDABLE HOUSING ORGANIZATIONS, NONPROFIT
ORGANIZATIONS, HOUSING FINANCE EXPERTS, LABOR ALONG WITH THE
MAYOR'S OFFICE TO CRAFT THIS CHARTER AMENDMENT THAT WILL
GRADUALLY EXPAND THE HOUSING TRUST FUND OVER THE COURSE OF
THE TIME TO REACH 125 MILLION ANNUALLY.
THERE WILL ALSO BE THE OPPORTUNITY TO ISSUE REVENUE
BONDS TO MAXIMIZE THESE FUNDS TO UNLOCK THOUSANDS OF NEW
AFFORDABLE HOUSING UNITS, PRESERVE EXISTING SITES
AND SUPPORT PROGRAMS FOR THE FIRST TIME FOR FIRST TIME
HOMEBUYERS. WE ALSO INCLUDED NEW POSSIBLE
USES OF THIS FUND FOR SUPPORTING LIMITED EQUITY
CO-OPS AND SOCIAL HOUSING. WE DESIGNED THIS CHARTER
AMENDMENT SO THAT THE HOUSING TRUST FUND GROWS BY ALLOCATING
A PORTION OF FUTURE PROPERTY TAX GROWTH EVERY YEAR.
LAST YEAR WE JUST RESOUND A LOT OF THE WEST SIDE AND NORTH OF
THE CITY. THIS IS A VALUE CAPTURED THAT
INVESTS BACK INTO MUCH NEEDED AFFORDABLE HOUSING.
WE ALSO MADE SURE THAT WE ARE EXPANDING THE HOUSING TRUST
FUND INTO A FISCALLY RESPONSIBLE WAY.
THE GRADUAL GROWTH OF THE FUND WILL NOT START UNTIL 2029
AND WE INCLUDED FISCAL SAFEGUARDS TO FREEZE THE GROWTH
OF THE FUND DURING A BUDGET DEFICIT AND TO DECREASE THE
BASELINE FUNDING DURING A RECESSION.
>> I WANT TO THANK ALONG WITH THE CO-SPONSORS MAYOR LURIE FOR
HIS SUPPORT AND HIS TEAM NED SEGAL, ALI BONDI, BEN WHITE,
LEILA PENSKE AND JACOB LIFF DIRECTOR DAN ADAMS, COMPTROLLER
GREG WAGNER AND HIS TEAM AT THE CONTROLLERS OFFICE FOR THE LATE
NIGHTS AND NUMBER CRUNCHING. ASSESSOR RECORDER JOAQUIN TOYS
AND HIS TEAM VICTORIA WONG AND THE CITY ATTORNEY'S TEAM.
AND OF COURSE ALL OF OUR COMMUNITY PARTNERS.
THE COUNCIL OF COMMUNITY HOUSING ORGANIZATIONS QUENTIN
MACKEY, CAROLYN FANG, THE COMMUNITY LAND TRUST SAKAE
BAILEY KYLE SMILEY NONPROFIT HOUSING ASSOCIATION NORTHERN
CALIFORNIA ESPECIALLY THE INCOMPARABLE BILL BARNES
HOUSING ACCELERATOR FUND REBECCA FOSTER AND KATE
HARTLEY. THE MISSION ECONOMIC
DEVELOPMENT AGENCY CHINATOWN COMMUNITY DEVELOPMENT CENTER
MALCOLM YOUNG ESPECIALLY AND SO MANY OTHERS.
I LOOK FORWARD TO FURTHER DISCUSSION ON GETTING YOUR
SUPPORT TO SEND THIS TO THE VOTERS FOR APPROVAL
IN NOVEMBER. >> TODAY I'M ALSO PROUD TO
INTRODUCE A RESOLUTION COMMEMORATING THE SAN FRANCISCO
YOUTH COMMISSION FOR ITS 30 YEARS OF SERVICE TO THE YOUTH
OF THE CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN FRANCISCO.
30 YEARS AGO THE VOTERS OF SAN FRANCISCO APPROVED A CHARTER
AMENDMENT THAT ESTABLISHED A COMMISSION TO REPORT TO ADVISE
THE MAYOR AND THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS ON ISSUES THAT
PRIMARILY AFFECTED CHILDREN AND YOUTH.
AND SINCE THEN HUNDREDS OF YOUTH COMMISSIONERS HAVE
DEDICATED THEIR TIME PROVIDED IMPORTANT FEEDBACK ON CITY
ISSUES. THE YOUTH COMMISSION HAS
ADVOCATED FOR THE EXPANSION OF FUNDING AND PROGRAMING FOR
SUPPOSED WELLNESS CENTER ACROSS THE CITY LED ON THE CREATION OF
A YOUTH LIFELINE PAST AND CURRENT FREE MUNI FOR ALL
YOUTH PROGRAMS AND THEY HAVE COLLABORATED WITH COMMUNITY
ORGANIZATIONS ACROSS SAN FRANCISCO TO ENSURE COMMUNITY
REPRESENTATION IN CITY HALL AND TO ALIGN COLLECTIVE YOUTH
ADVOCACY EFFORTS. ALSO IT HAS PROVIDED A
WONDERFUL LEADERSHIP OPPORTUNITY FOR GENERATIONS OF
YOUTH WHO HAVE GONE ON TO DO BIGGER AND BETTER THINGS
AND BEEN LEADERS IN OUR COMMUNITY.
THEY TAKE THEIR ROLE AS ALLIES SERIOUSLY AND NEVER TURN AWAY
THE OPPORTUNITY TO SUPPORT YOUTH LEADERSHIP AND ALSO LEND
SUPPORT TO THE CREATION OF LOCAL DISTRICT YOUTH COUNCILS
LIKE OUR DISTRICT SEVEN YOUTH COUNCIL.
I WANT TO ACKNOWLEDGE CURRENT YOUTH COMMISSION INTERIM
DIRECTOR JOY ZINE AND COMMUNITY PARTNERSHIP SPECIALIST JOSHUA
OCHOA. >> I SEE THEM BACK THERE.
FOR THEIR TIRELESS DEDICATION IN MENTORING AND NURTURING THE
PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT OF OUR YOUTH COMMISSIONERS.
AND I ALSO WANT TO THANK MY EARLY CO-SPONSOR AND THIS
RESOLUTION SUPERVISORS DORSEY CHEN, WALTON MAHMOOD AND SADR.
CONGRATULATIONS YOU COMMISSION. THE REST I SUBMIT.
THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR MELGAR.
SUPERVISOR SAUTER SUBMIT. >> THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR CHERYL COLLEAGUES. >> TODAY THERE HAS BEEN
SIGNIFICANT HOUSING LEGISLATION INTRODUCED THIS MEETING
ESPECIALLY FROM SUPERVISOR MELGAR AND THE MAYORAL
ADMINISTRATION. >> I'M VERY PROUD TO BE AN
EARLY CO-SPONSOR OF THESE SIGNIFICANT REFORMS TO ADDRESS
OUR HOUSING CRISIS BY LOWERING CONSTRUCTION COSTS AND TRULY
DELIVERING FUNDING FOR NEEDED AFFORDABLE HOUSING.
>> SAN FRANCISCANS CONTINUE TO BE CLEAR THE COST OF LIVING IS
TOO HIGH FOR OUR WORKING CLASS OUR YOUNG FAMILIES, OUR SENIORS
AND OUR YOUTH TO THRIVE HERE TODAY.
THE COST OF A HOME IS 12.4 TIMES THE MEDIAN INCOME HERE
IN SAN FRANCISCO. THAT IS STUPIDLY AND INSANELY
AND RIDICULOUSLY OUT OF WHACK. AND WHILE AS A BOARD WE'VE
TAKEN BIG STRIDES TO EXPAND HOUSING OPPORTUNITIES CITYWIDE,
IT'S CLEAR THAT MORE NEEDS TO BE DONE TO GET SHOVELS IN THE
GROUND AND THAT WE NEED TO BE MORE AMBITIOUS IN ORDER TO
EFFECTIVELY BUILD MORE HOMES. >> THAT'S WHY I'M ALSO
INTRODUCING LEGISLATION THAT WILL FURTHER BRING DOWN CITY
RELATED COSTS ON HOUSING CONSTRUCTION SPECIFICALLY FOR
HOUSING PROJECTS ON CORNER LOTS THAT USE THE FAMILIES OWNING
PLAN PASSED BY THE BOARD LAST DECEMBER.
THIS BOARD PASSED THE FAMILY ZONING PLAN BECAUSE WE NEEDED A
ROADMAP FOR THE FUTURE A FUTURE OF HOUSING THAT IS BUILT THE
SAN FRANCISCO WAY. BUT ZONING ALONE IS NOT THE
SOLUTION. >> IF WE GOING TO BUILD ANY
TYPE OF HOUSING MARKET RATE OR BELOW MARKET RATE HOUSING, WE
NEED TO DO ALL THAT WE CAN TO BRING DOWN THE CONSTRUCTION
COST PER UNIT, MAKING HOUSING PRODUCTION FINANCIALLY FEASIBLE
TO GET DONE. IF WE DO NOT WE RISK ALL OF OUR
WORK BEING A MERE PAPER EXERCISE.
I'M COMMITTED TO ENSURING WE ARE BEING AMBITIOUS TO MEET OUR
HOUSING GOALS BECAUSE WHEN WE BUILD MORE HOUSING WE MAKE IT
EASIER FOR ALL SAN FRANCISCANS TO STAY HERE, GROW HERE, AGE
HERE AND THRIVE HERE. THIS LEGISLATION WILL TAKE US
ANOTHER STEP FORWARD TOWARD BUILDING THIS NEEDED HOUSING
AND I HOPE TO EARN YOUR SUPPORT AS THIS ORDINANCE WORKS AWAY
THROUGH THE LEGISLATIVE PROCESS.
THANK YOU COLLEAGUES AND THE REST OF SUBMIT.
>> THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR SHERYL SUPERVISOR
WONG. SUPERVISOR WALTON.
>> THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK. COLLEAGUES TODAY I HAVE
IN MEMORIAM FOR MAGNUS MARK MATO A SAN FRANCISCO NATIVE,
DEDICATED PUBLIC SERVANT AND A MAN WHO GAVE MORE THAN THREE
DECADES OF HIS LIFE TO THE YOUNG PEOPLE OF THIS CITY.
>> MARK WAS BORN ON DECEMBER 13TH, 1953 RIGHT HERE IN SAN
FRANCISCO. HE PASSED AWAY ON MAY 30TH,
2026 AT THE AGE OF 72. IN JANUARY 1977, MARK WALKED
THROUGH THE DOORS OF THE SAN FRANCISCO JUVENILE PROBATION
DEPARTMENT AS A COUNSELOR AND FROM THAT FIRST DAY HE WAS
EXACTLY WHERE HE WAS MEANT TO BE.
OVER THE YEARS HE GREW INTO EVERY ROLE HE TOOK ON.
HE SERVED AS A BOY'S RANCH COUNSELOR, THEN AS A DEPUTY
PROBATION OFFICER, A SENIOR DEPUTY PROBATION OFFICER
AND FINALLY BEGINNING IN MAY 1998 AS A SUPERVISING PROBATION
OFFICER. HE RETIRED ON DECEMBER 31ST,
2011 AFTER MORE THAN 34 YEARS OF SERVICE.
BUT THE TITLES DON'T TELL THE REAL STORY WITH SEVEN MARK
APART WAS HE DID BEYOND THE JOB DESCRIPTION.
HE INVESTED IN PEOPLE YOUTH FAMILIES, INTERNS, COLLEAGUES
NOT JUST DURING BUSINESS HOURS BUT ON HIS OWN TIME BECAUSE
THAT'S WHO HE WAS. HE BELIEVED IN HIS YOUTH BEFORE
THEY WOULD BELIEVE IN THEMSELVES AND FOR COUNTLESS
YOUNG SAN FRANCISCANS THAT BELIEVE CHANGED EVERYTHING.
MARTIN LEAVES BEHIND A LEGACY THAT WILL RIPPLE THROUGH
GENERATIONS IN THE LIVES HE TOUCHED, THE CAREERS HE SHAPED
AND THE COMMUNITY HE SERVED WITH SUCH QUIET, STEADY
DEDICATION. HE IS SURVIVED BY HIS PARTNER
LETICIA, HIS BROTHER JOHN, HIS SISTERS MARY BARBARA AND LYNN
AND BY MANY BELOVED NIECES AND NEPHEWS.
>> THE REST I SUBMIT. THANK YOU SUPERVISOR WALTON.
>> SUPERVISOR WANG. COLLEAGUES, SAN FRANCISCO HAS
BANNED THE PRIVATE DISCHARGE OF FIREWORKS SINCE 1938.
FOR NEARLY 90 YEARS THAT BAN HAS CARRIED NO ENFORCEMENT
MECHANISM. SECTION 1290 OF THE POLICE CODE
TELLS PEOPLE THEY CANNOT DISCHARGE FIREWORKS.
THEN SAYS NOTHING ABOUT WHAT HAPPENS IF THEY DO.
AN ORDINANCE THAT I'M WORKING ON CHANGES THAT RIGHT NOW WHEN
AN OFFICER RESPONDS TO FIREWORKS CALL THERE'S NO
CITATION TO RIGHT. STATE LAW COVERS VERY DANGEROUS
FIREWORKS BUT DOES NOT TOUCH LESSER BUT STILL DANGEROUS
FIREWORKS WHICH ARE ILLEGAL IN SAN FRANCISCO.
THE FIRE DEPARTMENT CAN ISSUE ADMINISTRATIVE VIOLATIONS BUT
THAT TOOL IS NOT AVAILABLE TO POLICE OFFICERS ON PATROL.
THAT'S THAT'S WHY I'VE WORKED WITH CPD TO DRAFT THIS
PROPOSAL. THE PENALTIES HERE ARE
PROPORTIONATE. THE FIRST OFFENSE CARRIES A
FINE COMPARABLE TO A PARKING TICKET.
THE SECOND OFFENSE ESCALATES TO MISDEMEANOR CAPS WELL BELOW
WHAT STATE LAW ALREADY IMPOSES FOR MORE DANGEROUS FIREWORKS.
TENS OF THOUSANDS OF SAN FRANCISCO HOUSEHOLDS HAVE A PET
AFFECTED BY FIREWORKS. THOUSANDS OF RESIDENTS HAVE
AUTISM. >> DEMENTIA AND PTSD ARE
IMPACTED EVERY YEAR. THE 2023 2024 CIVIL GRAND JURY
INVESTIGATED THIS ISSUE AND SAID IT PLAINLY SAN
FRANCISCO IS NOT A PLACE WHERE ANYONE SHOULD BE ABLE TO
DISCHARGE FIREWORKS WITHOUT CONSEQUENCE.
THEY RECOMMENDED ADDITIONAL LEGAL TOOLS FOR LAW ENFORCEMENT
AND BETTER TRACKING OF CITATIONS AND FINES.
>> THIS ORDINANCE DELIVERS BOTH.
I ASK FOR YOUR SUPPORT. >> SECONDLY, I'M INTRODUCING
TWO ORDINANCES TO REPEAL THREE PROVISIONS FROM SAN FRANCISCO'S
MUNICIPAL CODE THAT HAVE OUTLIVED ANY PURPOSE THEY ONCE
SERVED. THE FIRST ORDINANCE AMENDS
HEALTH CODE TO REPEAL TWO PROVISIONS.
THE FIRST PROHIBITS TRANSPORTING BREAD CAKES OR
PASTRIES THROUGH CITY STREETS IN OPEN BASKETS OR EXPOSED
CONTAINERS. A PLAGUE ERA PUBLIC HEALTH
MEASURE THAT MODERN STATE AND FEDERAL FOOD SAFETY
STANDARDS HAVE LONG SINCE SUPERSEDED.
THE SECOND REQUIRES THAT RAGS FURNISHED TO INDUSTRIAL WORKERS
BE STERILIZED BY BOILING AND CAUSTIC SODA SOLUTION.
CAL OSHA AND FEDERAL OCCUPATIONAL HEALTH STANDARDS
NOW GOVERN THIS AREA COMPREHENSIVELY.
THE SECOND ORDINANCE AMENDS THE POLICE CODE TO REPEAL THE
CITY'S CIRCULATING LIBRARY LAW WHICH REQUIRES ANY FOR PROFIT
BOOK RENTAL BUSINESS TO OBTAIN WRITTEN PARENTAL CONSENT SIGNED
IN PERSON BEFORE A LIBRARIAN BEFORE LENDING A BOOK TO ANYONE
UNDER THE AGE OF 21. CIRCULATING LIBRARIES CEASE TO
EXIST IN 1950S. THE LAW HAS NO LIVING SUBJECTS
FOR 70 YEARS. NONE OF THESE REPEALS
NECESSARILY CREATE AN ENFORCEMENT GAP.
EACH WAS ENACTED IN RESPONSE TO A GENUINE PROBLEM.
EACH OUTLIVED THE PROBLEM IT WAS DESIGNED TO ADDRESS.
THEY REMAIN IN THE CODE SIMPLY BECAUSE REMOVING OBSOLETE LAWS
REQUIRED THAT WE SEEK TO ACT. THIS IS THE FIRST SERIES OUT OF
A LARGER SERIES OF OBSOLETE OUTDATED AND UNNECESSARY LAWS
THAT MY OFFICE IS SEEKING TO REPEAL.
>> THE REST I SUBMIT. THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR WANG AND SUPERVISOR CHAN YOU ASKED TO BE REFERRED.
INDEED JUST WANTED TO BE ADDED TO THE IN MEMORIAM TO JACK
DAVIS. THANK YOU.
NOTED THANK YOU MR. PRESIDENT. SEEING NO NAMES ON THE ROSTER
THAT CONCLUDES THE INTRODUCTION OF NEW BUSINESS.
>> ALL RIGHT. THEN I THINK WE'LL GO TO PUBLIC
COMMENT. OKAY.
>> AT THIS TIME THE BOARD WELCOMES YOUR GENERAL PUBLIC
COMMENT. YOU CAN LINE UP ON YOUR RIGHT
HAND SIDE OF THE CHAMBER ALONG THE CURTAINS AND YOU MAY SPEAK
TO THE MINUTES AS PRESENTED ITEMS 19 THROUGH 25 ON THE
ADOPTION WITHOUT COMMITTEE REFERENCE CALENDAR AND OTHER
GENERAL MATTERS THAT ARE NOT ON THE AGENDA TODAY.
>> THIS IS NOT AN OPPORTUNITY TO DISCUSS THE UM THE LINES OR
THAT HEARING WILL COME UP AFTER GENERAL PUBLIC COMMENT.
WE'RE SETTING THE TIMER FOR TWO MINUTES.
>> WELCOME TO OUR FIRST SPEAKER .
>> MY NAME IS SALA HOWE CHANDLER ABOLITIONIST AND A
SOCIAL JUSTICE FIGHTER FOR MY PEOPLE FOR MY NATION.
FOR ALMOST OVER 38 YEARS I HAVE METAMORPHOSED INTO MY POSITION.
I AM KNOWN AS SALA HA WARRIOR QUEEN QUEEN CALIFORNIA NAMED
AFTER THE BLACK AMAZON HEBREW QUEEN THAT CALIFORNIA WAS NAMED
AFTER. I CONSTANTLY HEAR THAT WE AS A
BLACK NATION HAVE NO CULTURE. >> WELL I AM CARRYING THE STAFF
OF JUDAH TO SYMBOLIZE THE STAFF OF JUDAH WOULD NOT BE TAKEN
FROM MY FEET. >> THE ROYAL LINEAGE WE ARE
HERE ACCORDING TO THE TRANS ATLANTIC SLAVE TRADE.
>> AND AS MOSES SAID AND JA ELOHIM THE ANCIENT HEBREW
CREATOR TETRO GRANDMA AND SHOW THEM MY STAFF AND TELL THEM WHO
SENT YOU I AM THAT I AM YOUR. >> WELL OHEMAA HAS SENT A WOMAN
THIS TIME WHEN YOU WASN'T EXPECTING A MALE WOMAN IS THE
CARRIER OF LIFE. >> AND WE HAVE NOTICED ALL OF
THE DECADES AND GENERATION THAT OUR BLACK CHILDREN HEBREW BOYS
HAVE BEEN MURDERED AND NO ONE HAS CALLED IN FOR A STATE OF
EMERGENCY. I AM INTRODUCING THE STAFF TO
YOU TODAY FOR THE ENFORCER OF JUSTICE.
>> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS .
>> NEXT SPEAKER I'M DEBORAH MURPHY AND I'M THE PRESIDENT OF
THE COALITION FOR SAN FRANCISCO NEIGHBORHOODS AND I'M HERE TO
SPEAK ABOUT AUXILIARY WATER SUPPLY SYSTEM FOR ALL SAN
FRANCISCO NEIGHBORHOODS. SAN FRANCISCO HAS TO MAKE SOME
TOUGH FINANCIAL CHOICES ABOUT OUR FUTURE.
WE'RE IN THIS MESS BECAUSE PREVIOUS ELECTED OFFICIALS
AND POLICYMAKERS HAVE MADE POOR DECISIONS IN THE PAST.
OUR ONLY HOPE IS FOR OUR CURRENT AND FUTURE LEADERS TO
START MAKING SMART FISCAL CHOICES FOR OUR CITY.
WHEN HE WAS MAYOR, GAVIN NEWSOM REMOVED CONTROL OF THE FUNDS
FROM OUR FIRE DEPARTMENT TO THE PUBLIC UTILITIES COMMISSION
AND 2010 2014 AND 2020 THE SAN FRANCISCO PUBLIC UTILITIES
COMMISSION PROMISED SAN FRANCISCO VOTERS THAT THE PUC
WOULD EXPAND THE ACCESS TO HIGH PRESSURE EMERGENCY FIREFIGHTING
WATER SYSTEM THAT WAS PROTECTED THE EAST SIDE OF SAN FRANCISCO
SINCE 1913. VOTERS APPROVED THESE BONDS
AND WERE TOLD THAT THE 15 NEIGHBORHOODS ON THE WESTERN
AND SOUTHERN SIDES WHICH IS TWO THIRDS OF SAN FRANCISCO WOULD
GET THE SAME IWC PROTECTION. THE IWC SAYS HYDRANTS IN THE
EAST SIDE HAVE AN UNLIMITED SUPPLY OF SALTWATER FROM THE
PACIFIC OCEAN AND THE ENTIRE CITY NEEDS THE SAME PROTECTION.
OVER THE LAST SIX YEARS A PUC HIS A SAN FRANCISCANS FOR THREE
ETHER BONDS RECEIVED AND SPENT 1.44 BILLION AND PROMISED US
THEY WOULD SPEND 312 MILLION TO EXPAND THE RW SS EMERGENCY
FIREFIGHTING WATER SYSTEM. HOWEVER THE PUC HAS PLACED ZERO
HIGH PRESSURE W SS HYDRANTS AND ZERO MILES OF WATER PIPE
ANYWHERE IN THE CITY AND THEY CANNOT TELL US WHERE OUR 312
MILLION MET WENT. TO THIS DAY THE PUC STILL DOES
NOT HAVE AN EMERGENCY FIREFIGHTING WATER PLAN TO
PROTECT THE WESTERN AND SOUTHERN SIDES OF THE CITY.
FORMER SUPERVISOR QUENTIN KOPP WROTE AN ARTICLE ABOUT THIS
ISSUE STATING IN AUGUST 2021 FRANK BLACKBURN AND 61 OTHER
RETIRED CHIEFS SIGNED AN OPEN LETTER TO THE MAYOR AND BOARD
OF SUPERVISORS STATING THAT THE CITY'S UNLIMITED AND READILY
AVAILABLE SUPPLY OF SALT WATER WAS THE ONLY VIABLE SOLUTION TO
FIREFIGHTING FOR POST EARTHQUAKE AND FLAG OPERATIONS.
MAYOR LURIE HAS SAID THAT PUBLIC SAFETY IS HIS NUMBER ONE
PRIORITY. THIS MEANS EIGHT W SS FOR THE
ENTIRE THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
APOLOGIES IF WE'RE CUTTING ANYONE OFF WE'RE SETTING THE
TIMER FOR TWO MINUTES. IF YOU LOOK AT THE TALL PODIUM
THERE WE DO HAVE A CLOCK AND YOU CAN SEE THAT THE
SOFTBALL WILL OCCUR WHEN THERE'S 30S LEFT.
HE'LL WRAP UP YOUR STATEMENT AND THEN THE FINAL BELL WILL
RING AFTER TWO MINUTES. >> WELCOME.
CHAIR AND SUPERVISORS, I'M HEATHER DAVIS SO I'M GOING TO
SPEAK ON THE SAME TOPIC. >> 60 SEVEN FORMER FIRE CHIEFS
AND CAPTAINS HAVE BRAVELY STAND TOGETHER OPPOSED TO THE
PROPOSED WEST SIDE PORTABLE EMERGENCY FIREFIGHTING SYSTEM.
>> IT'S NOT THE RESILIENT AND TIMING'S TIMELY SOLUTION.
>> WE NEED TO ADDRESS THE CRITICAL LACK OF FIREFIGHTING
RESPONSE CAPACITY IN THE SUNSET AND RICHMOND DISTRICTS.
>> THESE SEASONED LEADERS KNOW THAT THE AUXILIARY WATER SUPPLY
SYSTEM THE SYSTEM THAT SAVED THE MARINA IN 1989 IS THE ONLY
SOLUTION WE CAN AFFORD TO BUILD IN TIME TO ADDRESS THE OUTBREAK
OF FIRES ASSOCIATED WITH THE SEVEN POINT EIGHT EARTHQUAKE
THAT THE USGS HAS FORECAST. THIS WILL HIT US IN THE NEXT 30
YEARS. >> THE PROPOSED PROJECT IS AN
UNHAPPY MARRIAGE BETWEEN TWO DISTINCTLY DIFFERENT UTILITY
PROJECTS. ONE IS A LARGE VOLUME LOW
PRESSURE DRINKING WATER PIPE UPGRADE THAT WOULD INCREASE THE
VOLUME OF LOW PRESSURE WATER DISTRIBUTED THROUGHOUT THE
NEIGHBORHOODS. THE SECOND IS A DECADES LONG
DELAYED CRITICAL FIRE RESPONSE SYSTEM THAT REQUIRES HIGH
PRESSURE CAPACITY IN COMBINING THESE TWO PURPOSES.
>> ONE PROJECT REQUIRES A COSTLY TECHNOLOGY TO FLIP
BETWEEN HIGH AND LOW PRESSURE IN THE EVENT OF A MAJOR FIRE.
ADDING COMPLEXITY, REDUCING RESILIENCE AND RELIABILITY
IN THE FIREFIGHTING FUNCTION. >> THIS DUAL PURPOSE PROJECT
WILL COST FIVE BILLION DOLLARS FIRST COST AND THE PUMP
STATIONS ARE NOT SCHEDULED TO BE BUILT UNTIL THE END.
IF WE CAN ONLY BOND $250 MILLION EVERY THREE YEARS AS
CAN THE COMBINED ANSWER AND SPOOKY MONEY WOULD ALLOW.
>> IT WILL TAKE US 20 MORE ESSER BONDS OR GEARS TO
COMPLETE THIS PROJECT AND ONLY THEN WE WILL HAVE FIRE.
>> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS .
WELCOME EILEEN BOWMAN AS CHIEF CUP TV I'LL BE USING THE
OVERHEAD. >> OKAY.
EILEEN BOGAN WAS SPEAKING SENSEI PARKSIDE EDUCATION
AND ACTION COMMITTEE. >> EVEN THOUGH IT'S BEEN MORE
THAN 100 YEARS SINCE THE 1906 EARTHQUAKE, WE STILL LIVE
IN ITS SHADOW. WHAT DID THE SURVIVORS OF THE
1906 EARTHQUAKE LEARN ABOUT SAVING LIVES, PROTECTING
PROPERTY AND PERSUADING THE INSURANCE COMPANIES NOT TO
ABANDON THE SAN FRANCISCO MARKET?
>> AND DO WE STILL REMEMBER THOSE LESSONS OR HAVE WE
ABANDONED THOSE LESSONS OF 1906 IN ORDER TO CHASE THE SHINY NEW
TOYS SO THAT A CITY DEPARTMENT CAN GRASP AT THE TITLE OF BEING
THE UTILITY OF THE FUTURE? >> AN OFFICIAL REPORT RECENTLY
STATED THAT THE CITY IS AT AN INFLECTION.
>> THIS BEGS THE QUESTION WILL THE CITY CONTINUE TO ABANDON
THE PAINFUL LESSONS OF 1906 FOR A MARKETING STRATEGY
AND BRAGGING RIGHTS INSTEAD OF SOUND SCIENCE AND TESTED
ENGINEERING? IF SO, WE'LL SAN FRANCISCO BE
THE NEXT PACIFIC PALISADES. WE'RE OVER OCEANFRONT HOMES
BURNED TO THE GROUND BECAUSE THE LOS ANGELES FIRE DEPARTMENT
DIDN'T HAVE THE INFRASTRUCTURE TO USE OCEAN WATER TO FIGHT
CATASTROPHIC FIRES ON THE OVERHEAD IS THE AFTERMATH.
>> THANK YOU. THANK YOU, EILEEN BOWMAN FOR
YOUR COMMENTS. WELCOME.
THE NEXT SPEAKER. >> GOOD AFTERNOON FOLKS.
I'M APPRECIATED BY MY COMMENTS TO FIT WITHIN THE TWO MINUTES
BUT I SUBMITTED MY COMPLETE COMMENTS TO BE INCLUDED IN THE
MEETING MINUTES AS WELL AS A SPECIAL COPY FOR SUPERVISOR
CHEN IN A ROLE AS CHAIR OF THE OF THE BUDGET APPROPRIATIONS
COMMITTEE. MY NAME IS JOHN ALLEN AND I'M A
MEMBER OF THE HIV ADVOCACY NETWORK.
I'M HERE TO SPEAK ABOUT DISEASE PREVENTION AND LET'S SAY THAT
I'M VERY ANGRY AND FRUSTRATED ABOUT HOW THE HIV PROGRAMS ARE
BEING CARRIED IN THE MAYOR'S PROPOSED BUDGET.
AGAIN, PUBLIC COMMENTS AND SEVERAL HEALTH COMMISSION
MEETINGS ALONG WITH MANY OF MY COLLEAGUES WHO ARE HERE TODAY
AND BUT MOST OF THE TIME I FELT LIKE I WAS SWIMMING INTO A VOID
. HERE'S AN EXAMPLE OF WHY I'M SO
FRUSTRATED IN THE CURRENT PROPOSAL BUDGET HIV PREVENTION
PROGRAMS HAVE BEEN COMPLETELY GUTTED WHICH MEANS THAT NO
FUNDING WILL BE MADE AVAILABLE FOR SAN FRANCISCO'S AIDS
FOUNDATION'S PREP HARM REDUCTION PROGRAMS NOR THEY'RE
THE AUTOMATIC OPT OUT HIV TESTING AND EMERGENCY UNITS.
IF WE LET THESE PROGRAMS LAPSE FOR EVEN A SHORT PERIOD OF TIME
THEN THE COST TO THE CITY WILL BE MUCH, MUCH GREATER DOWN THE
ROAD. THESE PROGRAMS HAVE BEEN PROVEN
VERY SUCCESSFUL AND SUCCEEDED IN PREVENTING, DETECTING
AND TREATING HIV CASES IN NEWLY INFECTED PEOPLE.
THIS IS A STAGE WITH THESE WHERE DO CASES CAN BE TREATED
WITH THE GREATEST SUCCESS? TO QUOTE CANDIDATE LAUNCHES
CAMPAIGN PROMISES ONE OF HIS CAMPAIGN PROMISES QUOTE ACCESS
TO CULTURALLY COMPETENT HEALTH CARE IS A FUNDAMENTAL RIGHT.
THIS INCLUDES ROBUST FUNDING FOR HIV, AIDS PREVENTION
AND TREATMENT AS. AS MAYOR I WILL CONTINUE TO
BACKFILL ANY FEDERAL BUDGET CUTS ANY FEDERAL BUDGET CUTS OR
TO REDUCE IT DOWN TO THE IMMEDIATE HELP ISSUE MEETING.
I'M SURE THE MAYOR LURIE GETS HIS REGULAR PROSTATE EXAMS
AND COLONOSCOPY TO AVOID GETTING CANCER AND NOT WAIT
TILL HE'S DIAGNOSED. IF WE'RE GOING THROUGH
TREATMENTS IN CONCLUSION I WISH PREP WAS AVAILABLE BEFORE I WAS
DIAGNOSED WITH HIV 25 YEARS AGO.
HAVING HIV AIDS CAUSED ME TO HAVE MANY HIV RELATED HEALTH
ISSUES AND IT'S CAUSED ME TO MAKE MAJOR AND UNDESIRED
CHANGES TO MY LIFESTYLE. WE MUST END THIS EPIDEMIC OF
RADIO CASES IN SAN FRANCISCO FROM EXPLODING IN THE COMING
YEARS ALL BECAUSE PREVENTION PROGRAMS ARE BEING LIMITED.
>> THANK YOU. THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
ALL RIGHT. WELCOME MR. GAMBRELL.
I'VE BEEN HERE LONG TIME AGO AND I CAN'T TO BY OUT.
I'M LIVE IN DISTRICT SIX IN DORSEY ON MY SUPERVISOR OVER
MY DISTRICT JUST A COUPLE OF DAYS AGO.
I CAME INTO DORSEY'S OFFICE TO DISCUSS SOMETHING WITH HIM WAS
VERY IMPORTANT. I LIVE IN BRING HIS CORNER THEY
CUT MY IN-PERSON VISITS ALL IN ONE THEY CUT MY VISITS ALL
CAME IN AT GIB HIM SOME PEOPLE WERE IN HIS CHAIR.
HE ACKNOWLEDGED WHAT I WAS TRYING TO SAY TO HIM ABOUT MY
INJURY ACTION HIM WHY CAN HE GO AND HAVE A CONVERSATION ABOUT
MY SERVICES AND THEY VIOLATED ME ON THREE DIFFERENT OCCASIONS
AND HE GOT IN HE'S SITTING INSIDE OF H S H THEY READY TO
PUT ME OUT OF THE PROGRAM. NOW I REMIND YOU NOW I HAVE A
HEAD INJURY WHERE THESE PEOPLE ARE TRYING TO PUT A NEEDLE
IN THE BACK OF MY HEAD AND WHEN I WENT TO THE SUPERVISOR IS
IN MY DISTRICT INSTEAD OF HE'S TRIED TO HELP ME HE CALL THE
SHERIFF'S DEPARTMENT THEY COME TO THE AFTER I COME IN HERE THE
DAY TO FIND OUT IS YOU PLANNING TO END THE FEAR WITH THIS
INVESTIGATION? ARE YOU TRYING TO THE BOARD AS
A WHOLE PLEASE? ARE YOU TRYING TO DESTROY ME
BECAUSE THE LAST TIME I WAS IN HERE THIS IS WHAT YOU IGNORE
ON THE LAST TIME I WAS HERE YOU'LL SEE THAT THIS IS WHAT HE
IGNORED FOR ME THE LAST TIME THIS WAS DONE BY A CITY
EMPLOYEE. I LET THAT GO.
BUT RIGHT NOW I'M GETTING READY TO GET NEEDLES ON MY HEAD AND I
WANT YOU TO KNOW MR. GOOD, YOU'RE GOING TO ADDRESS YOUR
COMMENTS TO THE BOARD AS A WHOLE.
>> OKAY? I JUST WANT TO MAKE SURE THAT
YOU WANT TO GET IT DOCUMENTED IN MORE FURTHERMORE, YOUR YOUR
EMPLOYEE WAS STANDING BEHIND ME WHEN I CAUGHT HER AS SHE WAS
DOING THAT. >> I WANT TO KNOW WHAT THAT
WAS. MR. GAMBRELL, ADDRESS YOUR
COMMENTS TO THE BOARD AS A WHOLE.
>> THE BOARD AND I WANT TO DID IT DIRECTLY TO HIM IN FRONT OF
THE BOARD THIS IS NOT A MEETING BETWEEN YOU AND ONE SUPERVISOR.
>> I'LL BE BACK NEXT WEEK. THANK YOU, MR. GAMBRELL.
WELCOME TO THE NEXT SPEAKER GOOD EVENING.
BOARD. MY NAME IS MICHAEL WHITE AND I
AM HERE IN SUPPORT OF BOOKER T'S STABILIZATION OF ELDER HILL
HUTCH COMMUNITY CENTER. >> I WORKED AT ELIHU WHERE I
WAS A COHORT LEADER FOR THE THIRD, FOURTH, FIFTH GRADE FOR
SEVEN YEARS. WE ARE ASKING THE BOARD OF
SUPERVISORS TO STAND IN SOLIDARITY WITH US
IN SECURING THIS FACILITY AS A DEDICATED YOUTH DEVELOPMENT
CENTER A SAFE SPACE, A SAFE STRUCTURE ENVIRONMENT DESIGN TO
KEEP YOUNG PEOPLE ENGAGED, PROTECTED AND EMPOWERED.
>> THIS SPACE WILL PROVIDE AFTERSCHOOL PROGRAMING,
MENTORSHIP, MENTAL HEALTH SUPPORT, TUTORING, CAREER
READINESS, MUSIC AND ARTS DEVELOPMENT LEADERSHIP TRAINING
,CONFLICT RESOLUTION RESOURCES AND RECREATIONAL ACTIVITIES FOR
YOUTH WHO NEED POSITIVE OUTLETS AND GUIDANCE.
>> MY VERBAL OUTREACH IS IMPERATIVE IN A TIME WHERE MANY
YOUNG PEOPLE FACE INCREASED VIOLENCE, ISOLATION,
INSTABILITY AND LACK OF OPPORTUNITY.
>> PLEASE ALLOW ELLA HILL COMMUNITY CENTER TO REMAIN A
CORNERSTONE HOME FOR PREVENTION ,HEALING AND GROWTH RATHER
THAN ALLOWING ANOTHER COMMUNITY SPACE TO DISAPPEAR.
>> THANK YOU. THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
NEXT SPEAKER GOOD EVENING SUPERVISORS.
>> MY NAME IS JD KYRIE AND I AM HERE IN SUPPORT OF BOOKER T.
I WAS IN THIRD GRADE WHEN MY MOM SIGNED ME UP TO ATTEND
ELLIE HILL AND FOR YEARS THIS SPACE WAS ALL I KNEW.
SOME OF MY MOST IMPORTANT MEMORIES WERE MADE IN THAT
CENTER. IT GAVE ME AND MY PEERS A SAFE
EXCUSE ME PLACE TO LEARN, GROW AND BUILD RELATIONSHIPS WITHIN
OUR COMMUNITY. I DID NOT FULLY UNDERSTAND THE
IMPACT THIS SPACE HAD ON ME UNTIL I HAD THE PRIVILEGE TO
WORK IN THE SAME SPACE IN THE SAME BUILDING THAT ONCE SERVED
ME AS AN ADOLESCENT. I'M 24 NOW BY THE WAY.
NOT EVERY YOUNG PERSON HAS ACCESS TO STABILITY, MENTORSHIP
OR A SAFE ENVIRONMENT OUTSIDE OF SCHOOL IN HOME COMMUNITIES
LIKE OURS NEED MORE INVESTMENT, MORE SUPPORT AND MORE SAFE
SPACES FOR YOUNG PEOPLE, NOT FEWER.
AND I AM A LIVING TESTIMONY AS TO WHY ELLIE HILL WAS AND STILL
IS IMPORTANT. AS I CLOSE OUT I ASK THAT YOU
GUYS CONSIDER THIS NOTION WITH AN OPEN MIND BECAUSE IT'S NOT
ABOUT ANY OF US. IT'S SOLELY ABOUT FURTHERING
THIS ESTABLISHMENT FOR THE SAKE OF THE CHILDREN OF OUR
COMMUNITY. >> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. >> NEXT SPEAKER.
>> GOOD AFTERNOON. BOARD OF SUPERVISORS.
I'M ALSO HERE IN SUPPORT OF BOOKER T STABILIZING A LARGE
COMMUNITY CENTER. >> MY NAME IS KENNETH CARRIGAN.
I WORKED AT THE HILL HUTCH COMMUNITY CENTER AS A MIDDLE
SCHOOL LEAD FOR FOUR YEARS. IN THOSE FOUR YEARS I'VE SEEN
THE STUDENTS FLOURISH INTO AMAZING STUDENTS, ATHLETES
AND UPSTANDING MEMBERS OF THE COMMUNITY.
THEY'VE EXPLORED COLLEGES AND DIFFERENT CAREER
OPPORTUNITIES AND LEARNED ABOUT THEMSELVES AND AND EACH OTHER
IN FUN AND ENGAGING WAYS. AND THIS ALL HAPPENED BECAUSE
THE DOORS WERE OPEN AND THE NEED TO STAY OPEN.
LAST SUMMER I TOLD MY STUDENTS I'LL SEE YOU NEXT SUMMER.
I DON'T WANT TO BREAK MY PROMISE AND LEAVE THEM.
IT'LL BREAK THEIR HEART WHEN THEY FOUND OUT THAT THEIR
SUMMER HAS BEEN TAKEN AWAY. I WANT TO SEE MY STUDENTS
AGAIN. PROGRAMS LIKE BOOKER T CAN
CHANGE LIVES BY KEEPING THE DOORS OF L.A. HILL CAN CONTINUE
SUPPORTING YOUTH AND INSPIRE THEM TO BE THE BEST VERSIONS OF
THEMSELVES. ELMHURST COMMUNITY CENTER ISN'T
JUST A BUILDING. IT'S A BEACON OF HOPE
AND SAFETY TO THE COMMUNITY. WE NEED PROGRAMS THAT HELP TO
KEEP THE SPIRIT OF ELLIOT HILL HUT ALIVE.
PLEASE ALLOW BOOKER T WASHINGTON TO ACTIVATE THE
SPACE AND CONTINUE PROGRAMING LITTLE HOPE COMMUNITY CENTER.
>> THANK YOU. THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
WELCOME TO OUR NEXT SPEAKER. JUST LIKE YOU.
>> HI, MY NAME IS JESSICA. LET'S START MY TIME OUT.
CAN WE PLEASE. OKAY.
HERE WE GO. LET ME START IT.
>> WHEN I UPLOAD THIS JESSICA OUR I.T. EMPLOYEE IS COMING
AROUND TO ASSIST YOU. >> OKAY, PERFECT.
THANK YOU. THANK YOU, BILLY.
THANK YOU, BILLY. SO YOU'VE GOT IT.
THIS IS THE ONE. YEAH.
YES, PLEASE. ALL RIGHT.
I'M STARTING YOUR TIME NOW, JESSICA.
>> OH, GREAT. HI.
MY NAME IS JESSICA PERSICO HERE ARE MY CREDENTIALS.
LAST TIME WE TALKED ABOUT FIXING OVERLAPPING BUS ROUTES
TO GUARANTEE DIRECT ONE SEAT RIDE TO ESSENTIAL PLACES
INCLUDING SAN FRANCISCO GENERAL HOSPITAL CLINICS AND MAJOR
COMMUNITY EVENTS PUBLIC HEALTH AND SANITATION BY IMPLEMENTING
MEASURES SUCH AS SECURING LIDS TO ALL PUBLIC GARBAGE CANS
WE'LL BE ABLE TO PREVENT LITTERING AND PESTS.
WE ALSO WANT TO EXPAND RESTROOM ACCESS FOR EXAMPLE ON LARKIN
AND GROVE. THE RESTROOM IS ONLY OPEN TILL
7 A.M. UNTIL 7 P.M.. THAT'S PRETTY LIMITED HOURS OF
OPERATION. >> WE ALSO WANT TO EXPAND
HEALTH CARE OFF SERVICES. >> WE KNOW THAT MENTAL HEALTH
CARE CRISIS IS CAN HAPPEN AT ANY TIME OF THE DAY PAST OUR
BUSINESS HOURS. >> WE WANT TO ENSURE
AND INSURANCE FLEXIBLY. WE KNOW THAT SILVER AVENUE
HEALTH CARE CLINIC AND S.F. GENERAL ONLY ACCEPTS MEDICAL
INSURANCE BY ACCEPTING MORE TYPES OF INSURANCE.
WE'LL BE ABLE TO GET MORE FUNDING.
WE ALSO WANT TO TALK NEXT ABOUT LOWERING THE COST OF HEALTH
CARE SERVICES AND IMPROVING OUR VISION CARE WHICH WE'LL GET
INTO NEXT TIME. >> HOUSING STABILITY.
ONE IMPORTANT WAYS TO ENSURE THIS IS BY HAVING OUR HOUSING
STABILITY OVERSIGHT COMMITTEE STILL MEET.
RIGHT NOW IT'S CANCELED. WE ALSO WANT TO ADVERTISE
DIFFERENT EVENTS AND OPTIONS FOR AFFORDABLE HOUSING SUCH AS
THE ONE YOU SEE HERE TOO TO ENSURE COMPETITION.
NEXT WEEK WE'LL TALK ABOUT OR NEXT TIME WE'LL TALK ABOUT
OPPOSING THE S.F. DRUG FREE HOUSING MANDATE.
STRENGTHENING CONSUMER PROTECTIONS LOWERING THE COST
FOR SMALL BUSINESSES, REDUCING RED TAPE AND INVESTING
IN DISTRICT TEN INFRASTRUCTURE LIKE JACKSON PLAYGROUND PARK.
SECURING A $5 MILLION INVESTMENT FOR POOLS LIKE
MARTIN LUTHER KING JUNIOR. AND CREATING A SOUND BARRIER
WALL ON 18TH AND VERMONT AND MORE.
>> THANK YOU ALL. THANK YOU, JESSICA.
>> WELCOME TO OUR NEXT SPEAKER .
HELLO. MY NAME IS LETICIA HOWARD.
I AM THE CEO OF QUICHE CARE'S NONPROFIT.
I AM BASED IN SAN FRANCISCO SO I GO TO ALL DISTRICTS.
I AM URGING YOU TO SUPPORT BOOKER T COMMUNITY SERVICE
CENTER CENTER'S 13 MONTH LEASE TO THE HISTORICAL ELLA HILL
HUTCH COMMUNITY CENTER OPEN MORE THAN 150 VULNERABLE
FAMILIES, YOUTH AND TEENS WHO ARE RELYING ON SERVICES TO
START ON TIME ON JUNE 15TH WITHOUT AN APPROVED LEASE OR IF
THE PROCESS IS EVEN MORE DELAYED.
ELLA HILL HUTCHINS SERVICES WILL END WITHOUT A CLEAR PATH
FOR CONTINUALLY THAT WILL LEAVE FAMILIES AND SENIORS WITHOUT
ESSENTIAL SUPPORT AND PUT OTHERS HISTORICALLY BLACK
COMMUNITY INSTITUTIONS AT RISK. WE KNOW THAT WHEN THE DOORS OF
BLACK INSTITUTIONS, BUSINESSES AND ORGANIZATIONS IN THE
FILLMORE CLOSED THEY RARELY REOPEN.
WE CAN'T LET THAT HAPPEN AGAIN. BOOKER T HAS OUR FILLMORE
AND WESTERN EDITION FOR MORE THAN 107 YEARS.
I SUPPORT THIS TRANSITION BECAUSE I WORKED AT BOOKER T
FOR 1920 YEARS. I WAS A YOUTH AT BOOKER T AND I
DID EVERY JOB THAT YOU CAN NAME.
I GREW THERE AND I BECAME A GOOD CITIZEN AND A LEADER
AND MY MISSION IS TO GIVE A LITTLE HOPE AND HELP TO THOSE
THAT MAY NEED IT IN THE COMMUNITY.
SO I GO TO DIFFERENT EVENTS AND I TABLE AND I GIVE AWAY
ESSENTIAL THINGS AND ITEMS AND INFORMATION THAT IS
ESSENTIAL TO THE RESIDENTS. AND WITHOUT BOOKER T'S HELP
GUIDANCE AND SUPPORT I WOULD NOT BE HERE TODAY.
PLEASE GIVE THEM THAT LEASE. THANK YOU.
THANK YOU LAKEISHA HOWARD FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
WELCOME TO OUR NEXT SPEAKER. >> GOOD EVENING SUPERVISORS.
MY NAME IS SASHA EARL AND I'M HERE IN SUPPORT OF BOOKER T
STRENGTHENING EDGHILL HUTCH COMMUNITY CENTER.
I'M FROM THE NEIGHBORHOOD AND I ALSO WORKED AT ALLEY HILL FOR
THREE YEARS AS A K THROUGH TWO TEACHER ELLA HILL WAS MORE THAN
A PROGRAM TO US. IT'S A VILLAGE FOR MYSELF
AND OUR CHILDREN GROWING UP AND BEING A PRODUCT OF EARLY
HILL EARLIER HAS BEEN THERE FOR MY FAMILY.
L.L. HAS PUT MYSELF AND MY SIBLINGS IN INTERNSHIPS.
THEY PLACE THIS IN HOUSINGS. THEY PROVIDED FOOD AND THEY
PROVIDED SUPPLIES. ELIOR HAS PARTNERED WITH MANY
PROGRAMS THROUGH OUR SAN FRANCISCO HELPING CONNECT
STUDENTS AND FAMILIES TO RESOURCES, INTERNSHIPS
AND OPPORTUNITIES TO ENTER THE WORKFORCE.
STARTING AT THE AGE OF 13 YEARS OLD.
MANY FAMILIES DEPEND ON THESE RESOURCES AND LOOKING FORWARD
TO THE NEW OPPORTUNITIES LRO GIVES CHILDREN A SENSE OF
BELONGING, CONFIDENCE, FRIENDSHIP AND A SAFE PLACE TO
EXPRESS THEMSELVES. ELLIE HILL IS A SAFETY NET FOR
A LOT OF PEOPLE THAT DO NOT HAVE THAT ACCESS.
TAKE A LOOK AROUND. NOT EVERY CHILD GROWS UP WITH
STABILITY OR SAFETY AT HOME. >> EXCUSE ME AND PLACES LIKE
ELIHU HELPS FILL THAT GAP. LOSING THIS PROGRAM WOULD
DEEPLY IMPACT CHILDREN AND FAMILIES WHO DEPEND ON IT
AND WHEN AND WITHOUT SPACES LIKE THIS, MANY YOUTH CAN
BECOME MISGUIDED OR DISCONNECTED FROM POSITIVE ROLE
MODELS, SUPPORT SYSTEMS AND OPPORTUNITIES THAT HELP
THEM GROW. WE NEED PROGRAMS LIKE EARLY
HILL TO PROTECT OUR BLACK CHILDREN ON OUR BACK IN OUR
BLACK FAMILIES. THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU SASHA EARLE FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
WELCOME TO OUR NEXT SPEAKER. >> GOOD EVENING.
BOARD OF SUPERVISORS BOARD OF SUPERVISORS MY NAME IS MARVA
AUSTIN I'M SUPPORT HERE BOOKER T'S BACKING OF L.A. COMMUNITY
CENTER. I'M ASKING TO KEEP L.A. HEAL
OPEN. WE NEED PROGRAMS LIKE THIS
ESPECIALLY IN A FILLMORE DISTRICT.
MY CHILDREN HAVE BEEN ATTENDING BOOKER T FOR SEVERAL YEARS
AND THEY LOVE IT EVERY TIME THEY GO BETWEEN AFTERSCHOOL
PROGRAMS, SUMMER CAMP PROGRAMS. I HONESTLY DON'T KNOW WHAT TO
DO WITHOUT BOOKER T OR L.A. HEAL COMMUNITY CENTER.
THESE PROGRAMS HELP MY CHILDREN FEEL MORE CONFIDENT IN SCHOOLS
WITH THEIR READING AND MATH WHICH ENCOURAGE THEM TO SUCCEED
THROUGHOUT THEIR EDUCATIONAL JOURNEY.
BOOKER T AND L.A. HEAL HAVE BEEN A HUGE PART OF THE
COMMUNITY BUY HELPING FAMILIES, SENIORS, RESIDENTS AND MOST OF
OUR CHILDREN'S FAMILIES DEPEND ON THESE CENTERS FOR SUPPORT
FOOD RESOURCES, MENTAL HEALTH SERVICES, SUPPORTIVE HOUSING
SERVICES, GUIDANCE FOR CHILDREN AND YOUTH AND MOST OF ALL A
SAFE PLACE FOR CHILDREN. BOOKER T'S LEADER WITH BOOKER
T'S GREAT LEADERSHIP I BELIEVE L.A. HEAL CAN JUST BE
SUCCESSFUL AS BOOKER T AND CONTINUE TO MAKE AND MAKING
A POSITIVE IMPACT IN OUR BLACK COMMUNITIES.
>> PLEASE KEEP L.A. HEAL OPEN. THANK YOU FOR YOUR TIME.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. WELCOME TO OUR NEXT SPEAKER.
HELLO, I AM GLADYS WONG, A PROUD CHINESE WITH FAMILY
FRIENDS OF DIFFERENT RACIAL BACKGROUNDS.
IT IS A ASIAN AMERICAN NATIVE HAWAIIAN PACIFIC ISLANDER
MONTH. >> THE MONTH OF MAY WAS CHOSEN
TO COMMEMORATE THE IMMIGRATION OF THE FIRST JAPANESE TO THE
UNITED STATES ON MAY 7TH, 1843 AND TO MARKED THE ANNIVERSARY
OF THE COMPLETION OF THE TRANS CONTINENTAL RAILROAD ON MAY
10TH, 1869. >> THE MAJORITY OF THE WORKERS
WHO LAID THOSE TRACKS WERE CHINESE IMMIGRANTS.
MY MOTHER'S GRANDFATHER WORKED ON THE RAILROAD I WALKED THE
LAST TEN MILES AT THE 150TH ANNIVERSARY.
>> MY MOTHER AT ANGEL ISLAND CALLED IT A PRISON.
>> AUNTIE MARY SYCAMORE WROTE WE THE PEOPLE A STORY OF THE
AMERICAN INTERNMENT AND STEPHEN RICARDO SAID CONCENTRATION
CAMPS THE JAPANESE WERE PATRIOTIC LOYAL CITIZENS
WRONGLY ACCUSED. >> THE US GOVERNMENT DID
APOLOGIZE GIVING REPARATIONS BUT RACISM STILL EXISTS.
>> I HAVE BEEN HERE 20 PLUS YEARS IN BEAUTIFUL SAN
FRANCISCO WHICH I LOVE. >> I AM ALSO A GOOD CITIZEN
HAVING DONE NOTHING WRONG BUT I AM TRACKED, INTIMIDATED,
HARASSED. MY MISSION HOME HAS BEEN BROKEN
INTO MANY TIMES INVASION OF PRIVACY KEYS, CARS, PAPERS,
PHONE GIVE INFORMATION ACCESS TO MY PRIVATE PROPERTY ACCOUNTS
WHEREABOUTS THE CITY HAS DAMAGED MY PROPERTY YET TO BE
REPAIRED. >> AMERICANS OF ALL AGES
CLASSES HAVE DIFFERENT VALUES PRIORITIES FUTURES SANFORD'S
FISCAL IS ALSO VERY TOUGH. I NEED HELP.
>> THANK YOU. THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
NEXT SPEAKER GOOD AFTERNOON SUPERVISORS.
I'M JONATHAN FRANKS WORK WITH SAN FRANCISCO AIDS FOUNDATION.
I'M TESTIFYING REGARDING ITEM 19 THE RESOLUTION RECOGNIZING
HIV LONG TERM SURVIVORS AWARENESS DAY.
I'D LIKE TO THANK SUPERVISOR CHAN AND THE OTHER SPONSORS OF
THIS RESOLUTION FOR BRINGING MUCH APPRECIATE IT ATTENTION TO
THE NEEDS OF LONG TERM HIV SURVIVORS AND OTHER OLDER
ADULTS LIVING WITH HIV AT THE SAME TIME I WOULD BE REMISS IF
I DIDN'T HIGHLIGHT THAT THOSE NEEDS ARE NOT CURRENTLY BEING
MET BY SAN FRANCISCO'S AGING AGENCY.
AS THE RESOLUTION STATES, THE DEPARTMENT OF DISABILITY
AND AGING SERVICES HAS ACTUALLY NEVER DEDICATED FUNDING TOWARD
PROGRAMS THAT ARE SPECIFICALLY TAILORED TO PEOPLE AGING WITH
HIV. >> THE DEPARTMENT HAS DECLINED
REQUESTS FROM ADVOCATES TO ALLOCATE NEW FUNDING FOR HIV
AND AGING SERVICES TO SET ASIDE EXISTING FUNDING FOR THESE
SERVICES TO IDENTIFY LONG TERM HIV SURVIVORS AS A PRIORITY
POPULATION OR EVEN TO COLLECT DATA ON HOW MANY LONG TERM HIV
SURVIVORS THEY SERVE. AGAIN, WE ARE TRULY GRATEFUL
FOR YOUR RECOGNITION OF HIV LONG-TERM SURVIVORS AWARENESS
DAY AND WE ENCOURAGE THE BOARD TO FOLLOW UP ON THIS WONDERFUL
RECOGNITION BY SUPPORTING ADVOCATES REQUEST FOR DOS TO
FUND THE PROGRAMS CARING FOR SAN FRANCISCO'S HIV ELDERS.
THANK YOU. THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
>> WE WELCOME THE NEXT SPEAKER. GOOD EVENING SUPERVISORS.
I DON'T WANT TO REPEAT EVERYTHING THE LAST SPEAKER
SAID SO I JUST MAKE THIS PERSONAL.
MY NAME IS VINCE CHRISTMAS TOMORROW.
I'VE BEEN LIVING WITH HIV SINCE 1986 AND PART OF THE REASON WHY
I AM ALIVE TODAY IS BECAUSE I GOT THE TREATMENT, I GOT THE
SERVICES, I GOT EVERYTHING THAT I NEEDED AND MOST OF THAT I GOT
IN SAN FRANCISCO WHEREVER I WENT IN THE WORLD IT SAN
FRANCISCO PROVIDED ME A HOME AND I WANT TO THANK SUPERVISOR
CHEN FOR THIS RESOLUTION AND WE ARE OVER 11 THOUSAND 500 PEOPLE
LIVING WITH HIV IN THIS CITY AND THERE ARE ABOUT 15,000.
WE HAVE MANY FRIENDS, LOVED ONES WE ARE A VOTING BLOCK
AND I WANT TO JUST THANK SUPERVISOR CHEN AND ALL THE
SUPERVISORS WHO ARE ENDORSING THIS WHO HAVE COME FORWARD TO
SUPPORT THIS INITIATIVE BECAUSE IT'S IMPORTANT.
>> LAST YEAR I LOST 25 FRIENDS TO HIV.
PEOPLE WILL SAY IT'S OLD AGE BUT YOU KNOW, I WAS TOLD I
WOULDN'T LIVE TO SEE 30. I TURNED 65 IN FEBRUARY AND NOW
I'M LOOKING TOWARD RETIREMENT AND SAN FRANCISCO MADE THAT
POSSIBLE. SO I WANT TO THANK YOU AGAIN.
LONG TERM SURVIVOR HIV LONG TERM SURVIVOR AWARENESS STAYS
IMPORTANT TO US AS A COMMUNITY. I ALSO WANT TO SAY THAT WHILE
IT'S GREAT THAT I GET ALL THESE SERVICES, THE MOST IMPORTANT
THING ABOUT HIV IS PREVENTING PEOPLE FROM GETTING IT.
SO AS YOU KNOW THERE IS A BUDGET COMING UP SO I HOPE YOU
WILL THINK ABOUT THAT BECAUSE IT'S MUCH MORE EXPENSIVE TO
TREAT HIV THAN IT IS TO PREVENT IT.
>> THANK YOU. THANK YOU, VINCE.
CHRIS, ESTIMATE FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
WELCOME TO THE NEXT SPEAKER. GOOD AFTERNOON.
GOOD AFTERNOON. MY NAME IS MATT FORM AND I'M
EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR OF AIDS LEGAL REFERRAL PANEL.
WE PROVIDE FREE LEGAL SERVICES TO PEOPLE LIVING WITH HIV
AND AIDS AND WE'VE HANDLED 100,000 CASES SINCE OUR
FOUNDING 43 YEARS AGO. I'M HERE TO SPEAK IN SUPPORT OF
THE RESOLUTION CONCERNING LONGTIME SURVIVORS.
I REALLY WANT TO APPRECIATE ALL OF YOU FOR BEING HERE TONIGHT
AND DURING THESE MEETINGS AND FOR SUPPORTING THIS
RESOLUTION. >> THIS IS SOMETHING WE NEVER
THOUGHT WOULD HAPPEN THAT WE WOULD SEE PEOPLE LIVING WITH
HIV LIVING INTO THEIR 60S, 70S AND BEYOND.
THAT WAS UNIMAGINABLE 30 YEARS AGO.
BACK THEN OF COURSE HIV WAS A DEATH SENTENCE.
THE PEOPLE WE ARE TALKING ABOUT WITH THIS RECOGNITION
RESOLUTION ARE PEOPLE THAT LARGELY CONTRACTED THE VIRUS
BEFORE THEIR EFFECTIVE ANTIVIRALS THAT MEANT HIV ARE
WREAKING HAVOC ON THEIR BODIES. THEY WATCHED THEIR FRIENDS
AND ENTIRE SOCIAL NETWORKS DIE AROUND THEM.
MANY LOST THEIR ABILITY TO WORK.
MANY FELL INTO POVERTY. MANY FELL INTO LIFELONG
DEPRESSION. I DON'T WANT TO SAY, HOWEVER,
THESE PEOPLE ARE VICTIMS. >> THEY ARE INCREDIBLY
RESILIENT AND THAT'S WHAT THIS RESOLUTION WOULD LIFT UP.
>> AND I CONTRARY TO WHAT A LOT OF PEOPLE THINK, THIS
POPULATION IS NOT GOING AWAY ANYTIME SOON.
IN FACT IT IS RAPIDLY INCREASING.
THIS CHART I HAVE HERE SHOWS THAT OVER THE NEXT TEN YEARS
THE NUMBER OF PEOPLE LIVING WITH HIV OVER 70 IS GOING TO
DOUBLE IN SAN FRANCISCO AND THE CITY, AS I STATED EARLIER, IS
JUST NOT READY FOR IT. >> THANK YOU FOR YOUR
ATTENTION. THANK YOU METFORMIN FOR YOUR
COMMENTS. >> WE WELCOME THE NEXT SPEAKER
. >> GOOD AFTERNOON SUPERVISORS.
MY NAME IS JEFF SYSTEM NOW WITH THE HIV ADVOCACY NETWORK.
A HUGE SHOUT OUT TO CALVIN AND SUPERVISOR CHAN'S OFFICE
FOR SUPPORTING THIS RESOLUTION. I'M HERE IN SUPPORT OF IDA 19
THE LONG TO HONORING LONG TERM SURVIVORS IT IS IMPORTANT TO
HONORS THOSE WHO HAVE BEEN LIVING WITH HIV IN EVERY
CONCEIVABLE WAY. THE FIGHT FOR LIVING FOR THOSE
LIVING WITH HIV AND AT RISK FOR HIV AND AIDS IS NOT ONLY
EMBEDDED INTO THE FABRIC OF THIS CITY BUT IN THIS COUNTRY
AND THE WORLD. ADVOCATES IN THIS ROOM
AND BEYOND HAVE GREATLY IMPROVED NOT ONLY OUR OWN
SYSTEMS OF CARE BUT SYSTEMS OF CARE ACROSS THE WORLD.
I STAND BEFORE YOU AS SOMEBODY LIVING WITH HIV FOR EIGHT YEARS
AND I AM SO UNBELIEVABLY GRATEFUL FOR THE WORK FOR THOSE
THAT HAVE COME BEFORE ME SO THAT I CAN HEALTHILY LIVE
IN THIS BEAUTIFUL CITY. AND PART OF HONORING THIS WORK
IS ALSO CONTINUING TO SPEAK TRUTH TO THE UNMET NEEDS THAT
THIS COMMUNITY HAS. THE PROPOSED BUDGET CUTS AIM TO
TAKE AWAY MONEY FROM HIV PREVENTION AND HARM REDUCTION
AND IT IS AN AFFRONT TO THE LEGACY OF THESE LONG TERM
SURVIVORS. I HOPE THAT ALONG WITH YOUR
SUPPORT FOR THIS RESOLUTION WE CAN COUNT ON YOUR ADVOCACY
IN THE CITY BUDGET PROCESS TO ALSO HONOR THESE LONG TERM
SURVIVORS BY FULLY FUNDING HIV PREVENTION, HARM REDUCTION
AND LGBTQ SERVICES OR AT THE VERY LEAST PREVENT THESE CUTS
FROM HAPPENING BY THE END OF JUNE.
NOT ONLY ARE THESE SERVICES IMPORTANT FOR OUR COMMUNITY BUT
ALSO TO BE DEDICATED SPECIFICALLY TO PEOPLE OF COLOR
AND BLACK AND BROWN COMMUNITIES WHO HAVE OFTEN BEEN LEFT OUT OF
THIS CONVERSATION. ONCE AGAIN, THANK YOU ALL
SUPERVISORS FOR YOUR TIME AND I LOOK FORWARD TO WORKING WITH
YOU THROUGHOUT THE REST OF THE CITY BUDGET PROCESS AND IN
SUPPORT OF THIS RESOLUTION. >> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU JUSTICE FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
WELCOME. THE NEXT SPEAKER.
>> HELLO. GOOD EVENING BOARD OF
SUPERVISORS. MY NAME IS GEORGE GRAHAM.
I'M 69 YEARS OLD. I'M A RETIRED REGISTERED NURSE
FROM ST HURST HOSPITAL. I WORKED THERE FOR 40 YEARS.
I'M ALSO A PUBLIC HEALTH NURSE. >> IN 1985 WHEN I GRADUATED
FROM USF WITH MY BACHELOR'S OF NURSING SCIENCE, I FOUND OUT I
WAS HIV POSITIVE. I AM A LONG TERM SURVIVOR OF
HIV DISEASE. AS I URGE YOU TO CONSIDER THE
BUDGET CUTS TO HIV SERVICES. TO WHAT END WILL YOU BE MAKING
THOSE CUTS? SO THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR ALL OF
YOUR RECOGNITION. FOR THE HIV PEOPLE OUT HERE
IN SAN FRANCISCO. >> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. >> WE WELCOME TO THE NEXT
SPEAKER. >> HELLO BOARD.
MY NAME IS TREY TURNER. I'M HERE BECAUSE I STAND ON THE
SHOULDERS OF THE BRAVE ELDERS WHO CAME BEFORE ME WHO FOUGHT,
BLED AND SUFFERED SO THAT I COULD HAVE THE ABILITY TO STAND
HERE TODAY AS A PROUD, HEALTHY BLACK GAY MAN IN THIS CITY.
I'M ABLE TO DO THE WORK THAT I DO AS A MANAGER CLINICAL
ASSISTANT AT SAN FRANCISCO AIDS FOUNDATION BECAUSE OF THE GAY,
LESBIAN, TRANS AND GENDER PEOPLE WHO PAVED THE WAY, WHO
CREATED THE HIV INFRASTRUCTURE PROGRAM SERVICES
AND INSTITUTIONS THAT SHAPE THE HEALTH CARE AND PUBLIC HEALTH
LANDSCAPE IN SAN FRANCISCO AS IT EXISTS TODAY.
I'M CURRENTLY HIV NEGATIVE. I'VE NEVER LOST A FRIEND OR A
LOVED ONE TO HIV AND AIDS AND I ATTRIBUTE THAT DIRECTLY TO THE
SACRIFICE IN EFFORTS OF OUR LONG TERM SURVIVORS AND HIV
ADVOCATES. I WOULD BE REMISS IF I DIDN'T
FIGHT FOR THE OLDER GENERATIONS THAT WERE KNOCKED DOWN AND GOT
BACK UP TIME AND TIME AGAIN SO THAT THOSE OF US IN THIS ROOM
COULD DREAM OF ANY KIND OF FUTURE AS LGBT PEOPLE.
I KNOW THAT I WOULD NOT BE WHERE I AM WITHOUT MY LGBT
ELDERS, MENTORS AND FRIENDS ALL OF WHOM WHO HAVE PERSEVERED.
MANY ARE NOW GONE AND MANY OF THEMSELVES HAVE LOST DEARLY.
TO EVERY PERSON IN THIS ROOM IT IS NO UNDERSTATEMENT TO SAY
THAT WE OWE A GREAT DEBT TO THOSE LONG TERM SURVIVORS.
NOW IN THEIR LATTER YEARS TO SUGGEST THAT WE PULL VITAL HIV
RESOURCES AND PUBLIC HEALTH FUNDING AWAY FROM THEM AS
OUTLINED IN MAYOR LARRY'S PROPOSED BUDGET IS A DISGRACE.
MANY NEED THAT FUNDING NOW MORE THAN EVER.
THE CITY OWES A TREMENDOUS DEBT TO OUR LONG TERM SURVIVORS
AND I IMPLORE THE BOARD TO REVERSE CUTS TO HIV FUNDING
THAT DIRECTLY AND INDIRECTLY IMPACTS OUR LGBT.
THERE'S A LONG TERM SURVIVORS OF HIV AND AIDS.
ALSO SHOUT OUT TO BOOKER T PLEASE SAVE THAT AS WELL.
THANK YOU. >> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
WELCOME TO THE NEXT SPEAKER. >> GOOD AFTERNOON PRESIDENT
MERRIMAN MEMBERS OF THE BOARD. MY NAME IS PAUL AGUILAR.
I AM A LONG TERM SURVIVOR OF AIDS HAVING BEEN DIAGNOSED
IN 1988. I WANT TO THANK YOU FOR
RECOGNIZING LONG TERM SURVIVORS AWARENESS DAY HAPPENS TO FALL
ON THE ANNIVERSARY OF THOSE FIRST REPORTS FROM THE CDC FROM
JUNE 5TH, 1981 WHICH ALSO HAPPENED TO BE TWO WEEKS BEFORE
MY 18TH BIRTHDAY. >> BUT COMMEMORATIVE
RESOLUTIONS RING HOLLOW WHEN OUR ACTUAL LIFELINES ARE BEING
SEVERED. ON MAY 17TH 2020 TO EVERY
SINGLE PERSON ON THIS BOARD MADE A UNANIMOUS PROMISE TO THE
PEOPLE OF SAN FRANCISCO. YOU VOTED TO HONOR THE SAN
FRANCISCO PRINCIPLES 2020 AND PROTECT OUR HIV SAFETY NET.
BUT NOW THE SFO AND THE MAYOR ARE PROPOSING A $37
MILLION IN CUTS IN CONTRACT REDUCTIONS CUTTING 2.2 MILLION
FROM HIV COMMUNITY BASED ORGANIZATIONS AND SLASHING
FUNDING FOR BLACK, LATINO AND TRANS LED HEALTH ACCESS
POINTS. IT IS A DIRECT VIOLATION OF
THAT 2022 COMMITMENT. WE DIDN'T SURVIVE DECADES OF
THIS EPIDEMIC JUST TO BE ABANDONED TO BALANCE THE SHORT
TERM DEFICIT MOVING FORWARD WITH THESE CUTS WILLFULLY TO
DISMANTLE THE FRAMEWORK THAT YOU SWORE TO UPHOLD.
WE AREN'T ASKING FOR A NEW PRIORITY.
WE'RE ASKING FOR YOU TO KEEP THE EXACT PROMISES THAT YOU
MADE TO US. DO WHAT YOU CAN TO PREVENT
THESE CUTS. THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. WELCOME TO THE NEXT SPEAKER.
>> GOOD EVENING. MY NAME IS JERRY COFFEE
AND FIRST OF ALL I WANT TO THANK THE BOARD FOR THE
RESOLUTION 19. I'M A 74 YEAR OLD 38 YEAR LONG
TERM SURVIVOR. I'VE LIVED MORE THAN HALF MY
LIFE AS AN HIV SURVIVOR. >> I DON'T KNOW HOW I GOT HERE
. I'LL BE HONEST WITH YOU.
BUT WITHOUT THE HELP OF THE SAN FRANCISCO AIDS FOUNDATION
AND OTHER SERVICES IN SAN FRANCISCO, I'D BE DEAD.
>> FORTUNATELY I DIDN'T GO. I DIDN'T GO THAT ROUTE.
I WENT THROUGH STONEWALL. STONEWALL ARE A REHABILITATION
PROGRAM. I WENT THROUGH THE CLINICAL
ASSISTANCE INTERNSHIP PROGRAM WHICH TREY JUST SPOKE OF
AND BECAME A HEALTH EDUCATOR WITH SOUTH FLORIDA AIDS
FOUNDATION. AND THAT IS THAT IS MY PURPOSE.
PARDON ME. SORRY ABOUT THAT.
THAT IS MY PURPOSE TO HELP FOLKS LIKE ME WHO HAVE SURVIVED
THIS. THIS AMOUNT OF TIME THAT
CO-MORBIDITIES THAT WE HAVE TO DEAL WITH HEART DISEASE,
DIABETES, OSTEOPOROSIS THAT OCCUR IN US MUCH WORSE THAN IT
OCCURS IN SOMEONE WHO IS HIV POSITIVE.
I URGE THE BOARD AND THE MAYOR TO UPHOLD THE SAN
FRANCISCO PRINCIPLES THAT WAS ESTABLISHED IN SEPTEMBER 2020.
YOU TOLD US YOU WOULD HAVE OUR BACK.
YOU TOLD US THAT YOU WOULD HELP KEEP US ALIVE.
HONOR THAT PROMISE. IT'S A MORAL CONTRA ACT.
>> THANK YOU. THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
WELCOME TO THE NEXT SPEAKER. >> I GOOD AFTERNOON PRESIDENT
MERRIMAN AND MEMBERS OF THE BOARD.
MY NAME IS MICHAEL RUE PAIN. I'M A COAUTHOR OF THE SAN
FRANCISCO PRINCIPLES A LONG TERM SURVIVOR AND DISTRICT NINE
PRESIDENT. I WANT TO THANK SUPERVISOR CHAN
AND THE SPONSORS OF THE BOARD FOR INTRODUCING ITEM 19
AND RECOGNIZING JUNE 5TH AS HIV LONG-TERM SURVIVORS AWARENESS
DAY. BUT LET'S BE ENTIRELY CLEAR
HERE A RESOLUTION OF APPRECIATION MEANS NOTHING IF
THE CITY GUTS THE ACTUAL INFRASTRUCTURE KEEPING THOSE
SAME SURVIVORS ALIVE THEN BY THE NUMBERS ALONE THIS
EXECUTIVE BUDGET DIRECTLY THREATENS OUR AGING POPULATIONS
WITH DEEP ROLLBACKS $850,000 CUT TO SLASHES COMMUNITY HEALTH
ACCESS POINTS BY 6.6% AND STRIPS CLINICAL RESOURCES
FROM STRAIGHT HITTING THE EXACT GENERATION THAT BUILT OUR
SAFETY NET 1.5 MILLION CUT TO HARM REDUCTION TO DEFUND
SUBSTANCE ABUSE SUBSTANCE USE NAVIGATORS AND VITAL NARCAN
DISTRIBUTION WHEN LIVES ARE ON THE LINE MILLIONS MORE
THREATENS THE LIFELINES LIKE LION MARTIN LYRIC AND CARE FOR
HOMELESS YOUTH. YOUTH IT MAY 2020 THIS BOARD
OFFICIALLY ADOPTED OUR PRINCIPLES BINDING THE CITY TO
A COMMITMENT OF MEANINGFUL COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT
AND STAKEHOLDER LED PUBLIC HEALTH SAFETY POLICY.
NEARLY 75% OF SAN FRANCISCANS LIVING WITH HIV ARE OVER 50.
WE SURVIVED THE WORST OF THE EPIDEMIC.
OUR COMMUNITY EXPLICITLY DEMANDS THAT YOU PROTECT THE
VULNERABLE, NOT BALANCE THE BUDGET ON OUR BACKS.
THANK YOU FOR THE AWARENESS DAY.
AND PLEASE VOTE YES ON ITEM 19 BUT HOLD THE LINE ON YOUR OWN
COMMITMENTS REJECT THESE BUDGET CUTS AND FULLY RESTORE THE
FUNDING. >> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. WELCOME.
NEXT SPEAKER. >> GOOD AFTERNOON SUPERVISORS
AND THANK YOU SUPERVISOR CHAN FOR INTRODUCING THIS RESOLUTION
AND TO ALL THE OTHER CO-SPONSORS WHO ARE
CO-SPONSORING THIS RESOLUTION RECOGNIZING OUR LONG TERM
SURVIVOR COMMUNITY AND THE NEEDS OF THOSE AGING WITH HIV
AS AN EPICENTER. WHEN THE HIV CRISIS FIRST
STARTED EMERGING, SAN FRANCISCO HAS ALWAYS LED ON SERVING OUR
COMMUNITY. MANY LONG TERM SURVIVORS FACE
COMPLEX PTSD INCREASED ISOLATION, COMPLEX
CO-MORBIDITIES THAT REQUIRE SPECIALIZED CARE.
AS THE COMMUNITY CONTINUES TO AGE, IT'S MORE CRITICAL THAN
EVER THAT WE ENSURE THAT THESE SPECIALIZED SERVICES ARE
PROTECTED. WE MUST CONTINUE TO LISTEN TO
LONG TERM SURVIVORS, ENSURE THAT THEY HAVE THE SUPPORT THAT
THEY NEED. WE ARE DEEPLY INDEBTED TO THE
WORK THIS GENERATION HAS ACCOMPLISHED IN TRANSFORMING
PUBLIC HEALTH AND HOW IT'S DELIVERED.
>> WE ARE WITHIN STRIKING DISTANCE OF ENDING HIV
TRANSMISSIONS IN SAN FRANCISCO AND THIS IS ONE OF THE MOST
INCREDIBLE LEGACIES OF OUR LONG TERM SURVIVOR COMMUNITY AND THE
PUBLIC HEALTH SYSTEM THAT THEY HELPED BRING INTO BEING HERE
IN SAN FRANCISCO WE HAVE LEARNED SEXUAL HEALTH AS A
HUMAN RIGHT NOT A LINE ITEM TO BE CUT.
THE MAYOR'S BUDGET CUTS TO HIV PREVENTION RISK CRITICAL
INFRASTRUCTURE THAT PROP UP A CROWN JEWEL IN OUR PUBLIC
HEALTH SYSTEM. WE ARE LOOKING TO THIS BOARD
FOR LEADERSHIP IN PUSHING BACK AGAINST THESE CUTS WE MUST
HONOR THE LEGACY OF PUBLIC HEALTH OUR LONG TERM SURVIVORS
HAVE FOUGHT FOR AND CONTINUE THAT FIGHT BY ENSURING THAT THE
PREVENTION SYSTEMS THEY'VE BROUGHT INTO EXISTENCE CONTINUE
THAT HIV TRANSMISSION RATES DROP AND THAT WE ENSURE THAT
THEY AS OUR LONG TERM SURVIVOR COMMUNITY GET THE SERVICES
AND SUPPORT THEY NEED TO AGE WITH DIGNITY HERE IN THE CITY
THEY LOVE AND CALL HOME. >> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. WELCOME TO THE NEXT SPEAKER.
>> GOOD EVENING SUPERVISORS. THANKS FOR HEARING ALL OF US
OUT. I'M ROBERT HILL BURGESS.
I'M A PHYSICIAN AT SAN FRANCISCO GENERAL HOSPITAL
AND I'M HERE TO PROVIDE PUBLIC COMMENT AN ITEM NUMBER 23 I'M
NOT SPEAKING ON BEHALF OF UCSF BUT RATHER AS AN INDIVIDUAL
AND ALSO ON BEHALF OF THE HEALTH FOR ALL COALITION.
>> I'M HERE TO ASK FOR YOUR SUPPORT FOR ITEM 23 WHICH IS
THE RESOLUTION SUPPORTING CALIFORNIA STATE SENATE BILL
1422 ON MEDI-CAL ELIGIBILITY. THANK YOU SUPERVISOR MEHMOOD
FOR SPONSORING THIS BILL OR THIS RESOLUTION AND SUPERVISOR
SAUTER CHAN AND WALTON FOR BEING CO-SPONSORS.
>> SORRY IF I'M MISSING ANYONE ELSE.
WE REALLY APPRECIATE ALL OF YOUR SUPPORT.
CURRENTLY BECAUSE OF THE H.R. ONE AND STATE MEDI-CAL CUTS,
SAN FRANCISCO COULD POTENTIALLY SEE THOUSANDS OF RESIDENTS LOSE
ACCESS TO FULL SCOPE MEDI-CAL IN JANUARY 2025 A MEDICAL
ENROLLMENT FREEZE WAS IMPOSED SUCH THAT ADULTS OVER 19 WITH
UNSATISFACTORY IMMIGRATION STATUS COULD NO LONGER ENROLL
IN MEDI-CAL. >> WE ARE ALREADY SEEING
PATIENTS FALL THROUGH THE CRACKS.
>> RECENTLY I TRIED TO FOLLOW UP WITH A PATIENT WITH LIVER
DISEASE AFTER HIS HOSPITAL DISCHARGE.
HE COULDN'T COME TO CLINIC BECAUSE HIS COVERAGE HAD LAPSED
AND AS AN UNDOCUMENTED ADULT HE COULD NOT REENROLL.
MY TEAM HELPED HIM APPLY FOR HEALTHY SAN FRANCISCO BUT HIS
CARE WAS DELAYED AND DELAYS LIKE THIS INCREASE THE RISK THE
PATIENTS END UP BACK IN THE HOSPITAL SICKER.
>> UNFORTUNATELY GOVERNOR NEWSOM'S MAY BUDGET REVISION
CONTINUES TO ADVANCE CUTS TO HEALTH CARE FOR OUR STATE'S
MOST VULNERABLE IMMIGRANT COMMUNITIES.
IN CONTRAST, SB 14 22 WITH SUNSET ENROLLMENT RESTRICTIONS
AND IT HAS PASSED THE SENATE APPROPRIATIONS COMMITTEE BUT
WE'VE BEEN TOLD THAT COUNTY LEVEL SUPPORT COULD REALLY HELP
PUSH THIS THROUGH. >> SO IN ORDER TO PRESERVE
PREVENTATIVE HEALTH CARE FOR ALL SAN FRANCISCANS AND IN
ORDER TO NOT OVERBURDEN OUR HEALTHY SAN FRANCISCO PLAN, I
HOPE THAT YOU WILL SUPPORT THIS RESOLUTION.
>> THANKS SO MUCH. THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
>> NEXT SPEAKER. >> GOOD EVENING SUPERVISORS.
MY NAME IS BRETT MARTINEZ. I AM BOTH A DISTRICT FIVE
RESIDENT OF 20 YEARS AND THE SENIOR WELLNESS PROGRAM MANAGER
AT BOOKER T WASHINGTON ENSURING OUR OLDER ADULTS HAVE A PLACE
TO COME THAT IS CULTURALLY RESPONSIVE KEEPS THEM OUT OF
SOCIAL ISOLATION AND MOST IMPORTANTLY OFFERS AN
INTERGENERATIONAL SPACE ESPECIALLY FOR THOSE WITHOUT
FAMILY IN SAN FRANCISCO. WE NEED THE BOARD OF
SUPERVISORS TO SCHEDULE THE LEASE AGREEMENT FOR LITTLE HUTS
ON TIME AND STOP THE DELAY. OUR COMMUNITY WANTS AND DEPENDS
ON THESE IMPORTANT SUMMER PROGRAMS FOR YOUTH TO START ON
TIME. YOUR DELAY IN DECISION WILL
COST VULNERABLE WORKING FAMILIES TO LOSE THEIR CHILD
CARE AND FORCED MORE THAN 60 TEENS TO LOSE THEIR SUMMER JOBS
AS WELL AS THE EDUCATORS WHO SUPPORT THEM ALL.
HISTORY HAS SHOWN THAT WHEN THE DOORS OF POPULAR INSTITUTIONS
AND LOCAL BUSINESSES IN THE FILLMORE CLOSE THEY DO NOT
RETURN. WE SIMPLY CANNOT ALLOW THAT
PATTERN TO REPEAT ITSELF. PLEASE PLEASE SUPPORT THIS
AGREEMENT. NOT ONLY DOES THE COMMUNITY
NEED IT, OUR CITY DOES TOO. I WOULD ALSO LIKE TO ADD THAT I
AM SUPPORTIVE OF ALL THE PROGRAMS HERE ADVOCATING
AGAINST FACING, AGAINST AND FACING THE MAYOR'S PROPOSED
BUDGET CUTS INCLUDING OUR OWN SENIOR WELLNESS PROGRAM.
>> THANK YOU FOR YOUR TIME AND CONSIDERATION.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. >> NEXT SPEAKER.
>> GOOD EVENING. MY NAME IS JEANIE HAGLER AND I
AM HERE IN SUPPORT OF BOOKER T. STABILIZATION OF L.A. HEAL
HURTS COMMUNITY CENTER. >> I'M ASKING YOU TO KEEP L.A.
HEAL OPEN. WE NEED OUR SERVICES TO
CONTINUE TO SUPPORT THE COMMUNITY FOR THE FAMILIES.
A PLACE WHERE THE KIDS CAN CAN GET SUMMER JOBS AS WELL AS
LEARNING CENTER NEEDS PROVIDE STRUCTURE IN THEIR LIVES
AND LEARNING IMPORTANT SKILLS TO HELP FURTHER THEIR
EDUCATION. AGAIN, I SAY THAT WE KEEP L.A.
HEAL COMMUNITY CENTER OPEN. THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. NEXT SPEAKER.
>> GOOD AFTERNOON EVERYONE. MY NAME IS ELAINE SAMUELS FROM
DISTRICT FIVE, A RETIRED PUBLIC HEALTH NURSE.
BUT THE COUNTY AND CITY OF SAN FRANCISCO AND I'M HERE
IN REPRESENTING BOOKER T WASHINGTON BUDDY WASHINGTON
PROVIDE US WITH A HUMAN CONNECTION.
IT BONDS COMMUNITY TOGETHER. IT HAS THE INTEGRATION STORY TO
TELL TO OUR COMMUNITY TO KEEP OUR COMMUNITY TOGETHER, FORMING
NEW RELATIONSHIPS, SHARED HUMAN EXPERIENCES AND UNIFICATION.
I AM IN AGREEMENT TO KEEP BOOKER T WASHINGTON
IN CONNECTION WITH THE L.A. HEAL HUTCH PROGRAM BECAUSE THAT
PROGRAM PROVIDE ME STABILITY INVITED ME WITH CONNECTION
AND I'M IN ALSO IN THE SENIOR WELLNESS PROGRAM.
I'M 74 YEARS OLD AND I AM ALIVE AND WELL AND GOING TO MY NEXT
JOURNEY THE NEW BOOKER T WASHINGTON.
SO PLEASE HELP US AND MAKE THAT HAPPEN.
>> THANK YOU. >> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS
. >> WELCOME TO THE NEXT SPEAKER
. MY NAME IS TORI SPRAGUE AND I'M
A DISASTER WEEK FIVE RESIDENTS. I WAS RAISED IN FILLMORE
AND I'M ENCOURAGING THE TRANSITION OF BOOKER T
WASHINGTON INTO ELLIOT HIRSCH COMMUNITY CENTER.
AL HILL HUTCH WAS THE FIRST AFRICAN-AMERICAN BOARD OF
SUPERVISOR. THE HUB IN THE FILLMORE NEEDS
TO STAY OPEN. IT'S A PLACE THAT I GREW UP
IN AND I HAVE THE PRIVILEGE THAT MY CHILDREN NOT ONLY WENT
THERE FOR SUMMER PROGRAMS BUT ALSO THEY ARE OLD ENOUGH TO NOW
WORK THERE. KELLEY HILL HUTCH COMMUNITY
CENTER NEEDS TO REMAIN OPEN. THE FILLMORE HAS ALREADY LOST
SO MUCH WE CANNOT CONTINUE TO HAVE THESE FILLMORE ACTION
PLANNING MEETINGS AND THE VOICES OF THE COMMUNITY NOT
BEING HEARD. >> ALSO GROWING UP IN SAN
FRANCISCO. >> I HAVE WITNESSED THAT
PROGRAMS IN CERTAIN COMMUNITIES ARE NOT AVAILABLE TO YOUTH
UNLESS YOU GET IN TROUBLE. >> I WORK FOR SAN FRANCISCO
UNIFIED SCHOOL DISTRICT. I'VE CAME THROUGH THE FOSTER
CARE SYSTEM. >> I CAME THROUGH THE JUVENILE
JUSTICE SYSTEM AND I IT IS IMPERATIVE THAT WE KEEP ELIHU
HUTCH COMMUNITY CENTER OPEN SO THAT OUR CHILDREN HAVE A PLACE
TO GO AND NOT ONLY OUR CHILDREN ,OUR SENIORS AS WELL.
>> IT NEEDS TO BE A COMMUNITY HUB AS IT WAS BEFORE AND I
BELIEVE THAT BOOKER T WASHINGTON TAKING OVER THE
LEAST OF LITTLE HUTCH COMMUNITY CENTER CAN FULFILL WHAT WE NEED
IN OUR COMMUNITY. >> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS
. WELCOME TO THE NEXT SPEAKER.
>> REVEREND BROWN, WELCOME. >> MR. PRESIDENT, MADAM CLERK,
MEMBERS OF THE BOARD, PLEASE HEAR ME.
>> EACH OF YOU HAS SAT IN THOSE SEATS WHERE YOU ARE SITTING NOW
. WHEN I SERVED ON THIS BOARD I
RISE SIMPLY TO SAY IN MISSISSIPPI WHERE I CAME
FROM AS AN OLD ADAGE THAT SAYS YOU CAN'T JUNK ST WITH A
CROOKED STICK AND YOU CAN CHUNK STRAIGHT WITH A CROOKED STICK.
>> LET ME SAY RESPECTFULLY AS WE CONSIDER THE MATTER WHAT IS
TO HAPPEN AT BOOKER T OR WHAT'S HAPPENED TO HAPPEN AT LITTLE
HUTCH? I BEG YOU TO UNDERSTAND THAT
ALL THE TRUTH IS NOT BEING TOLD .
AND I RISE AS A PASTOR OF THIS DR. BAPTIST CHURCH FOR NEARLY
50 YEARS TO SPEAK THE TRUTH. THE GOOD BOOKS AIRS AND YOU
SHALL KNOW THE TRUTH. >> AND THIS TRUTH SHALL SET YOU
FREE. AND THE TRUTH IS THERE HAS BEEN
SOME IN SIGHT DEALING STRAIGHT UP ON THIS MEASURE.
>> THERE HAS BEEN A GOOD TALK ABOUT COMMUNITY.
BUT EVERYBODY WAS NOT INCLUDED. WE WERE EXCLUDED.
>> WE KNOW AND THAT THE SPEAKERS WHO CAME PREVIOUS THEY
UNDERSTAND. PLEASE I AM NOT SAYING YOU DO
NOT RECEIVE GOOD MEASURES AT BOOKER T.
>> THAT'S NOT THE ISSUE. WELL THE LEADERSHIP OF BOOKER T
HAS REFUSED TO MEET WITH THE BLACK COMMUNITY INCLUDING THE
BLACK FAITH LEADERSHIP. >> AND THE QUESTION BECOMES WHY
? >> WHO IS THE MOTIVE?
THAT HAS HAPPENED. >> AND THERE ARE INDIVIDUALS
WHO ARE SHAKING THEIR HEADS TO SAY IT'S STRANGE THAT THE
LEADERSHIP REFUSED A PLAN. THERE WAS ADVANCE.
>> WHAT WAS THEIR PLAN? THAT THERE WILL BE JOINT
LEADERSHIP. >> AND THERE'S ONE PERSON OF
INTEGRITY A PERSON OF SKILL WHO WAS RECOMMENDED AND THE
LEADERSHIP KNOWS ABOUT IT. >> WELL, THAT LEADERSHIP SAID
NO. NO.
AND THE QUESTION BECOMES WHY? >> WHY?
>> THE AFRICAN PROVERB SAYS IF YOU WANT TO GO FAST, GO ALONE.
BUT IF YOU WANT TO GO FAR, GO TOGETHER.
>> AND MEMBERS OF THE BOARD DON'T ADOPT THIS MEASURE UNTIL
YOU SEND THE MESSAGE TO THE LEADERSHIP OF BOOKER T THAT YOU
MUST GO TOGETHER ON THE PLAN THAT THE COMMUNITY RECOMMENDED
IN THE FIRST PLACE. >> THAT'S WHAT IT'S ALL ABOUT.
WE'VE HAD TOO MUCH DIVISION. >> BY INTENT AND BY ACCIDENT
IN OUR BLACK COMMUNITY. THAT'S WHY OUR POPULATION IS
DOWN FROM 15% NOW DOWN TO 4% IN THIS TOWN.
AND WE SAY, REVEREND BROWN, YOU'RE GETTING ME IN TROUBLE.
>> AS A FORMER MEMBER OF THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS, I GET
THREE MINUTES AND YOU KNOW THAT, MR. CHAIRMAN, WE'RE WELL
PAST THAT. >> MAYBE WRAP IT UP IN THIS
RACE TO. >> MR. PRESIDENT, DON'T DIVIDE
THIS COMMUNITY. WE CAN HAVE THIS L.
STAY OVER OPEN. I WAS THERE WHEN THAT WAS THE
GROUNDBREAKING. I WAS AROUND DIANNE FEINSTEIN,
FORMER MAYOR OF THE CITY WITH TOWNSEND AND OTHERS.
AND WE WENT TO WASHINGTON D.C. AND THAT IS A FACT.
>> AND NOTHING MADE UP. ALL WE'RE SAYING LET'S BE
DRIVEN BY THE TRUTH AND NOT INSIDE DEALING AWAY.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH. THANK YOU, REVEREND BROWN.
>> HOLD YOUR APPLAUSE PLEASE. THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS HAS A
BOARD RULE WHICH ALLOWS PRIVILEGE OF THE FLOOR TO BE
GRANTED AND THE BOARD GAVE IT TO FORMER MEMBER OF THIS BOARD
OF SUPERVISORS IS REVEREND AMOS BROWN.
>> CAN WE HEAR FROM THE NEXT SPEAKER, PLEASE?
>> WE ARE SETTING THE TIMER FOR TWO MINUTES.
THANK YOU. I'M GOING TO WANT TO SUBMIT A
COUPLE OF DOCUMENTS FOR RECORD PLEASE.
AND I'VE GOT COPIES FOR THE MEMBERS OF THE BOARD AS WELL.
>> THANK YOU. THANK YOU.
THAT'S A HARD ACT. A TOUGH ACT TO FOLLOW.
I'M GOING TO SPEAK A LITTLE TRUTH HERE AS WELL.
MY NAME IS LISA DAGES. I'M A RESIDENT OF DISTRICT FOUR
COMMUNITY LEADER, AN ACTIVIST AND A PRINCIPAL OFFICER OF THE
EQUAL FIRE PROTECTION FOR ALL COMMITTEE.
I'D LIKE TO SUBMIT INTO THE RECORD WRITINGS FROM TWO PUBLIC
SERVANTS WHO HAVE DONE MORE FOR THE CITY OF SAN FRANCISCO THAN
ANYONE IN THIS CHAMBER. NO DISRESPECT BUT I CALL IT
LIKE I SEE IT. >> THE FIRST IS FROM FRANK
BLACKBURN, ASSISTANT CHIEF SAN FRANCISCO FIRE DEPARTMENT
RETIRED WRITTEN SHORTLY BEFORE HIS DEATH LAST SEPTEMBER.
THE TITLE OF WHICH IS LESSONS FROM LOS ANGELES ARE WE CAPABLE
OF LEARNING FROM THEIR LACK OF PLANNING?
FRANK SERVED AS A FIREFIGHTER AND IN COMMAND STAFF AT SFD FOR
35 YEARS AFTER HIS RETIREMENT. FRANK CONTINUED TO ADVOCATE FOR
THE EXPANSION OF THE HEAVY WATER SUPPLY SYSTEM.
>> THE SECOND PIECE IS FROM FORMER SUPERVISOR STATE SENATOR
AND RETIRED JUDGE QUENTIN KOPP. A PERSONAL FRIEND OF FRANK
BLACKBURN. JUDGE COP'S PIECE WAS PUBLISHED
IN THE EXAMINER AT THE LOCAL 798 NEWSLETTER AND IN THE WIND
. NOW FOR MY COMMENTS THERE ARE
TWO THINGS THAT ARE NECESSARY TO FIGHT FIRE, WATER
AND FIREFIGHTERS. NOWHERE IS MORE TRUE THAN WITH
FIGHTING POST-EARTHQUAKE CONFLAGRATIONS AND FIRESTORMS.
I BELIEVE IT'S A GOOD THING TO PROTECT OUR FIREFIGHTERS,
POLICE OFFICERS AND FIRST RESPONDERS.
EVERYONE DOES. BUT IF THEY ARE FORCED TO WATCH
THE CITY BURN, TO WATCH OUR HOMES, BUSINESSES AND OUR VERY
LIVES PERISH IN THE GREAT CONFLAGRATIONS AND FIRESTORMS,
WHAT WILL BE THE POINT OF ANY OF IT WHEN THE NEXT MASSIVE
EARTHQUAKE HITS SAN FRANCISCO? THE FIRESTORM WILL COME AND IF
WE ARE NOT PREPARED TO MAKE NO MISTAKE WE ARE NOT PREPARED NOR
ARE WE GETTING PREPARED EVERY DAY.
WE DON'T HAVE THE BIG ONE IS ONE DAY CLOSER TO THE BIG ONE.
HOW MANY FIREFIGHTERS WILL PAY FOR THE CITY'S HUBRIS WITH
THEIR LIVES? HOW MANY RESIDENTS?
RESIDENTS ARE MORE THAN 15 UNPROTECTED NEIGHBORHOODS
AND SOUTHERN NEIGHBORHOOD. SIX YEARS.
BROKEN PROMISES THREE BONDS 1.44 BILLION BORROWED
AND SPENT. ZERO HIGH PRESSURE HYDRANTS.
ZERO MILES OF FIREFIGHTING MAIN PLACED IN THE ALMOST TWO THIRDS
OF THE CITY THAT'S UNPROTECTED. WE NEED A RESET.
>> IT MUST BE HAPPEN NOW. THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
>> WE WELCOME THE NEXT SPEAKER. OH, THANK YOU.
>> THANKS FOR LOOKING OUT FOR ME.
>> GOOD EVENING, EVERYONE. MY NAME IS SHANI WYATT AND I AM
PART OF K'ICHE CARES AS WELL AS ASSAF HTC.
I AM HERE ON BEHALF OF MYSELF AND BOTH OF THE ORGANIZATIONS
TO SUPPORT BOOKER T WASHINGTON AND THE 13 MONTH LEASE TO
OBTAIN THIS SPACE. IT WILL WORK.
>> THIS IS VERY VITAL FOR THE COMMUNITY.
>> IT IS NOT TO DIVIDE THE COMMUNITY.
IT IS TO CONTINUE TO TO LET THE COMMUNITY PROSPER THROUGH THE
RESOURCES IS TO MAKE SURE THAT THE FAMILIES IN THE CHILDREN
WHO HAVE BEEN A PART OF ALI HILL FOR ALL OF THESE YEARS
CONTINUE TO OBTAIN THIS SPACE THAT THEY CONTINUE TO THRIVE.
WITHOUT THIS AND SUMMER APPROACHING, SUMMER JOBS WILL
BE LOST FOR THE TEENS. >> SUMMER JOBS WILL BE LOST FOR
THE ADULTS AND ON A PERSONAL NOTE, TWO YEARS AGO WHEN MY SON
PASSED AWAY OF ASTHMA WHICH LED TO HIM HAVING A HEART ATTACK,
SHAKIRA IN HER TEEN PULLED UP TO MY HOUSE TO MY LIVING ROOM
WITH ONE OF THE WORST TIMES OF MY LIFE AND HELPED ME TO PLAN
ARRANGE THE HOMEGOING FOR MY 22 YEAR OLD SON WHO WAS A SENSE
FRANCISCO NATIVE. THAT WAS ONE OF THE WORST TIMES
IN MY LIFE AND WITHOUT THEM WITHOUT THE SUPPORT OF THEM I
DON'T KNOW WHERE I WOULD BE. >> I WOULD PROBABLY BE IN THE
CASKET WITH HIM BECAUSE LOSING A CHILD IS SOMETHING THAT I
DON'T WISH UPON ANYONE BUT ONCE AGAIN WITH THEIR SUPPORT.
I WAS ABLE TO MAKE IT THROUGH THAT TOUGH TIME AND I AM
STANDING HERE IN FRONT OF YOU TO THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS
WHICH YOU YOU LOVED. >> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS
AND I SAY THANK YOU. >> WELCOME TO THE NEXT SPEAKER
. >> GOOD EVENING BOARD OF
SUPERVISORS. THIS IS NEW FOR ME.
>> I'M NOT GOING TO GO INTO THE SPEECH THAT I WAS SUPPOSED TO
SAY. I THINK A LOT OF US FROM A
BOOKER T WE SAID THIS SPEECH SO I'M JUST GOING TO SAY STANDING
HERE LOOKING OUT. I REMEMBER I AM A YOU KNOW I'M
A I'M PART OF THE SENIOR CLUB THAT'S GOING ON THERE AND I
HAPPENED TO BE LOOKING OUT THE WINDOW ONE DAY AND I SAW ALL
THESE LITTLE BITTY CHILDREN PLAYING OUT IN THE BACK AND YOU
SEE THE CHILDREN RUNNING THROUGH THERE.
YOU SEE THE TEENAGE YEARS. >> WE HAVE THE MOST FUN IN THE
SENIOR CLUB ESPECIALLY WHEN WE DO BINGO.
AND SO THIS IS I WANT TO SAY THIS IS A PERSONAL FOR ME AND I
CAN'T THINK OF ANYTHING ELSE TO SAY EXCEPT FOR I LOOK OUT AND I
LOOK INTO THE YOU GUY SITTING THERE AND I THINK ABOUT THE
LITTLE CHILDREN THAT WERE RUNNING AROUND AND NOT ONLY
THAT WE HELP SO MANY PEOPLE FROM DIFFERENT BACKGROUNDS
AND DIFFERENT NATIONALITIES HIS AND YOU KNOW WHICH FOOD AND THE
HELP WITH THE DAY CARE AND THE SCHOOLING THAT GOES ON IN THE
SUMMERTIME JOBS YOU KNOW SO I'M LOOKING FORWARD TO I DON'T KNOW
MUCH ABOUT POLITICS AND THINGS BUT I'M LOOKING FORWARD TO THE
CONVERSION OF BOOKER T L HEAL HUTCH AND I JUST THINK THAT WE
JUST NEED TO MOVE FORWARD AND I THINK YOU CAN'T REALLY KNOW
ABOUT THE CUTTING OF ANYTHING UNLESS YOU COME AND YOU
EXPERIENCE IT WOULD BE SUCH A GREAT THING IF SOME OF YOU
COULD COME SOMETIMES AND BE BINGO IN WITH US OR EAT DINNER
WITH US AND TO KNOW REALLY WHAT GOES ON THERE.
>> OH THAT'S MUST BE YOUR THANK YOU.
>> WELL THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
WELCOME TO THE NEXT SPEAKER. HI.
MY NAME IS RYAN BABBITT. I'M THE ASSOCIATED RECTOR OF
EXPANDED LEARNING ENRICHMENT AT BOOKER T.
I'VE BEEN THERE FOR SIX YEARS AND I CERTAINLY HAVEN'T SEEN
THE IMPACT THAT BOOKER T HAS DONE IN COMMUNITY.
I'VE SEEN THE LEADERSHIP THAT SHAKIR HAS BROUGHT OVER THE
LAST SIX YEARS. WHEN I STARTED THERE WE ONLY
HAD SEVEN STAFF AND NOW WE SIT AT 57.
BOOKER T HAS BEEN DOING HIS WORK FOR 107 YEARS AND EVEN
THOUGH THIS IS NEW TO THE COMMUNITY ABOUT AS GOING OVER
AND TAKING OVER AT LEAST THAT EARLY HILL 40 YEARS AGO WHEN
ELLIE HILL STARTED THERE THERE EDDIE LEFT WAS A CASE MANAGER
AT BOOKER T FOR 20 YEARS AND SO WE SHARED A BOARD WITH THEM
AND SO THIS IS JUST AS DOING FULL CIRCLE AND STEPPING IN AND
MAKING SURE THAT WE CAN SUPPORT OUR FAMILIES, OUR SENIORS
AND OUR YOUTH AND MAKE SURE THEY HAVE A SAFE THIRD SPACE TO
GO TO. I'M JUST TIRED OF BURYING OUR
BABIES AND I JUST WANT TO MAKE SURE THAT OUR BABIES HAVE A
SAFE PLACE TO GO TO DURING THE SUMMER AND FOR AFTERSCHOOL AS
WELL. SO AGAIN I PLEASE ENCOURAGE ALL
THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS PLEASE PASS THE LEASE SO THAT WAY WE
CAN MAKE SURE WE START SERVICES FOR 95 K THROUGH EIGHT AND 60
TEENS ON JUNE 6TH 15. >> THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. WELCOME.
NEXT SPEAKER HELLO MY NAME IS MARVELOUS LUKE LUCAS.
>> I WORK WITH BOOKER T WASHINGTON COMMUNITY SERVICE
CENTER. I AM UTMOST FOR BOOKER T
WASHINGTON STEWARDING ALLIE HILL HUTCH AND LOOK, LET'S JUST
STICK THE BLINDS DOWN. IT'S FOR ONE YEAR AND SIX
MONTHS THESE PEOPLE GET TO BID FOR IT LIKE EVERYONE ELSE RIGHT
NOW THEY'RE DEADLOCKED ON IF THEY DON'T COME TO THE TABLE
THEN NOTHING HAPPENS. >> WHO WOULD SAY THAT ABOUT THE
COMMUNITY AND WHAT'S AT RISK WE'RE TALKING ABOUT THEY'RE
READY TO SAY STOP THE PROGRAM. WE'RE TALKING 60 CHILDREN TO
ALL KINDS OF FAMILIES WHO WOULD TAKE THAT POSITION.
IT'S NOT A GOOD POSITION TO TAKE WHEN THEY TALK ABOUT
BACKDOOR DEALS. >> HOLD ON, BROTHER.
I'M I'M STIRRING IT UP. LET ME START UP NOW I'M A START
UP BROTHER WHEN YOU TALK ABOUT THE PERSON THAT I WON'T PUT THE
PERSON'S NAME OUT THERE WHEN YOU TALK ABOUT THE PERSON WHO
WANTS TO CO EXECUTIVE DIRECT WOULD SECURE THAT GUY HAVE AN
OPPORTUNITY THAT BACK ROOM DOOR DEAL IF YOU WANT TO CALL THOSE
DEALINGS I WAS THERE OTHER PEOPLE WERE THERE HE SAID THESE
WORDS I DON'T HAVE THE THE CAPACITY TO SECURE HAS THE TEAM
AND FRANKLY IS SOMETHING I DON'T WANT NOW NOW THEY'RE
UPLIFTING THEIR CHAMPION THE GUY WHO DIDN'T EVEN WANT TO
TAKE THE FIGHT BECAUSE THE FIGHT IS LOOKING LIKE IT COULD
BE SAVED AND EVERYONE WANTS TO COME IN ON WIN.
THAT'S NOT WHO AND PEOPLE THE REASON AND YOU GUYS PROBABLY
DON'T LIKE WHEN PEOPLE COME IN WHO REALLY WANTS TO MEET
WITH PEOPLE WHO ARE IN FIGHTING ALL THE TIME YOU WILL NEVER GET
ANYTHING DONE. >> BUT SHE MEETS THESE PEOPLE
PLANS ON MEETING THESE PEOPLE BUT THAT'S IT.
>> THEY COME UP WITH ANOTHER REASON I WILL SAY THIS I CAME
BY A STUDY FROM HARVARD UNIVERSITY AND IT SAID THAT
BLACK ORGANIZATIONS THAT WERE CLOSED DOORS WERE 6800 TIMES
POSSIBLE NEVER OPENING AGAIN. >> THANK YOU FOR YOUR TIME.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. WELCOME TO THE NEXT SPEAKER
HOUR GO BEHIND THAT. >> HELLO MY NAME IS KAT SWIRE.
I AM THE SENIOR WELLNESS COORDINATOR AT BOOKER T AND YET
I DON'T COME HERE TODAY AS AN EMPLOYEE.
I COME HERE TODAY AS A MOTHER, AUNT AND A FORMER EDUCATOR.
>> HAD I NOT HAD QUALITY CHILD CARE FOR MY 16 YEAR OLD TWINS I
MIGHT NOT BE EMPLOYED OR BE GAINFULLY EMPLOYED TODAY I AM
IN SUPPORT OF ELLIE HILL STABILIZATION PROJECT BECAUSE
NOT ONLY WILL IT PROVIDE QUALITY CARE FOR BABIES, IT
WILL PROVIDE A SAFETY NET FOR WORKING FAMILIES AND SINGLE
MOTHERS LIKE MYSELF. >> SOME OF YOU GUYS ARE
PARENTS, SOME OF YOU GUYS ARE GRANDPARENTS.
>> SOME OF YOU GUYS ARE AUNTS. THINK ABOUT THOSE BABIES
AND WHAT WOULD THEY DO IF YOU COULDN'T GO TO WORK OR YOU
DIDN'T KNOW WHAT YOU WERE GOING TO DO OR YOU HAD TO BRING YOUR
BABY TO WORK BECAUSE YOU DIDN'T HAVE SOMEWHERE FOR YOUR BABIES
TO GO. >> I REALLY, REALLY CONSIDER
MOVING FORWARD WITH THE LEASE BECAUSE IT WOULD NOT ONLY
PROVIDE QUALITY CARE AND SERVICE FOR OUR BABIES, IT
WOULD JUST PROVIDE A SAFETY NET FOR THOSE WHO LOOK LIKE ME,
TALK LIKE ME, WALK LIKE ME AND MAYBE LIKE YOU.
THANK YOU. >> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
WELCOME TO THE NEXT SPEAKER. >> GOOD EVENING.
FIRST GIVING HONOR TO GOD WHO'S THE HEAD OF MY LIFE?
>> MACCHIA WALK WATKINS FROM DISTRICT FIVE.
>> FIRST I WANT TO SAY TO MY COMMUNITY THAT WE DO NOT
DISAGREE MUCH ON WHAT'S GOING ON.
>> WE WANT THE HILL TO STAY OPEN AS WELL.
WE WANT THE BABIES TO BE FAIR WE DO NOT I REPEAT DO NOT WANT
ANYONE TO LOSE THEIR JOB. >> BUT WE'RE HERE BECAUSE THE
PROCESS WASN'T DONE RIGHT. >> THERE WERE BACK DOOR
AGREEMENTS AND WE'VE TALKED ERICA AND I WE'VE TALKED TO
BILAL AND OTHER SUPERVISORS AND AND PEOPLE ON A HUMAN
SOURCE COMMITTEE AND WHAT THEY DON'T KNOW IS THAT YOU YOU GUYS
HAVE OFFERED A COUPLE LEADERSHIP AND WE HAVE YOU
FIRST WHO'S A WHO IS A BLACK MAN NONPROFIT WHO CAN CALL HOME
CALL DIRECT WITH HER AND I DON'T UNDERSTAND WHY THAT IS
THE HEART SITUATION. >> HALL HE SHOWED THEY COULD
HOLD EACH OTHER ACCOUNTABLE. SO I'M SAYING PLEASE DON'T VOTE
ON THIS UNTIL WE COULD COME TO SOME KIND OF COLLABORATION
AND GET A COLE DIRECTOR IN THERE.
>> AND IF YOU GUYS ARE MORE TRANSPARENT WITH HOW YOU RUN
THINGS IN A CITY ARGUMENT YOU WOULDN'T BE LIKE THIS BUT THIS
IS WHAT YOU GUYS DO AS A CITY. >> YOU GUYS COME IN, YOU SPEW
ALL THESE IN THIS RHETORIC TO ONE SIDE THROUGH THINGS TO THE
OTHER SIDE AND HERE WE GO. >> WE'RE DIVIDED BUT WE'RE NOT
GOING TO BE DIVIDED. I LOVE ALL MY COMMUNITY BUT WE
JUST HAVE A DIFFERENCE OF AGREEMENT.
SO ONCE AGAIN WE I SUPPORT A COLE DIRECTOR AND IF YOU CAN'T
VOTE ON THAT I SAY DON'T VOTE UNTIL YOU CAN.
THANK YOU. THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
WELCOME TO THE NEXT SPEAKER. >> GOOD EVENING BOARD OF
SUPERVISORS. I ALSO WANT TO GIVE HONOR TO
THE LORD WHO'S THE HEAD OF MY LIFE AND I'M ERICA SCOTT.
I AM HERE AGAIN TO SHARE THE CONCERN AS TO WHY WE ARE EVEN
HERE AND IT WAS BECAUSE OF THE PREVIOUS LEADERSHIP AND WE
CAN'T JUST LOOK AT SIX MONTHS OR 13 MONTHS.
WE HAVE TO LOOK AT THE LONGEVITY OF OUR COMMUNITY.
WE HAVE LOST TEN YEARS OF OPERATION REGULAR OPERATION AT
LITTLE HUTCH COMMUNITY CENTER BECAUSE OF THE PREVIOUS
LEADERSHIP AND WE WANT TO MAKE SURE THAT THAT JUST DOESN'T
HAPPEN AGAIN. WE NEED SERIOUS ACCOUNTABILITY.
WE NEED TRANSPARENCY. AND THE WAY THAT THIS PROCESS
HAS HAPPENED HAS BEEN TOTALLY BEHIND CLOSED DOORS.
JESS, RECENTLY HAS IT BEEN BROUGHT TO THE PUBLIC?
BUT SO MUCH HAS BEEN DONE THAT I WAS ACTUALLY TOLD FROM
SOMEONE WHO WORKS IN THE MAYOR'S OFFICE NOT TO SAY
ANYTHING, NOT TO SAY ANYTHING TO MY COMMUNITY ABOUT AN
INSTITUTION THAT MEANS SO MUCH TO US WHICH IS CAHILL HODGE
COMMUNITY CENTER. SO WE ALL WANT THE SAME THING
BUT WE DON'T WANT TO FACE WHAT WE'RE GOING THROUGH RIGHT NOW
COURT PROCEEDINGS THAT ARE ABOUT TO TAKE PLACE BECAUSE OF
MISGUIDED LEADERSHIP. WE NEED TO MAKE SURE THAT
EVERYONE IS HELD ACCOUNTABLE AND THERE WERE SOME VERY CLOSE
DEALINGS WITH THE LEADERSHIP AT BOOKER T THAT WITH ELLA HILL
HUTCH. SO WE WANT ACCOUNTABILITY.
WE WANT TO MAKE SURE THAT THERE'S CHECKS AND BALANCES.
WE WANT TO MAKE SURE THAT OUR CHILDREN AND FAMILIES DON'T
HAVE TO FACE THIS AGAIN. >> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. WELCOME TO THE NEXT SPEAKER.
>> GOOD AFTERNOON. MY NAME IS DARBY VALES.
>> I'M HERE IN SUPPORT OF BOOKER T'S LEAD FOR ELLA HUTCH
HILL. I WORKED WITH K THROUGH TWO FOR
ABOUT TWO YEARS AND I JUST FEEL LIKE IT'S NOT FAIR TO THE KIDS
THAT I WORKED WITH BECAUSE EVEN SO THAT I'M CURRENTLY WORKING
WITH BOOKER T I GOT LUCKY. >> MY MOM WAS UNEMPLOYED AND I
DIDN'T HAVE A JOB SO WE WERE BOTH UNEMPLOYED.
>> I GOT LUCKY AND GOT HIRED ALOHA CHILL AND GOT THE
OPPORTUNITY TO WORK WITH KIDS. BEFORE THAT I DID WORK WITH
THEM UNDER THE HIGH SCHOOL PROGRAM AND I WAS LUCKY ENOUGH
TO DO A LOT OF INTERNSHIPS WITH THEM WITH UCSF AND I JUST THINK
THAT I WITH THE LITTLE TIME THAT I'VE BEEN WORKING WITH
BOOKER T, I FEEL LIKE THEY CAN DO SO MUCH MORE THAN WHAT WE
HAD LHO AND THEY CAN HELP SURPASS THAN WHAT WE HAD
AND MAKE IT WAY BETTER THAN WHAT WHAT IT WAS.
>> SO PLEASE HELP US OUT. >> I DON'T WANT TO CLOSE THE
BUILDING. I GREW UP IN MAYBE NOT FOR TOO
LONG BUT I DID GROW UP THERE FOR A GOOD AMOUNT OF TIME.
>> UM, SO PLEASE HELP US KEEP ELLA HOTEL COMMUNITY CENTER
OPEN. >> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. WELCOME TO THE NEXT SPEAKER.
>> HELLO. MY NAME IS FREDERICK CLAREMONT
AND I OVERSEE PROGRAMING FOR ADVOCACY WASHINGTON.
AND I AM GOING TO TRY TO KEEP THIS SHORT AND SWEET IN THAT
THIS IS A DAUNTING TASK THAT IS ABOUT TO BE UNDERTAKEN.
THERE WILL BE AN RFP PROCESS. SO IF ANYBODY WANTS TO APPLY
THEY CAN. BUT MORE IMPORTANTLY IT'S
ALMOST INSULTING TO EVEN IMPLY OR TO INNUENDOS THAT THE
PREVIOUS ADMINISTRATION OR THE PREVIOUS A COLLECTIVE IMPACT
THERE WAS ANY ASSOCIATION. WE HAVE BEEN GOING THROUGH
CONTRACT MONITORING AFTER CONTRACT MONITORING PROGRAM
AUDITS AND WE ARE STILL IN THAT SENSE.
>> AND SO DO NOT INSULT US. AND WE WILL LOOK FORWARD TO
THIS CONTINUED PARTNERSHIP AND THE IDEA THE IDEA THAT
SOMEONE CAN ACTUALLY BE A CO LEADER AT THE SAME LEVEL OF
BOOKER T IS ALSO INSULTING. WE ARE ABSORBING SO MUCH COST.
AND I LOOK FORWARD TO THIS CONTINUED DISCUSSION.
>> THANK YOU. THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
WE JUST ASK THAT THERE'S NO INTERRUPTION FROM THE PUBLIC
GALLERY WHILE SOMEONE IS SPEAKING PLEASE.
THANK YOU. >> WELCOME SIR.
WELL, I'M KIND OF YOUR GADFLY. I'M NOT HERE TO SUPPORT BOOKER
T OR NOT SUPPORT IT. MY SON WHO'S NOW IN HIS 50S,
WAS BUSED AROUND SAN FRANCISCO AND I KNOW HOW IMPORTANT
SCHOOLS AROUND THE CITY ARE IMPORTANT TO TO STUDENTS
GROWING UP. >> BUT ON MY GADFLY THING I
NOTICED THAT THE SUPERVISOR KAISER FROM DISTRICT NINE IS
ONCE AGAIN ABSENT. AND WE TALK ABOUT TRANSPARENCY.
I'M REALLY KIND OF PERPLEXED ON WHAT KIND OF LEGAL BASIS WE
HAVE FOR ALLOWING A SUPERVISOR NOT TO REPRESENT HER DISTRICT
AND ACTUALLY SIGN ON TO CERTAIN NOT ENDORSE CERTAIN RULES THAT
COME UP. I THINK THAT'S WRONG AND I
THINK THAT THE LET THE LEGAL DEPARTMENT OF THE CITY ARE TO
START INVESTING GATING THIS DISTRICT.
DISTRICT NINE IS NOT REPRESENTED.
WHAT'S GOING TO HAPPEN WHEN SHE COMES BACK?
I SAID AS SUDDENLY IS THERE GOING TO BE A MONTH OR THREE
MONTHS OF NOTHING BUT DISTRICT NINE?
CONGRATULATIONS FOR SERVICE TO DISTRICT NINE.
SHE'S MISSING OUT ON A LOT OF THINGS.
SO I'VE GOT 30S TO WIND UP BY SIDE JUST JOE ESKENAZI ADDRESS
THE COMMONWEALTH CLUB AND ESSENTIALLY IT WAS
EVERYBODY WAS GETTING ALONG JUST BOUGHT A SUPERVISOR
GETTING ALONG WITH THE MAYOR AND THE MAYOR WAS DOING
REAL WELL BUT NO MENTION WAS MADE EXCEPT THE ACKNOWLEDGMENT
THAT DISTRICT NINE HAD A SUPERVISOR ONCE.
SO LET'S GET A NEW DISTRICT NINE SUPERVISOR FOR DISTRICT
NINE. >> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS
. >> WELCOME TO THE NEXT SPEAKER
. MY NAME'S SHELLY AND I
REPRESENT THE WESTERN DISTRICT COMMUNITY.
>> SO WE WANT TO HEAR YOU BEST. CAN YOU SPEAK DIRECTLY INTO
THAT MICROPHONE PLEASE? >> HAVEN'T STARTED YOUR TIME
YET. I SAID MY NAME IS SHELLY.
I REPRESENT THE WEST IN ADDITION COMMUNITY AND I'M
HERE SPEAKING ON BEHALF HEARD AND YOU KNOW Y'ALL KEEP TALKING
ABOUT THE CHILDREN EARLY. YOU HEARD WHAT ABOUT MYSELF?
YOU KNOW I REMEMBER ELLIE WHO USED TO HELP ALL PEOPLE IT
WASN'T JUST NO CHILDREN. I WAS ABLE TO RUN NEAR IT 20 TO
20 YEARS OLD, 23 YEARS OLD AND GET HELP YOU KNOW, GET A
JOB, WHATEVER. YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN?
SO IT'S NOT ABOUT WHO PARTY TAKE OVER THE OWNERSHIP HERE
WAS ABOUT HOW Y'ALL DOING IN THE PROCESS THAT IT TOOK TO
BE DONE YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN? SO WE'RE JUST TRYING TO WE JUST
TRYING TO GET SOME TRANSPARENCY AND SOME SOME CLARITY ON WHO
ACTUALLY FINISHED COMING EARLY AND WHAT'S ACTUALLY GOING TO
HAPPEN BECAUSE IT CAN'T JUST BE FOR NO CHILDREN.
NO, I MIGHT WANT TO GO PLAY BASKETBALL.
I MIGHT WANT TO GO DO SOME AS I ONCE DID BEFORE YOU I MEAN
BECAUSE WE JUST SAW THE PROGRAM WE SEE NO WE DIDN'T SEE NO
BOOGIE TEAMS AND ALL THE OTHER TEAMS TRYING TO GETTING CLICKED
DOWN EARLY HERE AND MAKE IT OPEN TO WHERE'S THEY TRYING TO
DO NOW WE JUST WHAT WE JUST WATCHED HOW YOU FEEL WITH ALL
THESE PROGRAMS AROUND HERE THAT WAS IN CLOSE QUARTERS THEY JUST
WORKING WE WE WE DIDN'T WE DIDN'T SEE NO WE JUST SEE NO
THRIVING BOOGIE NO THRIVE IN LSU NO DRIVING NOTHING
AND LSU WAS FOR GUYS THAT DIDN'T GROW UP IN IN IN IN THE
GOOD AREAS LIKE THE PRESIDIO THAT'S WHAT THE GUYS THAT
PRESIDIO GO TO THE GUY THAT COME FROM THE PROJECTS WE GO TO
HOLLYWOOD IS A DIFFERENT ENVIRONMENT.
IT'S A DIFFERENT TYPE OF ENVIRONMENT WITH A DIFFERENT
TYPE OF STRUCTURE DOWN HERE FOR US THAT THAT WAS THERE, YOU
KNOW AND I WANT TO STAND YOUR GROUND JUST TURN IT FOR THE
KIDS. I WAS GOING TO BRING BOOKER T
WE'RE JUST DEALING WITH KIDS AND NOT KNOW THE WHOLE NO
COMMUNITY BECAUSE I WANT TO GO IN EARLY MYSELF AND PLAY
BASKETBALL AND DO SOME SOME TIME.
>> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS OR WELCOME TO OUR NEXT SPEAKER
. GOOD EVENING.
GOOD EVENING. THANK YOU.
YOU HAVE A MINCED DECISION TO MAKE BOOKER T WASHINGTON
STABILIZE HSIEN ELLA HILL HUTS WERE PREPARED FOR THE FIRST OF
ALL MY NAME IS KEVIN BROWN I'M THE DIRECTOR OF OPERATIONS
AND FACILITIES FOR BOOKER T WASHINGTON AND WE HAVE A HEAVY
LIFT AS WELL AS YOU HAVE A HEAVY LIFT WE ARE PREPARED TO
STEP IN AND DO THE WORK. IT WAS A NUMBER THAT WAS THROWN
OUT THERE A FEW MINUTES AGO BY THE STEAM BROTHER AND HE STATED
THAT 15% OF IT USED TO BE 15% OF BLACK POPULATION IN SAN
FRANCISCO. NOW DOWN TO 3%.
AND I JUST WANT TO JUST YOU KNOW, STATE I WAS ON YOUR WATCH
AND WE NEED TO DO BETTER. THERE WAS A TIME WHERE CERTAIN
TEAMS WERE SUCCESSFUL BUT NOW THERE'S A TIME THINGS NEED TO
CHANGE AND EVOLVE AND WE ARE PREPARED TO MAKE THAT MAKE THAT
CHANGE AND HELP WITH THAT EVOLUTION.
THE FILLMORE NEEDS TO BE STABILIZED BECAUSE NOT JUST
L.A. OR HUTCH AND OUR PRESENCE STEPPING INTO THAT SPACE
AND ACTIVATING THAT SPACE WILL IMPROVE THE COMMUNITY IMMENSELY
. >> ALSO STATING OUR OUR WORK I
MEAN AUDITS THE JUST THE GROWTH OF OUR YOUNG PEOPLE, THE GROWTH
OF OUR PROGRAMS IN THE COMMUNITY EXTENDED INTO L.A. OR
HUTCH WILL IMPROVE ELWELL HUTCH AS WELL AS THE FILLMORE WHICH
IS SOMETHING I BELIEVE EVERY PERSON WHO SITS BEHIND THESE
DESK WANT FOR SAN FRANCISCO. >> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. WELCOME TO THE NEXT SPEAKER.
>> HI. MY NAME'S ARLENE EDWARDS.
I'M A NATIVE OF SAN FRANCISCO, GREW UP IN GLENDALE HEIGHTS,
FOREST HILLS. MY FAMILY CAME TO SAN FRANCISCO
IN THE LATE 20S AND HAVE SUPPORTED THIS COMMUNITY AS
I'VE SEEN IT IN MY LIFETIME. IT TURNS 65 NEXT MONTH.
I'VE SEEN THE BLACK COMMUNITY KIND OF WITHER AND FLY OFF
MOSTLY TO THE EAST BAY AND OTHER PLACES BUT ANYTHING
YOU CAN DO TO SUPPORT THE CHILDREN, THE ADULTS, ALL THE
PEOPLE OF COLOR IN THIS COMMUNITY THAT HAVE DONE MANY
THINGS TO SUPPORT IN THEIR HARD WORK.
YOU KNOW, I HEARD ONE OF THE PEOPLE MENTIONED THAT THERE'S A
LOT OF SERVICES FOR CHILDREN WHO ARE HAVING TROUBLES BUT IF
YOU WANT TO BUILD A HEALTHY CHILD YOU NEED TO START WITH
THEM YOUNG AND SUPPORT THEM AND ALL THE GOOD THINGS AND LET
THEM KNOW THAT THAT IS A PATH OF LIFE FOR THEM AND I BELIEVE
L.A. HUTCHINS CENTER IS ONE OF THOSE
PLACES ALONG WITH BOOKER T WHO HAS DONE THAT IN THIS COMMUNITY
AND WE NEED TO FIND ANY WAY WE CAN TO KEEP IT OPEN, SUPPORT IT
AND NOT ALLOW THE STRONG HISTORY TO BE LOST BY NOT
SUPPORTING THE THE NEW THE YOUNG AND MAKE THAT SO PEOPLE
KNOW WHAT'S GONE ON IN THIS CITY AND AND IN THIS COUNTRY
WITH BLACK PEOPLE THAT THERE'S BEEN TRYING TO BE ERASED ALL
OVER SO NOT JUST IN THIS COUNTRY BUT EVERY COUNTRY BUT
SO WE NEED TO THINK ABOUT THAT AND PLEASE MY UNCLE WHO IS 101
JUST PASSED IT'S GOING TO BE HONORED AT THE END OF THIS
GERALD JOHNSON AND MY MOTHER WILHELMINA EDWARDS AND MY
GRANDMOTHER ANNA WHO SUPPORTED WHEN THE JAPANESE WERE PUT INTO
INTERNMENT SHE TOOK CARE OF THEIR BUSINESSES AND RETURNED
THEM TO THEM FOR THE PRICE THAT SHE BOUGHT THEM FROM THEM SO
THEY COULD HAVE MONEY WHILE THEY WERE IN CAMP.
AND THAT'S THE KIND OF SUPPORT WE NEED TO HAVE.
WE NEED PEOPLE LIFTING UP ALL OF THESE COMMUNITIES NOT TRYING
TO TEAR THEM DOWN AND SHUT THEM OUT.
>> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS BEFORE THE NEXT SPEAKER SPEAKS
I'LL JUST THIS IS THE LAST CALL LAST CALL FOR GENERAL PUBLIC
COMMENT AFTER THIS INDIVIDUAL AFTER THE SPEAKER WILL THEN GO
TO THE NEXT HEARING. >> ALL RIGHT.
WELCOME. THANK YOU.
HELLO. BOARD OF SUPERVISORS IS MY NAME
MONICA HOPKINS. >> I AM THE BSA ASSOCIATE
DIRECTOR AT BOOKER T WASHINGTON WHICH STANDS FOR BELONGING
SAFETY ACCESS FREEDOM AND EQUITY.
>> I THINK I JUST WANT TO HIGHLIGHT A COUPLE OF THINGS
BECAUSE WE TALKED A LOT ABOUT THE CHILDREN AND THE SENIORS
BUT BOOKER T IS STEPPING IN TO STEWARD ELLA HILL HUTCH TO SAVE
COMMUNITY MY PROGRAM AND PARTICULARLY THE SERVE
ADULTS ENSURING THAT THERE IS COMMUNITY STABILIZATION FOR THE
ENTIRE COMMUNITY NOT JUST CHILDREN.
SO I JUST WANT TO ECHO THAT THIS IS ABOUT SAVING COMMUNITY
AS A WHOLE AND NOT SPLITTING TWO BLACK AGENCIES APART WHO
ACTUALLY HAVE HISTORY TOGETHER PREVIOUSLY IN THE HUNDRED
AND SEVEN YEARS THAT BOOKER T WASHINGTON HAS EXISTED.
THANK YOU. THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS.
>> ALL RIGHT, MR. PRESIDENT. ALL RIGHT.
>> PUBLIC COMMENT IS NOW CLOSED AND MADAM CLERK, I THINK WE
HAVE DBE STAFF. YES.
>> TO RETURN BACK ON ITEM 16. THANK YOU.
>> SO SHOULD I JUST READ IN THE LINES THAT HAVE BEEN REMOVED?
OKAY, SO I WILL REMOVE OR READ IN THE LINES THAT WE REMOVED
WHILE WE WERE IN SIDEBAR. LINE SIX, LINE 30.
LINE 37 AND 38 AND 46 7588, 89 9100 102 103 104 118 119 133
134 135 150 224 233 241 242 243 2733083 16 317 THREE 22 THREE
39 3793 80 AND THAT'S THAT'S THE ONES WE'RE REMOVING.
>> OKAY SO COLLEAGUES CAN WE ACCEPT THE AMENDMENTS THE
REPORT CONTAINED IN ITEM 16 AND REMOVE THE PROPERTIES THAT
WERE JUST IDENTIFIED BY DEPARTMENT STAFF?
WITHOUT OBJECTION I DON'T SEE ANY OBJECTION.
>> SO WITHOUT OBJECTION THE CHANGES ARE ACCEPTED AND THEN
MADAM CLERK, CAN YOU PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON RESOLUTION
ITEM 16 WITH THE AMENDED REPORT ON ITEM 16 WITH THE AMENDED
REPORT SUPERVISOR CHAN CHIN I SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN I
SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I
SUPERVISOR RANDLEMAN I MANDOLIN I SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR I
SUPERVISOR SADR SADR I SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I
SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I AND SUPERVISOR HUANG WONG I
THERE ARE TEN EYES WITHOUT OBJECTION ITEM 16 IS ADOPTED
WITH THE AMENDED REPORT MADAM CLERK LET'S GO TO THE FOR
ADOPTION OF THAT COMMITTEE REFERENCE AGENDA ITEMS 19
THROUGH 25 ITEMS 19 THROUGH 25 WERE INTRODUCED FOR ADOPTION
WITHOUT COMMITTEE REFERENCE A UNANIMOUS VOTE IS REQUIRED FOR
ADOPTION OF A RESOLUTION ON FIRST READING TODAY ANY MEMBER
MAY REQUIRE A RESOLUTION ON FIRST READING TO GO TO
COMMITTEE SUPERVISOR MELGAR THANK YOU.
>> I'D JUST LIKE TO BE ADDED AS A CO-SPONSOR FOR ITEMS 19
AND 23. >> THANK YOU MADAM CLERK NOTED
THAT NOTED THANK YOU PROFESSOR WALTON.
>> THANK YOU PRESIDENT MADAM AND I JUST WANT TO MAKE SURE
THAT I'M ADDED AS A CO-SPONSOR TO ITEM 19 NOTED YOU'RE ALREADY
ON THERE FROM YOUR STAFF. THEY JUST PROVIDED IT TO US
TODAY. >> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU. >> JAN PLEASE COVER ITEMS 19
AND 25. OKAY.
>> AS A CHAIRMAN I WOULD LIKE TO ADD AS A CO-SPONSOR OF ITEM
NUMBER 25. >> OKAY THEN MADAM CLERK, CAN
YOU CALL THE ROLL ON ITEMS 20 THROUGH 24 AND ITEM 23 AND 2420
THROUGH 24 SORRY 2021, 22, 23 AND 24.
>> GOT IT 2122, 23 AND 24 AND 20 AND 28.
PARDON ME MR. PRESIDENT. I HAVE LOST MY HEARING A COUPLE
OF YEARS AGO SO I APPRECIATE THEY'RE JUST INDICATING WHAT
THE NUMBERS WERE 20, 21, 22, 23 AND 24.
SUPERVISOR CHEN I CHENNAI SUPERVISOR CHIN CHIN I
SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY I SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I
SUPERVISOR RANDLEMAN HI MENDELSON I SUPERVISOR MILKER
MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SHORTER SHORTER I SUPERVISOR CHERYL
CHERYL I SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I AND SUPERVISOR WONG
WONG EITHER ARE TONIGHT WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTIONS ARE
ADOPTED MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM 19 ITEM 19 RESOLUTION
RECOGNIZING JUNE 5TH 2026 AS HIV LONG TERM SURVIVORS
AWARENESS DAY IN THE CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN FRANCISCO
SUPERVISOR JAN THANK YOU AND COLLEAGUES YOU ALREADY HAVE
HEARD FROM MANY OF THOSE WHO CAME TODAY FOR PUBLIC COMMENT.
SO I JUST WANT TO HIGHLIGHT THAT THANKS TO DECADES OF
RESILIENCE AND SCIENTIFIC ADVANCEMENT, THE FIRST
GENERATION OF PEOPLE LIVING WITH HIV IS REACHING OLD AGE
IN SAN FRANCISCO. THESE LONG TERM SURVIVORS ARE
NOT AS SMALL OUTLIER THEY REPRESENT 75% OF ALL PEOPLE
LIVING WITH HIV IN OUR CITY. BUT AGING WITH HIV BRINGS
UNIQUE HEAVY CHALLENGES. THESE SURVIVORS AS THEY HAVE
INDICATED PARTICULARLY TODAY DURING PUBLIC COMMENTS FACE
CHRONIC PHYSICAL ILLNESS NEUROCOGNITIVE CHALLENGES
AND SOMETIMES SEVERE SOCIAL ISOLATION FROM LOSING ENTIRE
NETWORKS DURING THE HEIGHT OF THE EPIDEMIC.
LOCAL DATA SHOWS THEY EXPERIENCE DISPROPORTIONATELY
HIGH RATES OF PTSD AND FINANCIAL INSTABILITY BY
PROCHAIN CLAIMING TODAY, JUNE 5TH BY PROCLAIMING TODAY THAT
JUNE 5TH 2026 AS HIV LONG ARM SURVIVORS AWARENESS DAY WE ARE
NOT JUST OFFERING SYMBOLIC SUPPORT.
WE ARE RECOGNIZING THAT THERE ARE DISTINCT CHALLENGES REQUIRE
A DISTINCT FULLY FUNDED CITY RESPONSE.
WE OWE IT TO OUR ELDERS TO ENSURE THEY DO NOT JUST SURVIVE
BUT THRIVE. >> THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK.
WELL, I THINK WE CAN TAKE THIS OUT THE I THINK WE CAN TAKE
THIS ITEM SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED. >> MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM
20 FIVE. ITEM 25.
THIS IS A RESOLUTION RECOGNIZING THE MONTH OF MAY
2026 AS NATIONAL NURSES MONTH AND MAY 6TH THROUGH MAY 12TH
2026 AS NATIONAL NURSES WEEK IN THE CITY AND COUNTY
SURPRISED CHARM THANK YOU PRESIDENT AMENDMENT
AND COLLEAGUES AND THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR THIS THERE WERE NURSES
THAT ACTUALLY WANTED TO ATTEND AND JOIN US DURING PUBLIC
COMMENT TODAY BUT THERE ARE NURSES AND THERE THEY ACTUALLY
ARE TRULY BUSY WITH THEIR SHIFT AND THESE NURSES PARTICULARLY
ARE ACTUALLY FROM SAN FRANCISCO VETERAN AFFAIRS MEDICAL CENTER
LOCATED IN THE HEART IN THE IN OUR OUTER RICHMOND
IN ADDITION TO ALL THE CELEBRATION THIS MONTH MAY IS
NATIONAL NURSES MONTH AND MAY 6 TO 12 IS NATIONAL NURSES WEEK.
NURSES ARE THE BACKBONE, THE HEARTBEAT AND THE SOUL OF
HEALTH CARE. EVERY SINGLE DAY NURSES STEP
INTO THEIR SHIFT NOT KNOWING WHAT CHALLENGES AWAIT THEM.
THEY ARE CLINICAL EXPERTS QUICK THINKING PROBLEM SOLVERS
AND FIERCE PATIENT ADVOCATES. BUT JUST AS IMPORTANTLY THEY
ARE ATTENTIVE LISTENERS AND KEEPERS OF HOPE FOR FAMILY
AND FRIENDS AT THE FACE OF CHALLENGING NEWS.
SO SPECIFICALLY TODAY I DO WANT TO TAKE UP THIS OPPORTUNITY TO
CONGRATULATE THE ENTIRE TEAM OF NURSES AT THE SAN FRANCISCO
VETERAN AFFAIRS HEALTH CARE SYSTEM WHO RECENTLY WAS AWARDED
THE PRESTIGIOUS PATHWAY TO EXCELLENCE DESTINATION BY THE
AMERICAN NURSES CREDENTIALING CENTER.
THIS DESTINATION MAKES THE SAN FRANCISCO VA MEDICAL CENTER ONE
OF ONLY 16 VA HOSPITALS IN THE ENTIRE NATION.
V.A. NET WORK TO HAVE RECEIVED AS DISTINGUISH RECOGNITION.
THANK YOU TO THE TEAM OF EXTRAORDINARY NURSES AT THE SAN
FRANCISCO VA HOSPITAL AND THE VISIONARY LEADERSHIP OF TERRI
SHARP, ASSOCIATE DIRECTOR ASSOCIATE DIRECTOR OF PATIENT
CARE SERVICE AND NURSE EXECUTIVE FOR THE VA S.F. VA
CARE SYSTEM WHOSE COMMITMENT TO NURSE EMPOWERMENT
AND COMPASSIONATE VETERAN CARE MADE THIS RECOGNITION POSSIBLE.
AND THANK YOU AND I THINK WE CAN TAKE THAT SAME HOUSE SAME
CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED.
>> MADAM CLERK DO WE HAVE ANY IMPERATIVE AGENDA ITEMS?
I HAVE NONE TO REPORT. MR. PRESIDENT, COULD YOU PLEASE
READ THE IN MEMORIAM? >> YESTERDAY'S MEETING WILL BE
ADJOURNED IN MEMORY OF THE FOLLOWING BELOVED INDIVIDUALS
ON BEHALF OF SUPERVISOR CHAN FOR THE LATE MR. KENNETH LEE
YONG AND MR. GERALD W JOHNSON ON BEHALF OF SUPERVISOR DORSEY
AND SUPERVISOR RANDLEMAN FOR THE LATE MR. JACK DAVIS ON
BEHALF OF SUPERVISOR MANDEL MIN AND SUPERVISOR MELGAR FOR THE
LATE MISREAD ASSEMBLE AND ON BEHALF OF SUPERVISOR WALTON FOR
THE LATE MR. MAGNUS MARC MARTEL .
THANK YOU MADAM CLERK. DO WE HAVE ANY FURTHER BUSINESS
BEFORE US TODAY? THAT CONCLUDES OUR BUSINESS FOR
TODAY AND WE ARE ADJOURNED